<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Merged Defense / NATO / SpaceWar Feed</title><link>https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml</link><description>Aggregated RSS feed from NATO, DefenseOne, and SpaceWar</description><atom:link href="https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 19:11:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The D Brief: U.S. troops observe Zapad drills; Air Force’s future; Jokes about killing; Cost of Guard’s DC mission; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-18-2025/408194/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 11:46:27 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Senators question legality of strikes on alleged drug boats in Caribbean</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/senators-question-legality-strikes-alleged-drug-boats-caribbean/408200/</link><description>The nominee to lead the Pentagon’s counterterror policy office declined to comment on the administration’s strategy.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 14:18:24 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>AFSOC exercise brings concept created for great-power conflict to the Caribbean</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/afsoc-exercise-brings-concept-created-great-power-conflict-caribbean/408205/</link><description>Last month, U.S. forces “seized” a St. Croix airport in a demonstration of the Agile Combat Employment maneuver scheme.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:20:45 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How the rapid pace of AI connects to China’s threats toward Taiwan</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2025/09/what-rapid-pace-ai-means-chinas-threats-toward-taiwan/408220/</link><description>A hearing Wednesday explored why Taiwanese chips are more prized than ever.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 01:12:55 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: AFSOC’s Caribbean exercise; NATO’s new Ukraine aid-pool; Saudi-Pakistani pact; Back to Bagram?; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-19-2025/408228/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 11:57:50 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>When China plays orbital hide-and-seek, Maui’s telescopes give the US an edge</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2025/09/when-china-plays-orbital-hide-and-seek-mauis-telescopes-give-us-edge/408236/</link><description>In an interview, Space Force’s Saltzman reveals what’s next for the key sensor site.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 15:15:21 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Lockheed’s Skunk Works unveils work on a potential CCA competitor</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/lockheeds-skunk-works-unveils-work-drone-may-compete-future-cca-work/408252/</link><description>Officials say multipurpose Vectis drone is to fly by 2027, have “Indo-Pacific” range.</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 13:30:25 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Another boat strike; Russian jets over Estonia; F-47’s new flight date; Shutdown watch; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-22-2025/408267/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 11:20:49 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Anduril blames CCA delay on push for ‘semi-autonomous’ first flight</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/anduril-blames-cca-delays-push-semi-autonomous-first-flight/408278/</link><description>Air Force officials, who expected the milestone over the summer, now anticipate it by mid-October.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 15:42:19 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>F-47’s first flight expected in 2028</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/defense-systems/2025/09/f-47s-first-flight-expected-2028/408283/</link><description>That’s a year earlier than Air Force officials have previously said Boeing's sixth-gen combat aircraft might take wing.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 15:58:48 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>NATO will ‘not hesitate’ to act if Russian threats continue, says Estonian defense minister</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/nato-will-not-hesitate-act-if-russian-threats-continue-says-estonian-defense-minister/408292/</link><description>An alliance declaration about increased air defenses for Eastern Europe is expected on Tuesday.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:38:01 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The China threat goes beyond the Pacific, intel chiefs say</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/china-threat-goes-beyond-pacific-intel-chiefs-say/408293/</link><description>Air and Space Force intelligence chiefs warn of China’s global influence as military partnerships flourish.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 22:58:02 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: China’s global challenge; NATO on Russian incursions; Estonia’s requests; Germany’s big arms plan; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-23-2025/408300/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 11:27:33 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Has Space Force cracked the code on faster acquisition?</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/has-space-force-cracked-code-faster-acquisition/408312/</link><description>Leaders say the service is “disrupting” the Valley of Death, among other innovations.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 15:33:30 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>‘A game changer’: Space Force’s leader aims to debut future operating plans this year</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/game-changer-space-forces-leader-aims-debut-future-operating-plans-year/408320/</link><description>The document will predict future threats, so the service can better prepare for them.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 18:04:31 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>China’s new missiles on parade: showpieces or showstoppers?</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/chinas-new-missiles-parade-showpieces-or-showstoppers/408304/</link><description>The Sept. 3 parade was clearly meant to convey China's growing military strength and technological ambition.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 02:35:32 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Trump’s Ukraine reversal; Russian refineries, hit; China’s missiles; Iran’s rebuilding effort; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-24-2025/408330/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 12:00:03 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign ties are crucial to US space dominance, officials say</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/foreign-ties-are-crucial-us-space-dominance-officials-say/408333/</link><description>More partnerships, tighter alliances are needed to counter advances by China and others, U.S. space leaders said.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 12:54:53 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>‘We need to be ready to go’: AFSOC preps for potential Caribbean missions</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/we-need-be-ready-go-afsoc-preps-potential-caribbean-missions/408351/</link><description>AFSOC held a long-planned exercise on St. Croix just days before the first U.S. strike on an alleged drug boat.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:26:44 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Inside NATO’s response to Russia’s violation of Estonian airspace</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/inside-natos-response-russias-violation-estonian-air-space/408353/</link><description>Russia’s increasing violations of NATO met with new radars, missiles, “calm heads.”</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:44:29 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Defense One Radio, Ep. 194: Highlights from AFA's Air, Space &amp; Cyber Conference</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/defense-one-radio-ep-194-highlights-afas-air-space-cyber-conference/408344/</link><description>Our editors explore the dominant themes from this year's edition.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 18:59:10 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>China defence minister slams 'hegemonic logic' at Beijing forum</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/China_defence_minister_slams_hegemonic_logic_at_Beijing_forum_999.html</link><description>Beijing (AFP) Sept 18, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/china-beijing-tiananmen-square-marker-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Chinese Defence Minister Dong Jun denounced "hegemonic logic and acts of bullying" during remarks Thursday at a Beijing forum that were full of thinly veiled references to the United States. 

Organisers say about 1,800 representatives from 100 countries, including political, military and academic leaders, are gathering in Beijing for the Xiangshan Forum, considered China's answer to the annua</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:48:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>In first, Taiwan, US firm to make missile, underwater drone</title><link>https://www.sinodaily.com/reports/In_first_Taiwan_US_firm_to_make_missile_underwater_drone_999.html</link><description>Taipei (AFP) Sept 18, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/taiwan-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Taiwan will jointly manufacture a missile and an underwater drone with a US company for the first time, officials said Thursday, as Taipei seeks to boost domestic weapons and ammunition production. 

The democratic island faces the constant threat of an invasion by China, which claims it is part of its territory, and is under US pressure to spend more on its own defence. 

Taiwan's National</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:48:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Khamenei says Iran 'won't yield' to pressure to abandon uranium enrichment</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Khamenei_says_Iran_wont_yield_to_pressure_to_abandon_uranium_enrichment_999.html</link><description>Tehran (AFP) Sept 23, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/iran-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Iran's supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei on Tuesday said the Islamic republic would not give in to pressure to abandon its enrichment of uranium. 

Khamenei, in a televised address, also called any talks with the United States a "dead end" that were of no benefit to his country. 

His statement came as European powers seeking to reimpose tough sanctions on Iran over its nuclear programme</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:48:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zelensky says China could force Russia to stop Ukraine war</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Zelensky_says_China_could_force_Russia_to_stop_Ukraine_war_999.html</link><description>United Nations, United States (AFP) Sept 23, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/putin-xi-handshake-goodbye-moscow-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
 Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky told the UN Security Council Tuesday that China could pressure Russia to end the war in his country, following a US call for Beijing to stop buying Moscow's oil.  

China is not a party to the conflict, but Kyiv has long complained that Beijing has supplied items to Moscow that can be used in its war against Ukraine, and continues to purchase Russian ener</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:48:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran meets Europeans but no breakthrough as Tehran pushes back</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Iran_meets_Europeans_but_no_breakthrough_as_Tehran_pushes_back_999.html</link><description>United Nations, United States (AFP) Sept 23, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/iran-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 European powers seeking to soon reimpose tough sanctions on Iran over its nuclear program met Tuesday with Tehran's top diplomat, but there were no signs of compromise. 

There was however an agreement to continue talks as the clock ticks on the reimposition of deep sanctions on Iran's economy, even as Iran's supreme leader resisted European pressure. 

"Iran must never obtain a nuclear weap</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:48:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump to U.N.: 'Your countries are going to hell'</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Trump_to_UN_Your_countries_are_going_to_hell_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Sep 23, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/jaxa-moon-sniper-lunar-earth-australia-india-ocean-euroasia-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
 U.S. President Donald Trump spent most of his speech before the U.N. General Assembly on Tuesday criticizing other countries' handling of immigration and energy, describing climate change as the "greatest con job ever." 
 He simultaneously praised his own record on these issues, touting reduced crossings at the southern border and a renewed focus on using "clean, beautiful coal." 
 "</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:48:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Italy sends navy frigate to assist Gaza aid flotilla</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Italy_sends_navy_frigate_to_assist_Gaza_aid_flotilla_999.html</link><description>Rome (AFP) Sept 24, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/naval-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Italy's Defence Minister Guido Crosetto sent a navy frigate to assist a Gaza-bound flotilla Wednesday, after organisers said several of their boats had been targeted by multiple drones off Greece. 

The Global Sumud Flotilla said more than a dozen explosions were heard around the flotilla as it sailed off Greece late on Tuesday, with damage caused by "unidentified objects" dropped on deck.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:48:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Voyager debuts first space based multi cloud region to advance orbital data processing</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/Voyager_debuts_first_space_based_multi_cloud_region_to_advance_orbital_data_processing_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Sep 17, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/iss-full-view-cloud-desk-dragon-view-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
Voyager Technologies Inc. (NYSE: VOYG) has deployed Space Edge to the International Space Station, creating what it describes as the first multi-cloud region in orbit. The platform, launched Sept. 14, introduces real-time space-based data processing capabilities. 

Developed by LEOcloud, a recent Voyager acquisition, Space Edge is a space-hardened cloud infrastructure designed to reduce late</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:48:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SSTL and IHI agree to develop Japanese ISR constellation</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/SSTL_and_IHI_agree_to_develop_Japanese_ISR_constellation_999.html</link><description>London, UK (SPX) Sep 17, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/sstl-surrey-satellite-technology-space-eye-novasar-1-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Surrey Satellite Technology Limited (SSTL) and IHI Corporation have signed an agreement to co-develop a small satellite constellation to strengthen Japan's intelligence, surveillance and reconnaissance capabilities. The deal was concluded on 10 September at DSEI in London, underscoring expanding UK-Japan cooperation in space and defence. 

The partnership aligns with the 2023 Hiroshima Accor</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:48:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New software tool opens access to spacecraft camera design</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/New_software_tool_opens_access_to_spacecraft_camera_design_999.html</link><description>London, UK (SPX) Sep 22, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/screens-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

A newly developed open-source software package promises to make advanced spacecraft camera modelling accessible to a much wider research community. The tool, known as SIMply, can replicate how light interacts with lenses, sensors, and surfaces to predict the performance of imaging systems in space before they are built. 

Created by Dr George Brydon of the University of Glasgow, SIMply is av</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:48:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AV secures new contract option to deliver BADGER phased array systems for SCAR program</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/AV_secures_new_contract_option_to_deliver_BADGER_phased_array_systems_for_SCAR_program_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Sep 22, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/antenna-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

AeroVironment, Inc. (NASDAQ: AVAV) has been awarded a firm-fixed-price option by the U.S. Space Force Space Rapid Capabilities Office to deliver two BADGER phased array antenna systems under the Satellite Communication Augmentation Resource (SCAR) program. This marks the first option exercised under the SCAR Other Transaction Agreement, aimed at boosting system performance, deployment speed, and</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:48:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China warns Papua New Guinea over Australian defence deal</title><link>https://www.terradaily.com/reports/China_warns_Papua_New_Guinea_over_Australian_defence_deal_999.html</link><description>Sydney (AFP) Sept 19, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/papua-new-guinea-png-map-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
 China cautioned Papua New Guinea against "undermining" its interests and sovereignty in signing a mutual defence pact with Australia widely seen as a counter to Beijing's growing influence in the Pacific. 

Australia and Papua New Guinea this week agreed on the text of a deal which will see the countries commit to defending each other from armed attacks. 

Asked about the deal, a spokesperso</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:48:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela accuses US of waging 'undeclared war,' urges UN probe</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Venezuela_accuses_US_of_waging_undeclared_war_urges_UN_probe_999.html</link><description>Caracas (AFP) Sept 20, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/ecuador-colombia-venezuela-guyana-suriname-guiana-amazon-panama-central-america-caribbean-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
 Venezuela on Friday accused the United States of waging an "undeclared war" in the Caribbean and called for a UN probe of American strikes that have killed over a dozen alleged drug traffickers on boats in recent weeks. 

Washington has deployed warships to international waters off Venezuela's coast, backed by F-35 fighters sent to Puerto Rico in what it calls an anti-drug operation. 

"It i</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:48:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US lawmaker warns of military 'misunderstanding' risk with China</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/US_lawmaker_warns_of_military_misunderstanding_risk_with_China_999.html</link><description>Beijing (AFP) Sept 23, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/us-taiwan-china-flags-chess-piece-map-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 The leader of a US congressional delegation to China warned Tuesday of the "risk of a misunderstanding" between the two countries' militaries as advances in defence technology move at breakneck speed. 

Adam Smith, the most senior Democrat on Washington's Armed Services Committee, told journalists in Beijing that China needs to talk more about its military with other global powers "for basic d</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:48:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taiwan running out of time for satellite communications, space chief tells AFP</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Taiwan_running_out_of_time_for_satellite_communications_space_chief_tells_AFP_999.html</link><description>Hsinchu, Taiwan (AFP) Sept 19, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/milspace-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Taiwan's space chief Wu Jong-shinn says the "clock is ticking" for the democratic island to launch its own satellites to secure internet and phone services during a potential conflict with China. 

The island faces the constant threat of an invasion by Beijing, which claims the island is part of its territory and in recent years has intensified military pressure. 

Taiwan needs 150 of its ow</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 09:48:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DOGE risks Americans’ data by operating outside federal law, Democrats say</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/democrat-report-doge-risking-americans-data-operating-outside-federal-law/408380/</link><description>A report released by the Senate Homeland Committee's ranking member says lax security practices cause “serious cybersecurity vulnerabilities, privacy violations, and risk of corruption.”</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Agencies should prep for mass layoffs if shutdown occurs, White House says</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/agencies-should-prep-mass-layoffs-if-shutdown-occurs-white-house-says/408378/</link><description>OMB is requesting updated reduction-in-force plans even if a shutdown is averted.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:36:22 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Hegseth yanks brass to Quantico; Drones close Danish airports; AFSOC’s Caribbean work; Russia’s AI drones; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-25-2025/408367/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 11:18:07 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>More than 60K defense civilians have left under Hegseth—but officials are mum on the effects</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/more-60k-defense-civilians-have-left-under-hegseth-officials-are-mum-effects/408375/</link><description>Months into a hastily ordered overhaul, officials declined to disclose metrics, discuss problems.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:24:30 -0400</pubDate></item></channel></rss>