<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Merged Defense / NATO / SpaceWar Feed</title><link>https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml</link><description>Aggregated RSS feed from NATO, DefenseOne, and SpaceWar</description><atom:link href="https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 19:10:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Lockheed’s Skunk Works unveils work on a potential CCA competitor</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/lockheeds-skunk-works-unveils-work-drone-may-compete-future-cca-work/408252/</link><description>Officials say multipurpose Vectis drone is to fly by 2027, have “Indo-Pacific” range.</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 13:30:25 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Another boat strike; Russian jets over Estonia; F-47’s new flight date; Shutdown watch; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-22-2025/408267/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 11:20:49 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Anduril blames CCA delay on push for ‘semi-autonomous’ first flight</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/anduril-blames-cca-delays-push-semi-autonomous-first-flight/408278/</link><description>Air Force officials, who expected the milestone over the summer, now anticipate it by mid-October.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 15:42:19 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>F-47’s first flight expected in 2028</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/defense-systems/2025/09/f-47s-first-flight-expected-2028/408283/</link><description>That’s a year earlier than Air Force officials have previously said Boeing's sixth-gen combat aircraft might take wing.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 15:58:48 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>NATO will ‘not hesitate’ to act if Russian threats continue, says Estonian defense minister</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/nato-will-not-hesitate-act-if-russian-threats-continue-says-estonian-defense-minister/408292/</link><description>An alliance declaration about increased air defenses for Eastern Europe is expected on Tuesday.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:38:01 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The China threat goes beyond the Pacific, intel chiefs say</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/china-threat-goes-beyond-pacific-intel-chiefs-say/408293/</link><description>Air and Space Force intelligence chiefs warn of China’s global influence as military partnerships flourish.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 22:58:02 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: China’s global challenge; NATO on Russian incursions; Estonia’s requests; Germany’s big arms plan; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-23-2025/408300/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 11:27:33 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Has Space Force cracked the code on faster acquisition?</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/has-space-force-cracked-code-faster-acquisition/408312/</link><description>Leaders say the service is “disrupting” the Valley of Death, among other innovations.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 15:33:30 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>‘A game changer’: Space Force’s leader aims to debut future operating plans this year</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/game-changer-space-forces-leader-aims-debut-future-operating-plans-year/408320/</link><description>The document will predict future threats, so the service can better prepare for them.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 18:04:31 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>China’s new missiles on parade: showpieces or showstoppers?</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/chinas-new-missiles-parade-showpieces-or-showstoppers/408304/</link><description>The Sept. 3 parade was clearly meant to convey China's growing military strength and technological ambition.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 02:35:32 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Trump’s Ukraine reversal; Russian refineries, hit; China’s missiles; Iran’s rebuilding effort; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-24-2025/408330/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 12:00:03 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign ties are crucial to US space dominance, officials say</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/foreign-ties-are-crucial-us-space-dominance-officials-say/408333/</link><description>More partnerships, tighter alliances are needed to counter advances by China and others, U.S. space leaders said.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 12:54:53 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>‘We need to be ready to go’: AFSOC preps for potential Caribbean missions</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/we-need-be-ready-go-afsoc-preps-potential-caribbean-missions/408351/</link><description>AFSOC held a long-planned exercise on St. Croix just days before the first U.S. strike on an alleged drug boat.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:26:44 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Inside NATO’s response to Russia’s violation of Estonian airspace</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/inside-natos-response-russias-violation-estonian-air-space/408353/</link><description>Russia’s increasing violations of NATO met with new radars, missiles, “calm heads.”</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:44:29 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Defense One Radio, Ep. 194: Highlights from AFA's Air, Space &amp; Cyber Conference</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/defense-one-radio-ep-194-highlights-afas-air-space-cyber-conference/408344/</link><description>Our editors explore the dominant themes from this year's edition.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 18:59:10 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>DOGE risks Americans’ data by operating outside federal law, Democrats say</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/democrat-report-doge-risking-americans-data-operating-outside-federal-law/408380/</link><description>A report released by the Senate Homeland Committee's ranking member says lax security practices cause “serious cybersecurity vulnerabilities, privacy violations, and risk of corruption.”</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Agencies should prep for mass layoffs if shutdown occurs, White House says</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/agencies-should-prep-mass-layoffs-if-shutdown-occurs-white-house-says/408378/</link><description>OMB is requesting updated reduction-in-force plans even if a shutdown is averted.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:36:22 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Hegseth yanks brass to Quantico; Drones close Danish airports; AFSOC’s Caribbean work; Russia’s AI drones; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-25-2025/408367/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 11:18:07 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>More than 60K defense civilians have left under Hegseth—but officials are mum on the effects</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/more-60k-defense-civilians-have-left-under-hegseth-officials-are-mum-effects/408375/</link><description>Months into a hastily ordered overhaul, officials declined to disclose metrics, discuss problems.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:24:30 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>China, China, Chi—wait, what? Air Force mulls next steps amid homeland focus</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/china-china-chiwait-what-air-force-mulls-next-steps-amid-homeland-focus/408392/</link><description>Officials tout applicability of ongoing modernization, but experts and former officials have doubts.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 16:52:06 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Air Force’s AI ambitions mean simplifying its tangle of networks</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/defense-systems/2025/09/air-forces-ai-ambitions-mean-simplifying-its-tangle-networks/408397/</link><description>Over the next year, battle-networks chief aims to reduce systems to a “rational number.”</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 18:56:21 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Welsh project aims to reinvent space cooling with laser textured graphite</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/Welsh_project_aims_to_reinvent_space_cooling_with_laser_textured_graphite_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Fri Sep 26, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/graphite-film-coat-perovskite-solar-cells-waterproof-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Teledyne Labtech and Bangor University have launched the Advanced Thermal Management for Space Electronics (ATMS) program to address heat removal in spacecraft, with support from Airbus Endeavr, a joint initiative between Airbus and the Welsh Government. The effort targets lighter, higher performance thermal solutions for space hardware. 

ATMS centers on replacing traditional copper heat co</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 06:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>MDA to bring enhanced space tracking services to support Canadian defence</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Enhanced_space_tracking_services_to_support_Canadian_defence_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Sep 26, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/mda-space-logo-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

MDA Space Ltd. has been awarded a standing offer by Canada's Department of National Defence (DND) to provide enhanced space situational awareness services in partnership with Canadian firm ThothX Group. The agreement highlights the growing importance of space domain awareness as orbital traffic and threats escalate worldwide. 

The service integrates ThothX's Earthfence Radar Capability with</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 06:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Razor's Edge raises $560 million to scale defense and aerospace technology firms</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Razors_Edge_raises_560_million_to_scale_defense_and_aerospace_technology_firms_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Sep 26, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/milplex-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Razor's Edge has announced the close of its fourth investment fund, securing $560 million in commitments, surpassing its $400 million target. The new fund increases the firm's total assets under management to more than $1.25 billion, highlighting strong investor confidence in its national security-driven growth equity model. 

Founded in 2010, the firm has become a major force in advancing c</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 06:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dream Chaser spaceplane set for first flight with expanded defense and commercial roles</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Dream_Chaser_spaceplane_set_for_first_flight_with_expanded_defense_and_commercial_roles_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Sep 26, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/snc-dream-chaser-runway-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Sierra Space announced it is advancing its Dream Chaser spaceplane toward a first free-flyer demonstration flight, with a launch planned for late 2026. The test mission will validate critical technologies and deliver data to NASA, while providing new flexibility for both civil and national security applications. 

The agreement with NASA shifts Dream Chaser's debut into a demonstration role,</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 06:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SKorea says North's long-range missiles at 'final stage' as warning shots fired at NK boat</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/South_Korea_says_Norths_long-range_missiles_at_final_stage_999.html</link><description>New York (AFP) Sept 26, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/north-korea-missiles-launched-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
 Pyongyang is at the "final stage" of developing an intercontinental ballistic missile which could hit the United States with nuclear weapons, South Korea's president said Thursday. 

Seoul and its Western allies have failed to stop North Korea's weapons programme and Pyongyang says it will never give up its nuclear arsenal. 

"Whether to gain leverage in talks with the United States or to se</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 06:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>U.S.military ramps up tech capabilities to improve effectiveness</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/USmilitary_ramps_up_tech_capabilities_to_improve_effectiveness_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Sep 25, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/marss-nidar-surveillance-technology-end-to-end-ai-layered-defence-unmanned-aerial-systems-uav-uas-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 The U.S. military is deploying a real-time cybersecurity system to ensure its soldiers, sailors, air and space personnel have technological superiority over the nation's adversaries. 
 The new system employs automation, critical controls, continuous monitoring, survivability and training to enable rapid recognition of threats and defeat them, according to War Department. 
 The new cy</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 06:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pete Hegseth orders top U.S. military leaders to Tuesday summit</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Pete_Hegseth_orders_top_US_military_leaders_to_Tuesday_summit_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Sep 25, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/pete-hegseth-face-palm-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 War Secretary Pete Hegseth has summoned the nation's military leaders from around the world to meet at a Marine Corps base in Quantico, Va., for an unspecified reason on Tuesday. 
 The number of generals and admirals called to the meeting is the most summoned for a meeting in many years, according to The New York Times. 
 Other media outlets reporting the meeting include The Hill and</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 06:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Denmark says drone incursions were 'professional', rules out Russia</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Denmark_says_drone_incursions_were_professional_rules_out_Russia_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Sep 25, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/nordic-countries-sweden-finland-norway-denmark-iceland-faroe-islands-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Authorities in Denmark said Thursday that a slew of incidents involving unidentified drones in the Scandinavian country's airspace in recent days that have shuttered airports were "hybrid attacks," but stressed they did not believe Russia was behind them. 
 Following fresh sightings Wednesday over the Skrydstrup air base and the closure of Aalborg Airport for the second time in three days</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 06:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Italy deploys frigate after drone 'attack' on Gaza aid flotilla</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Italy_deploys_frigate_after_drone_attack_on_Gaza_aid_flotilla_999.html</link><description>Rome (AFP) Sept 24, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/turkey-ship-freedom-flotilla-gaza-aid-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Italy's Defence Minister Guido Crosetto sent a navy frigate Wednesday to assist a Gaza-bound aid flotilla, after organisers said several of their boats had been targeted by drones off Greece. 

The Global Sumud Flotilla said more than a dozen explosions were heard around the flotilla late Tuesday, with damage caused by "unidentified objects" dropped on deck. 

Crosetto said he "authorised th</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 06:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yemen drone attack wounds 22 in Israeli resort town: army, rescuers</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Yemen_drone_attack_wounds_22_in_Israeli_resort_town_army_rescuers_999.html</link><description>Jerusalem (AFP) Sept 24, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/drones-uav-sanaa-yemen-models-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Israel's military said a drone launched from Yemen struck the southern resort town of Eilat on Wednesday, with rescuers reporting nearly two dozen wounded. 

A military statement said the drone "fell in the area of Eilat" on the Red Sea coast after air defences had failed to intercept it, in the second such incident within days. 

Israel's Magen David Adom emergency medical service said its</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 06:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nations weigh maritime stability as U.S. provides $55M for efforts in Indo-Pacific</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Nations_weigh_maritime_stability_as_US_provides_55M_for_efforts_in_Indo-Pacific_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Sep 25, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/indian-pacific-southern-oceans-indo-pacific-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 U.S. Secretary of State Marco Rubio and representatives from more than 35 nations participated in talks to address global threats to maritime security by China and others on Thursday. 
 Rubio also announced the United States is allocating $55 million to support maritime law enforcement in the Indo-Pacific region, the State Department announced on Thursday. 
 The talks occurred as the</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 06:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China develops UAV defenses from spoofing detection to covert links and shipboard landing</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/China_develops_UAV_defenses_from_spoofing_detection_to_covert_links_and_shipboard_landing_999.html</link><description>Tokyo, Japan (SPX) Sep 22, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/china-uav-cloud-shadow-wind-shadow-wing-loong-10-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Unmanned aerial vehicles are rapidly advancing as tools for agriculture, logistics, surveillance, and disaster response, yet their reliance on GPS, wireless communications, and complex landing maneuvers leaves them open to manipulation, interception, and operational hazards. Three new papers in the Chinese Journal of Aeronautics detail Chinese teams' efforts to address these challenges with low-</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 06:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lithuania eases rules on shooting down drones</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Lithuania_eases_rules_on_shooting_down_drones_999.html</link><description>Vilnius (AFP) Sept 23, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/baltics-latvia-lithuania-estonia-russia-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
 Lithuania has streamlined its rules to make it easier to order the military to shoot down drones that violate its airspace, Defence Minister Dovile Sakaliene said Tuesday. 

"Even though we live de jure in peacetime, our laws ... were not adapted to current threats," Sakaliene told parliament. 

As of October 1, Sakaliene said she or an "authorised person" would now be able to order that a d</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 06:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Denmark military intel fails to identify source of drone flights</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Denmark_military_intel_fails_to_identify_source_of_drone_flights_999.html</link><description>Copenhagen (AFP) Sept 25, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/nasa-fire-scalable-traffic-management-for-emergency-response-operations-stereo-drone-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
 Denmark's military intelligence service said Thursday it had not been able to identify who was behind a series of drone flights over the country's airports that triggered security fears. 

"We do not have information allowing us to name those responsible for the events of recent days," the head of the service, Thomas Ahrenkiel, told a press conference - though intelligence chief Finn Borch sa</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 06:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU states to hold talks on 'drone wall' to protect bloc</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/EU_states_to_hold_talks_on_drone_wall_to_protect_bloc_999.html</link><description>Brussels, Belgium (AFP) Sept 25, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/epirus-systems-counter-uas-anti-drone-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 EU countries on Friday will hold their first talks on proposals to build a "wall" of anti-drone defences, after air incursions from Russia rattled eastern members. 

The threat to Europe's airspace has been heightened by unidentified drone flights in recent days that have shut airports in Denmark. 

EU chief Ursula von der Leyen made a first call for a "drone wall" in a keynote speech earlie</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 06:27:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Trump can make defense reform stick</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/how-trump-can-make-defense-reform-stick/408383/</link><description>It will require sustained presidential attention and unprecendented transparency.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Defense One Radio, Ep. 195: Europe's growing defense industry</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/defense-one-radio-ep-195-europes-growing-defense-industry/408388/</link><description>The EU's ambassador to the U.S. underscores the importance of the bloc's $910 billion defense plans known as Readiness 2030.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 10:34:18 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: DOD sheds 60K civilians; EU warns Moscow; USAF’s new ‘homeland’ focus; China’s airborne gets help; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-26-2025/408407/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 11:21:29 -0400</pubDate></item></channel></rss>