<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Merged Defense / NATO / SpaceWar Feed</title><link>https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml</link><description>Aggregated RSS feed from NATO, DefenseOne, and SpaceWar</description><atom:link href="https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 05:13:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How the rapid pace of AI connects to China’s threats toward Taiwan</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2025/09/what-rapid-pace-ai-means-chinas-threats-toward-taiwan/408220/</link><description>A hearing Wednesday explored why Taiwanese chips are more prized than ever.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 01:12:55 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: AFSOC’s Caribbean exercise; NATO’s new Ukraine aid-pool; Saudi-Pakistani pact; Back to Bagram?; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-19-2025/408228/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 11:57:50 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>When China plays orbital hide-and-seek, Maui’s telescopes give the US an edge</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2025/09/when-china-plays-orbital-hide-and-seek-mauis-telescopes-give-us-edge/408236/</link><description>In an interview, Space Force’s Saltzman reveals what’s next for the key sensor site.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 15:15:21 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Lockheed’s Skunk Works unveils work on a potential CCA competitor</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/lockheeds-skunk-works-unveils-work-drone-may-compete-future-cca-work/408252/</link><description>Officials say multipurpose Vectis drone is to fly by 2027, have “Indo-Pacific” range.</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 13:30:25 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Another boat strike; Russian jets over Estonia; F-47’s new flight date; Shutdown watch; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-22-2025/408267/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 11:20:49 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Anduril blames CCA delay on push for ‘semi-autonomous’ first flight</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/anduril-blames-cca-delays-push-semi-autonomous-first-flight/408278/</link><description>Air Force officials, who expected the milestone over the summer, now anticipate it by mid-October.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 15:42:19 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>F-47’s first flight expected in 2028</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/defense-systems/2025/09/f-47s-first-flight-expected-2028/408283/</link><description>That’s a year earlier than Air Force officials have previously said Boeing's sixth-gen combat aircraft might take wing.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 15:58:48 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>NATO will ‘not hesitate’ to act if Russian threats continue, says Estonian defense minister</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/nato-will-not-hesitate-act-if-russian-threats-continue-says-estonian-defense-minister/408292/</link><description>An alliance declaration about increased air defenses for Eastern Europe is expected on Tuesday.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:38:01 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The China threat goes beyond the Pacific, intel chiefs say</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/china-threat-goes-beyond-pacific-intel-chiefs-say/408293/</link><description>Air and Space Force intelligence chiefs warn of China’s global influence as military partnerships flourish.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 22:58:02 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: China’s global challenge; NATO on Russian incursions; Estonia’s requests; Germany’s big arms plan; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-23-2025/408300/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 11:27:33 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Has Space Force cracked the code on faster acquisition?</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/has-space-force-cracked-code-faster-acquisition/408312/</link><description>Leaders say the service is “disrupting” the Valley of Death, among other innovations.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 15:33:30 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>‘A game changer’: Space Force’s leader aims to debut future operating plans this year</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/game-changer-space-forces-leader-aims-debut-future-operating-plans-year/408320/</link><description>The document will predict future threats, so the service can better prepare for them.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 18:04:31 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>China’s new missiles on parade: showpieces or showstoppers?</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/chinas-new-missiles-parade-showpieces-or-showstoppers/408304/</link><description>The Sept. 3 parade was clearly meant to convey China's growing military strength and technological ambition.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 02:35:32 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Trump’s Ukraine reversal; Russian refineries, hit; China’s missiles; Iran’s rebuilding effort; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-24-2025/408330/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 12:00:03 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign ties are crucial to US space dominance, officials say</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/foreign-ties-are-crucial-us-space-dominance-officials-say/408333/</link><description>More partnerships, tighter alliances are needed to counter advances by China and others, U.S. space leaders said.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 12:54:53 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>‘We need to be ready to go’: AFSOC preps for potential Caribbean missions</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/we-need-be-ready-go-afsoc-preps-potential-caribbean-missions/408351/</link><description>AFSOC held a long-planned exercise on St. Croix just days before the first U.S. strike on an alleged drug boat.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:26:44 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Inside NATO’s response to Russia’s violation of Estonian airspace</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/inside-natos-response-russias-violation-estonian-air-space/408353/</link><description>Russia’s increasing violations of NATO met with new radars, missiles, “calm heads.”</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:44:29 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Defense One Radio, Ep. 194: Highlights from AFA's Air, Space &amp; Cyber Conference</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/defense-one-radio-ep-194-highlights-afas-air-space-cyber-conference/408344/</link><description>Our editors explore the dominant themes from this year's edition.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 18:59:10 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>DOGE risks Americans’ data by operating outside federal law, Democrats say</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/democrat-report-doge-risking-americans-data-operating-outside-federal-law/408380/</link><description>A report released by the Senate Homeland Committee's ranking member says lax security practices cause “serious cybersecurity vulnerabilities, privacy violations, and risk of corruption.”</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Agencies should prep for mass layoffs if shutdown occurs, White House says</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/agencies-should-prep-mass-layoffs-if-shutdown-occurs-white-house-says/408378/</link><description>OMB is requesting updated reduction-in-force plans even if a shutdown is averted.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:36:22 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Hegseth yanks brass to Quantico; Drones close Danish airports; AFSOC’s Caribbean work; Russia’s AI drones; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-25-2025/408367/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 11:18:07 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>More than 60K defense civilians have left under Hegseth—but officials are mum on the effects</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/more-60k-defense-civilians-have-left-under-hegseth-officials-are-mum-effects/408375/</link><description>Months into a hastily ordered overhaul, officials declined to disclose metrics, discuss problems.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:24:30 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>China, China, Chi—wait, what? Air Force mulls next steps amid homeland focus</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/china-china-chiwait-what-air-force-mulls-next-steps-amid-homeland-focus/408392/</link><description>Officials tout applicability of ongoing modernization, but experts and former officials have doubts.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 16:52:06 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Air Force’s AI ambitions mean simplifying its tangle of networks</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/defense-systems/2025/09/air-forces-ai-ambitions-mean-simplifying-its-tangle-networks/408397/</link><description>Over the next year, battle-networks chief aims to reduce systems to a “rational number.”</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 18:56:21 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Taiwan running out of time for satellite communications, space chief tells AFP</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Taiwan_running_out_of_time_for_satellite_communications_space_chief_tells_AFP_999.html</link><description>Hsinchu, Taiwan (AFP) Sept 19, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/milspace-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Taiwan's space chief Wu Jong-shinn says the "clock is ticking" for the democratic island to launch its own satellites to secure internet and phone services during a potential conflict with China. 

The island faces the constant threat of an invasion by Beijing, which claims the island is part of its territory and in recent years has intensified military pressure. 

Taiwan needs 150 of its ow</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 02:03:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Microsoft trims service to Israel over Gaza surveillance</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Microsoft_trims_service_to_Israel_over_Gaza_surveillance_999.html</link><description>San Francisco, United States (AFP) Sept 25, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/computer-mouse-microsoft-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Microsoft on Thursday said it cut an Israeli defense unit's access to some cloud services apparently being used as part of a mass surveillance operation in Gaza. 

The move came after Microsoft spent more than two months investigating a report in The Guardian that the Israeli Defense Force was using cloud service Azure "for the storage of data files of phone calls obtained through broad or mas</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 02:03:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SKorea says North's long-range missiles at 'final stage' as warning shots fired at NK boat</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/South_Korea_says_Norths_long-range_missiles_at_final_stage_999.html</link><description>New York (AFP) Sept 26, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/north-korea-missiles-launched-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
 Pyongyang is at the "final stage" of developing an intercontinental ballistic missile which could hit the United States with nuclear weapons, South Korea's president said Thursday. 

Seoul and its Western allies have failed to stop North Korea's weapons programme and Pyongyang says it will never give up its nuclear arsenal. 

"Whether to gain leverage in talks with the United States or to se</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 02:03:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NATO sticks to guns as allies talk tough on Russian jets</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/NATO_sticks_to_guns_as_allies_talk_tough_on_Russian_jets_999.html</link><description>Brussels, Belgium (AFP) Sept 25, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/nato-russia-marker-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 After high-profile violations of NATO airspace by Russia over Poland and Estonia, alliance members have appeared at odds over how forcefully to react. 

While some have seemed to advocate for shooting down any jets breaching NATO's border, others have warned about getting dragged into a conflict. 

But behind all the noise, the differences may not be that great - and the Western defence all</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 02:03:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>North Korea could have up to 2 tonnes of highly enriched uranium: Seoul</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/North_Korea_could_have_up_to_2_tonnes_of_highly_enriched_uranium_Seoul_999.html</link><description>Seoul (AFP) Sept 25, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/north-korean-leader-kim-jong-un-inspection-nuclear-weapons-institute-uranium-enrichment-facility-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 North Korea is believed to possess up to two tonnes of highly enriched uranium, South Korea's unification minister said Thursday. 

The North has long been known to hold a "significant" amount of highly enriched uranium, the key material used to produce nuclear warheads, according to South Korea's defence ministry. 

But in a rare public confirmation, South Korea's unification minister said</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 02:03:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran says it has documents linked to Israel nuclear programme</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Iran_says_it_has_documents_linked_to_Israel_nuclear_programme_999.html</link><description>Tehran (AFP) Sept 24, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/nuclear-blackmarket-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Iranian state television on Wednesday broadcast images of documents and footage it said relate to Israel's nuclear activities - which Israel, Tehran's sworn enemy, has never officially confirmed nor denied. 

The documentary showed copies of passports said to identify Israeli scientists, along with information on the location of military sites. 

It also aired footage said to have been film</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 02:03:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU states to hold talks on 'drone wall' to protect bloc</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/EU_states_to_hold_talks_on_drone_wall_to_protect_bloc_999.html</link><description>Brussels, Belgium (AFP) Sept 25, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/epirus-systems-counter-uas-anti-drone-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 EU countries on Friday will hold their first talks on proposals to build a "wall" of anti-drone defences, after air incursions from Russia rattled eastern members. 

The threat to Europe's airspace has been heightened by unidentified drone flights in recent days that have shut airports in Denmark. 

EU chief Ursula von der Leyen made a first call for a "drone wall" in a keynote speech earlie</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 02:03:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US approves $1.2 bn missile sale to Germany</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/US_approves_12_bn_missile_sale_to_Germany_999.html</link><description>Washington (AFP) Sept 25, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/f-35-spear-3-missile-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 The United States on Thursday announced the approval of a $1.23 billion sale of up to 400 advanced air-to-air missiles and related equipment to NATO ally Germany. 

"The proposed sale will improve Germany's capability to meet current and future threats by providing increased air-to-air capability for the German F-35 program and supporting German and shared NATO planning, training, and operatio</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 02:03:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>France doubles down on threat to build future fighter jet alone</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/France_doubles_down_on_threat_to_build_future_fighter_jet_alone_999.html</link><description>Paris (AFP) Sept 24, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/future-combat-air-system-fcas-europe-jet-fighter-stealth-marker-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 France is in a position to develop a next-generation combat aircraft alone should negotiations with Germany and Spain fail, a government official said Wednesday. 

The statement comes a day after the head of French defence company Dassault said his firm could build the future European fighter jet by itself, as tensions persist with Germany over the multi-billion-euro project. 

The Future Co</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 02:03:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nations weigh maritime stability as U.S. provides $55M for efforts in Indo-Pacific</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Nations_weigh_maritime_stability_as_US_provides_55M_for_efforts_in_Indo-Pacific_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Sep 25, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/indian-pacific-southern-oceans-indo-pacific-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 U.S. Secretary of State Marco Rubio and representatives from more than 35 nations participated in talks to address global threats to maritime security by China and others on Thursday. 
 Rubio also announced the United States is allocating $55 million to support maritime law enforcement in the Indo-Pacific region, the State Department announced on Thursday. 
 The talks occurred as the</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 02:03:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pete Hegseth orders top U.S. military leaders to Tuesday summit</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Pete_Hegseth_orders_top_US_military_leaders_to_Tuesday_summit_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Sep 25, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/pete-hegseth-face-palm-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 War Secretary Pete Hegseth has summoned the nation's military leaders from around the world to meet at a Marine Corps base in Quantico, Va., for an unspecified reason on Tuesday. 
 The number of generals and admirals called to the meeting is the most summoned for a meeting in many years, according to The New York Times. 
 Other media outlets reporting the meeting include The Hill and</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 02:03:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Denmark military intel fails to identify source of drone flights</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Denmark_military_intel_fails_to_identify_source_of_drone_flights_999.html</link><description>Copenhagen (AFP) Sept 25, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/nasa-fire-scalable-traffic-management-for-emergency-response-operations-stereo-drone-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
 Denmark's military intelligence service said Thursday it had not been able to identify who was behind a series of drone flights over the country's airports that triggered security fears. 

"We do not have information allowing us to name those responsible for the events of recent days," the head of the service, Thomas Ahrenkiel, told a press conference - though intelligence chief Finn Borch sa</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 02:03:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India signs $7 bn deal for 97 domestically made fighter jets</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/India_signs_7_bn_deal_for_97_domestically_made_fighter_jets_999.html</link><description>New Delhi (AFP) Sept 25, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/india-fighter-jet-tejas-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 India on Thursday signed a $7 billion order for 97 domestically designed and built Tejas fighter jets as its air force retires its outgoing Russian MiG-21 jets after decades of use. 

The first Tejas jets - meaning "brilliance" in Hindi - were commissioned into the airforce in 2016, with the latest commission for the fourth-generation version of the fighter, Mk-1A. 

India, one of the worl</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 02:03:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Maintaining US space dominance requires rapid and reliable delivery of new systems</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Maintaining_US_space_dominance_requires_rapid_and_reliable_delivery_of_new_systems_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Sep 25, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/milspace-comms-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Winning in space depends on accelerating the way capabilities are developed and delivered, Chief of Space Operations Gen. Chance Saltzman told thousands attending the Air, Space and Cyber Conference on Sept. 23. He emphasized that future superiority hinges on force design, system acquisition, and delivering tools Guardians can employ immediately. 

Saltzman cited recent progress in GPS accur</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 02:03:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>U.S.military ramps up tech capabilities to improve effectiveness</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/USmilitary_ramps_up_tech_capabilities_to_improve_effectiveness_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Sep 25, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/marss-nidar-surveillance-technology-end-to-end-ai-layered-defence-unmanned-aerial-systems-uav-uas-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 The U.S. military is deploying a real-time cybersecurity system to ensure its soldiers, sailors, air and space personnel have technological superiority over the nation's adversaries. 
 The new system employs automation, critical controls, continuous monitoring, survivability and training to enable rapid recognition of threats and defeat them, according to War Department. 
 The new cy</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 02:03:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>