<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Merged Defense / NATO / SpaceWar Feed</title><link>https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml</link><description>Aggregated RSS feed from NATO, DefenseOne, and SpaceWar</description><atom:link href="https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 19:11:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The D Brief: War on leaks; IGs, targeted; Guard-deployment sitrep; The next geoint hub?; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-02-2025/408556/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:36:52 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Elon Musk’s SpaceX took money directly from Chinese investors, company insider testifies</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/elon-musks-spacex-took-money-directly-chinese-investors-company-insider-testifies/408557/</link><description>The newly unsealed testimony marks the first time direct Chinese investment in the company has been disclosed, raising new questions about foreign stakes in one of America’s most important military contractors.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:01:58 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>'Shadow economies' are growing. Military planners and operators must take them into account</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/shadow-economies-are-growing-military-planners-and-operators-must-take-them-account/408560/</link><description>Black markets prolong wars, defang sanctions, fray alliances, and help rogue governments and groups survive and thrive.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 13:21:41 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Inside Europe's crash effort to create a 'drone wall'</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2025/10/inside-emergency-effort-create-european-drone-wall/408582/</link><description>More sensors, more maneuverable, less expensive: How the Ukraine war is shaping the future of drone air defense.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:26:08 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Trump declares war on cartels; Feds storm Chicago apartments; Europe’s ‘drone wall’; Shadow economies; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-03-2025/408590/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:19:38 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Shutdown poised to drag into next week as layoff threat looms</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/shutdown-poised-drag-next-week-layoff-threat-looms/408602/</link><description>Senate once again fails to approve spending bill and the two sides remain far divided.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:35:33 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>NGA wants to put its idle PCs to work</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/defense-systems/2025/10/nga-wants-put-its-idle-pcs-work/408603/</link><description>GDIT is networking the agency’s St. Louis workstations to crunch geospatial data even when analysts aren’t around.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:42:55 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Guard deployments on hold; 4th speedboat bombed; Russia strikes Lviv; China’s black-market oil; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-06-2025/408615/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:37:39 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela, US edge toward war footing—but the White House may blink first</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/venezuela-and-us-edge-toward-war-footing-domestic-concerns-international-risks-may-hold-washington-back/408637/</link><description>The Trump administration is increasing the pressure, but domestic concerns, international risks may hold it back.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:30:03 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Hamas has run out of options</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/hamas-has-run-out-options/408639/</link><description>The group's survival now rests on accepting Trump’s plan and political reform.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>More employees set to receive furlough notices as shutdown drags on</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/more-employees-set-receive-furlough-notices-shutdown-drags/408636/</link><description>DOD has not said how long nonexempt civilian employees might be kept working.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:22:40 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Flood of questions leads Missile Defense Agency to push Golden Dome deadline one week</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/10/flood-questions-leads-missile-defense-agency-push-golden-dome-deadline-one-week/408635/</link><description>Pitches for a slice of MDA’s 10-year, up-to-$151 billion contract vehicle are now due Oct. 16.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:38:41 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>OMB quietly deletes reference to law requiring back pay to furloughed feds</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/omb-deletes-reference-law-guaranteeing-backpay-furloughed-feds-shutdown-guidance/408650/</link><description>A White House FAQ now says restitution is only guaranteed to excepted employees forced to work without pay.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:16:46 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Troops to Chicago; Trump’s partisan speech to sailors; F/A-XX OK?; MDA’s big Golden Dome vehicle; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-07-2025/408652/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 11:14:29 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Denied in July, DHS intelligence office resumes efforts to shed staff</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/dhs-intelligence-office-sent-deferred-resignation-offers-shed-staff-recent-months/408661/</link><description>After stakeholders scuttled dramatic cuts, the Office of Intelligence and Analysis is quietly offering buyouts instead.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 15:22:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Skeptical senators grill White House pick to lead Indo-Pacific policy</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/skeptical-senators-grill-white-house-pick-lead-indo-pacific-policy/408674/</link><description>The nominee to be assistant defense secretary for Indo-Pacific security affairs, backed the president's push for Taiwan to spend more.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 19:21:18 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Federal shutdown deals blow to already-hobbled cybersecurity agency</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/federal-shutdown-deals-blow-already-hobbled-cybersecurity-agency/408675/</link><description>Two-thirds of the staff at the nation’s cybersecurity agency are sidelined, opening opportunities for malicious hackers.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 21:46:45 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Senators doubt Asia policy; Jail Illinois leaders, says POTUS; Civil-military ‘crisis’; DHS cuts intel staff; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-08-2025/408684/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 11:26:01 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>It’s time to return Turkey to the F-35 fold, even if we have to get creative</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/its-time-return-turkey-f-35-fold-even-if-we-have-get-creative/408695/</link><description>It's a sticking point that is blocking deeper US-NATO-Turkish defense cooperation.</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 16:07:04 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Legal experts fear Trump admin is ignoring JAGs on cartel strikes, Guard deployments</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/military-legal-experts-fear-trump-admin-ignoring-jags-cartel-strikes-guard-deployments/408699/</link><description>A former military lawyer and a former judge encouraged commanders to stand up to unlawful orders.</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 17:25:15 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Lawmakers call for more defense biotech research as China pursues breakthroughs</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2025/10/lawmakers-call-more-defense-biotech-research-china-pursues-breakthroughs/408700/</link><description>Shelf-stable blood, biological camouflage, and biosensors are just some of the potential innovations.</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 17:36:20 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Stop trying to control every step’ of shipbuilding, senator tells Navy</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/stop-trying-control-every-step-shipbuilding-senator-tells-navy/408703/</link><description>Focus less on requirements and more on outcomes, says Montana’s Sheehy, and the entire Pentagon might get on board.</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 22:57:04 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Neuraspace launches autonomous defence platform to protect European space assets</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/Neuraspace_launches_autonomous_defence_platform_to_protect_European_space_assets_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Oct 07, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/neuraspace-marker-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Neuraspace, one of Europe's leading space domain awareness (SDA) providers, has expanded its role in defence and civil protection with the launch of "Neuraspace DEF," a system designed to deliver autonomous, rapid responses to threats against space-based infrastructure. 

The new platform advances beyond traditional passive monitoring by enabling active and self-directed control of space ope</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Planet renews US Navy contract for Pacific vessel monitoring</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Planet_renews_US_Navy_contract_for_Pacific_vessel_monitoring_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Oct 09, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/planet-labs-superdove-satellite-orbit-artwork-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Planet Labs PBC (NYSE: PL), a global leader in daily Earth observation data, has secured a $7.5 million contract renewal with the US Navy through its subsidiary, Planet Labs Federal, to continue vessel detection and maritime monitoring across the Pacific region. 

The renewed project integrates Planet's daily global PlanetScope imagery and high-resolution SkySat data into the SeaVision marit</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Next generation interceptor from Raytheon takes aim at drone warfare</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Next_generation_interceptor_from_Raytheon_takes_aim_at_drone_warfare_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Oct 09, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/raytheon-us-army-lids-ounter-uas-uav-drone-test-fire-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Raytheon, an RTX business, has revealed a prototype for its Next Generation Short Range Interceptor (NGSRI), a system designed to replace the combat-proven Stinger missile and meet the growing threat posed by drones and advanced airborne systems. Built with extensive input from soldiers and Marines, the new interceptor promises to fly both faster and farther, while integrating next-level sensing</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Denmark closes airspace to civilian drones amid rise in sightings</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Denmark_closes_airspace_to_civilian_drones_amid_rise_in_sightings_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Sep 29, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/uav-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Denmark will ban all civilian drones beginning Monday over safety concerns as Copenhagen prepares to host an EU summit on European defense. 
 Transport Minister Thomas Danielsen announced the airspace closure Sunday after a slew of incidents involving unidentified drones in recent weeks. The closure will be in effect from Monday to Friday. 
 He said the drones have created disruption</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Will Russia implode after Ukraine?</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Will_Russia_implode_after_Ukraine_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Oct 8, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/russia-protester-blank-piece-of-paper-arrested-police-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Here is a question few have posed or even considered: What will be the fate of Russia after the war in Ukraine ends, as it must sometime? The history of Russia and the USSR after wars ended, and neither was on the winning side, offers a hint of what may lie ahead. 
 In 1917, Russia was forced to accept a draconian peace and withdraw from World War I. What followed was a catastrophic civil</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Guyana strengthens territorial defense with French military support</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Guyana_strengthens_territorial_defense_with_French_military_support_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Oct 8, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/guyana-map-flag-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 During the opening ceremony of the French Embassy in Guyana, President Irfaan Ali said his country was ready to accept the France's offer of technological assistance - including land and maritime radar systems - to monitor Venezuela's movements amid pressure over the Essequibo region. 
 At the event Saturday, Ali confirmed that Guyana and France are cooperating on defense and security a</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia says missile strike kills three in Belgorod region: governor</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Russia_says_missile_strike_kills_three_in_Belgorod_region_governor_999.html</link><description>Moscow (AFP) Oct 8, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/ukraine-russia-belgorod-missile-attack-fuel-depot-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 A missile strike killed three people in a village in Russia's Belgorod region bordering Ukraine on Wednesday, the local governor said. 

"The village of Maslova Pristan in the Shebekinsky District was hit by a missile strike. According to preliminary data, three people were killed and one was wounded," governor Vyacheslav Gladkov said on Telegram, adding that some people could still be trapped</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>North Korea expected to stage military parade as party turns 80</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/North_Korea_expected_to_stage_military_parade_as_party_turns_80_999.html</link><description>Seoul (AFP) Oct 9, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/north-korean-military-parade-pyongyang-kim-jong-un-dais-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 North Korea is set to host top officials from China and Russia to mark 80 years under the ruling Workers' Party, a celebration that is expected to feature a massive military parade showcasing its latest advanced weaponry.  

Planning for the spectacle, which could begin as early as Thursday, has been shrouded in secrecy, with South Korea's military saying the North may stage the parade at nigh</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Space Systems Command adds second Blue Origin deal to boost vehicle processing at Cape Canaveral</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Space_Systems_Command_adds_second_Blue_Origin_deal_to_boost_vehicle_processing_at_Cape_Canaveral_999.html</link><description>El Segundo CA (SPX) Oct 09, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/blue-origin-new-glenn-ng-1-night-pad-laucher-candj-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Space Systems Command is expanding its space vehicle processing capacity at Cape Canaveral Space Force Station by 2028, awarding Blue Origin a $78.25 million contract. The award is the second National Security Space Launch Space Vehicle Processing Commercial Solutions Opening contract aimed at strengthening responsive and resilient launch operations. 

"This second CSO award reflects our con</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NATO drone competition highlightes use of autonomous technology in disaster relief</title><link>https://www.terradaily.com/reports/NATO_drone_competition_highlightes_use_of_autonomous_technology_in_disaster_relief_999.html</link><description>Huntsville AL (SPX) Sep 30, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/disaster-management-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
This summer, The University of Alabama in Huntsville (UAH), a part of The University of Alabama System, hosted the SAPIENCE Drone Competition, an international Unmanned Aircraft System (UAS) event supported by the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Science for Peace and Security Programme. SAPIENCE stands for "Sense and Avoid - a cooPeratIvE droNe CompEtition," a project that highlights t</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump unlikely to win Nobel Peace Prize, but who will?</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Trump_unlikely_to_win_Nobel_Peace_Prize_but_who_will_999.html</link><description>Oslo (AFP) Oct 8, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/nobel-peace-prize-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
 When it comes to this year's Nobel Peace Prize, one thing is almost certain: US President Donald Trump will not win, no matter how much he wants it. But who will? 

The Norwegian Nobel Committee in Oslo will bring the suspense to an end when it announces the winner Friday at 11:00 am (0900 GMT). 

The backdrop is bleak: the number of armed conflicts worldwide involving at least one state has</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dutch NGO rejects Burkina junta's claims of spying</title><link>https://www.africadaily.net/reports/Dutch_NGO_rejects_Burkina_juntas_claims_of_spying_999.html</link><description>Abidjan (AFP) Oct 8, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/africa-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 An NGO on Wednesday denied claims by the Burkina Faso authorities that its workers had been involved in spying a day after the military regime arrested more of its staff. 

The International and Safety Organisation (INSO) was responding a day after the country's Security Minister Mahamadou Sana accused its staff of "spying and treason". 

"We categorically reject the allegations made regardi</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Japan's Takaichi may skip visit to Tokyo war shrine: reports</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Japans_Takaichi_may_skip_visit_to_Tokyo_war_shrine_reports_999.html</link><description>Tokyo (AFP) Oct 9, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/yasukuni-shrine-japan-300-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Japan's likely new prime minister Sanae Takaichi may skip visiting a shrine honouring war dead this month to avoid angering Asian neighbours, media reports said. 

Past visits by senior politicians to Yasukuni - which honours even convicted war criminals - have angered China and South Korea. 

The conservative Takaichi, who on Saturday became leader of the ruling Liberal Democratic Party (</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU wants key sectors to use made-in-Europe AI</title><link>https://www.robodaily.com/reports/EU_wants_key_sectors_to_use_made-in-Europe_AI_999.html</link><description>Strasbourg, France (AFP) Oct 8, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/robot-hand-holding-atom-marker-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 The EU on Wednesday told European businesses in critical sectors to ramp up their uptake of artificial intelligence and pushed for the bloc to cut its dependence on foreign AI providers. 

Although the European Union is falling behind the United States and China, Brussels believes the bloc can still compete in the global AI race. 

To achieve this, the European Commission said it was mobilis</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU 'must respond' to Russia's 'hybrid warfare': von der Leyen</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/EU_must_respond_to_Russias_hybrid_warfare_von_der_Leyen_999.html</link><description>Strasbourg, France Oct 8, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/ukraine-snow-bohdanivka-russian-flag-hoisted-near-bakhmut-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 EU chief Ursula von der Leyen on Wednesday said Europe must ramp up its defences to deter Russia's "hybrid warfare", after a catalogue of air incursions, cyber attacks and damage to undersea cables. 

"These incidents are calculated to linger in the twilight of deniability. This is not random harassment. It is a coherent and escalating campaign," the European Commission head said in a speech t</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:48:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DHS tells hundreds of staffers: accept reassignment to border security, immigration—or face termination</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/hundreds-dhs-staff-face-reassignments-border-security-immigration/408709/</link><description>The affected workers including some at CISA, FEMA, and the Coast Guard. Some have been given a week to respond.</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 11:16:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Ceasefire near in Gaza?; Troops arrive in Chicago; Shipbuilding advice; Deportation stats; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-09-2025/408708/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 11:46:58 -0400</pubDate></item></channel></rss>