<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Merged Defense / NATO / SpaceWar Feed</title><link>https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml</link><description>Aggregated RSS feed from NATO, DefenseOne, and SpaceWar</description><atom:link href="https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 15:12:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The China threat goes beyond the Pacific, intel chiefs say</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/china-threat-goes-beyond-pacific-intel-chiefs-say/408293/</link><description>Air and Space Force intelligence chiefs warn of China’s global influence as military partnerships flourish.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 22:58:02 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: China’s global challenge; NATO on Russian incursions; Estonia’s requests; Germany’s big arms plan; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-23-2025/408300/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 11:27:33 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Has Space Force cracked the code on faster acquisition?</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/has-space-force-cracked-code-faster-acquisition/408312/</link><description>Leaders say the service is “disrupting” the Valley of Death, among other innovations.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 15:33:30 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>‘A game changer’: Space Force’s leader aims to debut future operating plans this year</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/game-changer-space-forces-leader-aims-debut-future-operating-plans-year/408320/</link><description>The document will predict future threats, so the service can better prepare for them.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 18:04:31 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>China’s new missiles on parade: showpieces or showstoppers?</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/chinas-new-missiles-parade-showpieces-or-showstoppers/408304/</link><description>The Sept. 3 parade was clearly meant to convey China's growing military strength and technological ambition.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 02:35:32 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Trump’s Ukraine reversal; Russian refineries, hit; China’s missiles; Iran’s rebuilding effort; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-24-2025/408330/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 12:00:03 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign ties are crucial to US space dominance, officials say</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/foreign-ties-are-crucial-us-space-dominance-officials-say/408333/</link><description>More partnerships, tighter alliances are needed to counter advances by China and others, U.S. space leaders said.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 12:54:53 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>‘We need to be ready to go’: AFSOC preps for potential Caribbean missions</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/we-need-be-ready-go-afsoc-preps-potential-caribbean-missions/408351/</link><description>AFSOC held a long-planned exercise on St. Croix just days before the first U.S. strike on an alleged drug boat.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:26:44 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Inside NATO’s response to Russia’s violation of Estonian airspace</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/inside-natos-response-russias-violation-estonian-air-space/408353/</link><description>Russia’s increasing violations of NATO met with new radars, missiles, “calm heads.”</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:44:29 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Defense One Radio, Ep. 194: Highlights from AFA's Air, Space &amp; Cyber Conference</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/defense-one-radio-ep-194-highlights-afas-air-space-cyber-conference/408344/</link><description>Our editors explore the dominant themes from this year's edition.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 18:59:10 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>DOGE risks Americans’ data by operating outside federal law, Democrats say</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/democrat-report-doge-risking-americans-data-operating-outside-federal-law/408380/</link><description>A report released by the Senate Homeland Committee's ranking member says lax security practices cause “serious cybersecurity vulnerabilities, privacy violations, and risk of corruption.”</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Agencies should prep for mass layoffs if shutdown occurs, White House says</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/agencies-should-prep-mass-layoffs-if-shutdown-occurs-white-house-says/408378/</link><description>OMB is requesting updated reduction-in-force plans even if a shutdown is averted.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:36:22 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Hegseth yanks brass to Quantico; Drones close Danish airports; AFSOC’s Caribbean work; Russia’s AI drones; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-25-2025/408367/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 11:18:07 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>More than 60K defense civilians have left under Hegseth—but officials are mum on the effects</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/more-60k-defense-civilians-have-left-under-hegseth-officials-are-mum-effects/408375/</link><description>Months into a hastily ordered overhaul, officials declined to disclose metrics, discuss problems.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:24:30 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>China, China, Chi—wait, what? Air Force mulls next steps amid homeland focus</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/china-china-chiwait-what-air-force-mulls-next-steps-amid-homeland-focus/408392/</link><description>Officials tout applicability of ongoing modernization, but experts and former officials have doubts.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 16:52:06 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Air Force’s AI ambitions mean simplifying its tangle of networks</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/defense-systems/2025/09/air-forces-ai-ambitions-mean-simplifying-its-tangle-networks/408397/</link><description>Over the next year, battle-networks chief aims to reduce systems to a “rational number.”</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 18:56:21 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How Trump can make defense reform stick</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/how-trump-can-make-defense-reform-stick/408383/</link><description>It will require sustained presidential attention and unprecendented transparency.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Defense One Radio, Ep. 195: Europe's growing defense industry</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/defense-one-radio-ep-195-europes-growing-defense-industry/408388/</link><description>The EU's ambassador to the U.S. underscores the importance of the bloc's $910 billion defense plans known as Readiness 2030.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 10:34:18 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: DOD sheds 60K civilians; EU warns Moscow; USAF’s new ‘homeland’ focus; China’s airborne gets help; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-26-2025/408407/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 11:21:29 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>SOCOM to get robotic anti-drone turret for maritime platforms</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/socom-get-robotic-anti-drone-tech-maritime-platforms/408418/</link><description>Defense tech startup Allen Control Systems landed a contract for Bullfrog, which can use a variety of common weapons.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 16:10:54 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Two mass shootings; Troops to Portland?; Trump to join Hegseth-brass confab; Arrested by ICE for “how they look”; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-29-2025/408439/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 11:21:45 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Military AI needs guardrails—not to slow it down, but to keep it useful</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/military-ai-needs-guardrailsnot-slow-it-down-keep-it-useful/408452/</link><description>Modifying commercial models isn’t as easy as removing the parts that discourage users from killing people.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 16:50:36 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Shutdown could erode cyber defenses by sidelining critical staff, experts warn</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/shutdown-could-erode-cyber-defenses-sidelining-critical-staff-experts-warn/408466/</link><description>And it would happen just as a bedrock law on sharing cyber threat data expires.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 18:48:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Don’t let the ‘unequal dialogue’ become a partisan one</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/dont-let-unequal-dialogue-become-partisan-one/408467/</link><description>Secretary Hegseth's short-notice summoning of flag officers evinces a dangerous lack of respect.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 20:21:13 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump to attend meeting with hundreds of senior U.S. military officers</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Trump_to_attend_meeting_with_hundreds_of_senior_US_military_officers_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Sep 28, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/superpowers-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 President Donald Trump said Sunday that he will attend a meeting organized by Defense Secretary Peter Hegseth that aims to gather hundreds of senior military officers near Washington this week. 
 Trump confirmed his Tuesday attendance with NBC News. 
 "It's really just a very nice meeting talking about how we're all doing militarily, talking about being in great shape, talking about</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:13:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Radio astronomers gain seat at global standards table on satellite interference</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/Radio_astronomers_gain_seat_at_global_standards_table_on_satellite_interference_999.html</link><description>Berlin, Germany (SPX) Sep 25, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/constellation-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Radio astronomers have secured a formal role in shaping global standards to mitigate satellite interference with their observations. The Committee on Radio Astronomy Frequencies (CRAF) has been admitted as an I-member of the International Special Committee on Radio Interference (CISPR), which defines international rules on electromagnetic compatibility. 

The initiative was led by ASTRON res</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:13:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zelensky condemns 'vile' Russian attack that lasted 12 hours</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Zelensky_condemns_vile_Russian_attack_that_lasted_12_hours_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Sep 28, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/war-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky on Sunday condemned a "vile" Russian airstrike that lasted more than 12 hours overnight Saturday, killing at least four people in Kyiv. 
 Zelensky, in a post to social media, said Russia used nearly 500 attack drones and more than 40 missiles, including air Kinzhal hypersonic missiles, for "targeted terror" against Ukrainian cities in the Kyiv, Zapor</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:13:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia blamed for GPS attack on Spanish defence minister's plane</title><link>https://www.gpsdaily.com/reports/Russia_blamed_for_GPS_attack_on_Spanish_defence_ministers_plane_999.html</link><description>Madrid (AFP) Sept 24, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/gps-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 A plane carrying Spain's defence minister suffered an attack on its GPS navigation while flying near Russia's exclave of Kaliningrad on Wednesday, a ministry source said, the latest such incident blamed on Moscow. 

"There was an attempt to scramble the GPS signal" of the plane transporting Margarita Robles to Lithuania, the defence ministry source said, adding that the flight had an encrypted</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:13:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kinetica 2 rocket on track for inaugural mission in 2025</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/Kinetica_2_rocket_on_track_for_inaugural_mission_in_2025_999.html</link><description>Tokyo, Japan (SPX) Sep 29, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/china-cas-space-kinetica-1-rocket-model-launch-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

CAS Space, a subsidiary of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, is completing development of its new Kinetica 2 rocket and aims to launch it before the end of 2025. The company confirmed that the first vehicle has been assembled and is undergoing integrated testing ahead of its debut flight in the fourth quarter. That mission will also introduce a new robotic cargo ship named Qingzhou, or Light Ship</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:13:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New U.S.-European Sea Level Satellite Will Help Safeguard Ships at Sea</title><link>https://www.terradaily.com/reports/New_U_S__European_Sea_Level_Satellite_Will_Help_Safeguard_Ships_at_Sea_999.html</link><description>Pasadena CA (JPL) Sep 29, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/sentinel-6-michael-freilich-sea-level-data-april-24-el-nino-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Sea surface height data from the Sentinel-6B satellite, led by NASA and ESA, will help with the development of marine weather forecasts, alerting ships to possible dangers. 

Because most global trade travels by ship, accurate, timely ocean forecasts are essential. These forecasts provide crucial information about storms, high winds, and rough water, and they depend on measurements provided</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:13:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China's President Xi makes rare visit to Xinjiang</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Chinas_President_Xi_makes_rare_visit_to_Xinjiang_999.html</link><description>Beijing (AFP) Sept 23, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/map-china-xinjiang-uyghur-uighur-autonomous-region-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Chinese President Xi Jinping began a rare visit Tuesday to the northwest region of Xinjiang, home to numerous ethnic groups including Turkic-speaking Uyghurs, the official Xinhua news agency reported. 

The vast territory borders several countries, including Kazakhstan, Afghanistan and Pakistan. 

Xi arrived in the regional capital Urumqi to attend celebrations marking the 70th anniversary o</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:13:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Wiretapping scandal goes to court in Greece</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Wiretapping_scandal_goes_to_court_in_Greece_999.html</link><description>Athens Sept 24, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/cyberwar-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 A trial linked to the illegal wiretapping of politicians and journalists using the spy software Predator opens on Wednesday in Greece, three years after a scandal that rocked the country. 

Four people, two Israelis and two Greeks, are being tried at the Athens Criminal Court for the "violation of telephone communication secrecy" and face a maximum five-year prison sentence. 

Their trial, i</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:13:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SFL Missions to Deliver Spacecraft Buses for HawkEye 360 RF Signal Detection Expansion</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/SFL_Missions_to_Deliver_Spacecraft_Buses_for_HawkEye_360_RF_Signal_Detection_Expansion_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Sep 29, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/hawkeye-360-logo-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
SFL Missions Inc. has secured a contract to build spacecraft bus units for three new HawkEye 360 satellite clusters, adding nine spacecraft to the company's expanding constellation for RF signal detection and geolocation. The order covers Cluster 14, which follows earlier designs, and Clusters 15 and 16, which incorporate advanced capabilities. 

Through its Flex Production program, SFL Miss</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:13:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NASA begins testing PExT wideband communications system in orbit</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/NASA_begins_testing_PExT_wideband_communications_system_in_orbit_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Sep 29, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/wideband-global-satcom-wgs-11+-orbit-marker-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Payload commissioning has started for NASA's Polylingual Experimental Terminal (PExT), a pioneering wideband space communications technology designed to connect spacecraft with both government and commercial networks. 

The demonstration rides aboard York Space Systems' Bard satellite, launched on July 23. The satellite completed its bus commissioning within four weeks, validating key system</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:13:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>We can build fighter jet without Germany: France's Dassault</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/We_can_build_fighter_jet_without_Germany_Frances_Dassault_999.html</link><description>Cergy-Pontoise, France (AFP) Sept 23, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/jet-rafale-dassault-300-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 The head of French defence company Dassault said on Tuesday his firm could build the future European fighter jet by itself, as tensions persist with Germany over the multi-billion-euro project. 

The Future Combat Air System (FCAS) programme was launched in 2017 to replace France's Rafale jet and the Eurofighter planes used by Germany and Spain. 

But the scheme, jointly developed by the thr</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:13:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Planet captures first light from Pelican-3 satellite as constellation expands</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/Planet_captures_first_light_from_Pelican_3_satellite_as_constellation_expands_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Sep 29, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/planet-labs-pelican-satellite-constellation-marker-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Planet Labs PBC (NYSE: PL) has released the first light image from its Pelican-3 satellite, capturing Turin, Italy on September 5 from an altitude of 458 km. The spacecraft, launched on August 26 aboard a SpaceX Falcon 9 NAOS mission with Pelican-4, is currently undergoing instrument calibration before entering full operations. 

CEO Will Marshall said the rapid imaging highlights the Pelica</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:13:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Elbit secures 120 million order for Hermes 900 maritime surveillance UAS</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Elbit_secures_120_million_order_for_Hermes_900_maritime_surveillance_UAS_999.html</link><description>Paris, France (SPX) Sep 30, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/uav-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Elbit Systems has received a contract worth approximately $120 million to supply its Hermes 900 Unmanned Aerial System for long-range maritime surveillance to an international customer. The award underscores sustained global demand for the companys high-performance unmanned capabilities. 

The Hermes 900 is Elbits largest MALE platform, designed for multi-mission operations including area do</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:13:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Top diplomats of North Korea, China agree to oppose 'hegemonism'</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Top_diplomats_of_North_Korea_China_agree_to_oppose_hegemonism_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Sep 29, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/superpowers-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 The top diplomats of North Korea and China met in Beijing and agreed to develop bilateral ties while resisting "hegemonism" and "unilateralism," both countries said Monday. 
 The first one-on-one meeting between North Korean Foreign Minister Choe Son Hui and her Chinese counterpart, Wang Yi, took place on Sunday. 
 "China is ready to strengthen coordination and cooperation with the D</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:13:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sierra Space clears design milestone for missile tracking satellites in SDA Tranche 2</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Sierra_Space_clears_design_milestone_for_missile_tracking_satellites_in_SDA_Tranche_2_999.html</link><description>Louisville CO (SPX) Sep 30, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/abm-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Sierra Space has completed the Critical Design Review (CDR) for the Space Development Agency's (SDA) Tranche 2 Tracking Layer, confirming readiness to begin production of missile tracking satellites for the Proliferated Warfighter Space Architecture (PWSA). The program will see Sierra Space deliver two orbital planes, totaling 18 satellites, each carrying advanced infrared sensors designed to de</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:13:43 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>