<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Merged Defense / NATO / SpaceWar Feed</title><link>https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml</link><description>Aggregated RSS feed from NATO, DefenseOne, and SpaceWar</description><atom:link href="https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:14:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The China threat goes beyond the Pacific, intel chiefs say</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/china-threat-goes-beyond-pacific-intel-chiefs-say/408293/</link><description>Air and Space Force intelligence chiefs warn of China’s global influence as military partnerships flourish.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 22:58:02 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: China’s global challenge; NATO on Russian incursions; Estonia’s requests; Germany’s big arms plan; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-23-2025/408300/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 11:27:33 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Has Space Force cracked the code on faster acquisition?</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/has-space-force-cracked-code-faster-acquisition/408312/</link><description>Leaders say the service is “disrupting” the Valley of Death, among other innovations.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 15:33:30 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>‘A game changer’: Space Force’s leader aims to debut future operating plans this year</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/game-changer-space-forces-leader-aims-debut-future-operating-plans-year/408320/</link><description>The document will predict future threats, so the service can better prepare for them.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 18:04:31 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>China’s new missiles on parade: showpieces or showstoppers?</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/chinas-new-missiles-parade-showpieces-or-showstoppers/408304/</link><description>The Sept. 3 parade was clearly meant to convey China's growing military strength and technological ambition.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 02:35:32 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Trump’s Ukraine reversal; Russian refineries, hit; China’s missiles; Iran’s rebuilding effort; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-24-2025/408330/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 12:00:03 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Foreign ties are crucial to US space dominance, officials say</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/foreign-ties-are-crucial-us-space-dominance-officials-say/408333/</link><description>More partnerships, tighter alliances are needed to counter advances by China and others, U.S. space leaders said.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 12:54:53 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>‘We need to be ready to go’: AFSOC preps for potential Caribbean missions</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/we-need-be-ready-go-afsoc-preps-potential-caribbean-missions/408351/</link><description>AFSOC held a long-planned exercise on St. Croix just days before the first U.S. strike on an alleged drug boat.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:26:44 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Inside NATO’s response to Russia’s violation of Estonian airspace</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/inside-natos-response-russias-violation-estonian-air-space/408353/</link><description>Russia’s increasing violations of NATO met with new radars, missiles, “calm heads.”</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 17:44:29 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Defense One Radio, Ep. 194: Highlights from AFA's Air, Space &amp; Cyber Conference</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/defense-one-radio-ep-194-highlights-afas-air-space-cyber-conference/408344/</link><description>Our editors explore the dominant themes from this year's edition.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 18:59:10 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>DOGE risks Americans’ data by operating outside federal law, Democrats say</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/democrat-report-doge-risking-americans-data-operating-outside-federal-law/408380/</link><description>A report released by the Senate Homeland Committee's ranking member says lax security practices cause “serious cybersecurity vulnerabilities, privacy violations, and risk of corruption.”</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Agencies should prep for mass layoffs if shutdown occurs, White House says</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/agencies-should-prep-mass-layoffs-if-shutdown-occurs-white-house-says/408378/</link><description>OMB is requesting updated reduction-in-force plans even if a shutdown is averted.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:36:22 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Hegseth yanks brass to Quantico; Drones close Danish airports; AFSOC’s Caribbean work; Russia’s AI drones; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-25-2025/408367/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 11:18:07 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>More than 60K defense civilians have left under Hegseth—but officials are mum on the effects</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/more-60k-defense-civilians-have-left-under-hegseth-officials-are-mum-effects/408375/</link><description>Months into a hastily ordered overhaul, officials declined to disclose metrics, discuss problems.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:24:30 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>China, China, Chi—wait, what? Air Force mulls next steps amid homeland focus</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/china-china-chiwait-what-air-force-mulls-next-steps-amid-homeland-focus/408392/</link><description>Officials tout applicability of ongoing modernization, but experts and former officials have doubts.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 16:52:06 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Air Force’s AI ambitions mean simplifying its tangle of networks</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/defense-systems/2025/09/air-forces-ai-ambitions-mean-simplifying-its-tangle-networks/408397/</link><description>Over the next year, battle-networks chief aims to reduce systems to a “rational number.”</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 18:56:21 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How Trump can make defense reform stick</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/how-trump-can-make-defense-reform-stick/408383/</link><description>It will require sustained presidential attention and unprecendented transparency.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Defense One Radio, Ep. 195: Europe's growing defense industry</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/defense-one-radio-ep-195-europes-growing-defense-industry/408388/</link><description>The EU's ambassador to the U.S. underscores the importance of the bloc's $910 billion defense plans known as Readiness 2030.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 10:34:18 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: DOD sheds 60K civilians; EU warns Moscow; USAF’s new ‘homeland’ focus; China’s airborne gets help; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-26-2025/408407/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 11:21:29 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>SOCOM to get robotic anti-drone turret for maritime platforms</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/socom-get-robotic-anti-drone-tech-maritime-platforms/408418/</link><description>Defense tech startup Allen Control Systems landed a contract for Bullfrog, which can use a variety of common weapons.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 16:10:54 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel links crypto wallets, $1.5B to Iran's Revolutionary Guard</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Israel_links_crypto_wallets_15B_to_Irans_Revolutionary_Guard_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Sep 15, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/iran-revolutionary-guards-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Israel's Ministry of Defense announced Monday the seizure of 187 cryptocurrency wallets that have received $1.5 billion. Israel says the wallets are linked to Iran's Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps, or IRGC, which has been designated as a terrorist group. 
 While $1.5 billion moved through the wallets over time, they currently hold $1.5 million, according to a document, detailing the se</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:31:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NATO sticks to guns as allies talk tough on Russian jets</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/NATO_sticks_to_guns_as_allies_talk_tough_on_Russian_jets_999.html</link><description>Brussels, Belgium (AFP) Sept 25, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/nato-russia-marker-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 After high-profile violations of NATO airspace by Russia over Poland and Estonia, alliance members have appeared at odds over how forcefully to react. 

While some have seemed to advocate for shooting down any jets breaching NATO's border, others have warned about getting dragged into a conflict. 

But behind all the noise, the differences may not be that great - and the Western defence all</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:31:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NATO's 'eyes in sky' scour eastern flank for Russian threats</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/NATOs_eyes_in_sky_scour_eastern_flank_for_Russian_threats_999.html</link><description>Aboard A Nato Aircraft, Poland (AFP) Sept 20, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/poland-russia-regional-map-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 In a NATO surveillance plane some 10,000 metres above eastern Poland, air force officers from a half dozen countries scanned screens for any sign of Russian aircraft breaching the alliance's borders. 

The threat was laid bare Friday when two Russian fighters violated Estonian airspace for 12 minutes, forcing NATO to scramble jets and sparking consternation across Europe.  

Now the skies ap</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:31:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Europe imposes 'snapback' sanctions on Iran's nuclear program</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Europe_imposes_snapback_sanctions_on_Irans_nuclear_program_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Sep 28, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/iran-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 A decade after they were lifted, economic and military sanctions were reimposed on Iran Sunday over its nuclear program. 
 Britain, France and Germany have accused Iran of "continued nuclear escalation," and reactivated what is known as a "snapback mechanism" over Iran's lack of cooperation to de-escalate the country's nuclear program. 
 Iran suspended inspections of its nuclear faci</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:31:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>North Korea could have up to 2 tonnes of highly enriched uranium: Seoul</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/North_Korea_could_have_up_to_2_tonnes_of_highly_enriched_uranium_Seoul_999.html</link><description>Seoul (AFP) Sept 25, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/north-korean-leader-kim-jong-un-inspection-nuclear-weapons-institute-uranium-enrichment-facility-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 North Korea is believed to possess up to two tonnes of highly enriched uranium, South Korea's unification minister said Thursday. 

The North has long been known to hold a "significant" amount of highly enriched uranium, the key material used to produce nuclear warheads, according to South Korea's defence ministry. 

But in a rare public confirmation, South Korea's unification minister said</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:31:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran says it has documents linked to Israel nuclear programme</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Iran_says_it_has_documents_linked_to_Israel_nuclear_programme_999.html</link><description>Tehran (AFP) Sept 24, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/nuclear-blackmarket-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Iranian state television on Wednesday broadcast images of documents and footage it said relate to Israel's nuclear activities - which Israel, Tehran's sworn enemy, has never officially confirmed nor denied. 

The documentary showed copies of passports said to identify Israeli scientists, along with information on the location of military sites. 

It also aired footage said to have been film</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:31:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan extends nuclear umbrella to Saudi Arabia: source close to govt</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Pakistan_extends_nuclear_umbrella_to_Saudi_Arabia_source_close_to_govt_999.html</link><description>Riyadh, Saudi Arabia (AFP) Sept 21, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/persian-gulf-saudi-arabia-iran-oman-turkey-afghanistan-pakistan-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Pakistan's nuclear umbrella will cover Saudi Arabia, a source close to the kingdom's government told AFP on Sunday, days after the two allies signed a surprise mutual defence treaty.  

The source told AFP that the deal had been in the works for years and that Saudi Arabia expected Pakistan's arch-rival India to understand the kingdom's security needs.  

When asked if the deal meant Pakista</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:31:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian armoured vehicle factory inaugurated in Morocco</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Indian_armoured_vehicle_factory_inaugurated_in_Morocco_999.html</link><description>Rabat (AFP) Sept 23, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/morocco-map-1-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 A factory producing Indian infantry combat vehicles was inaugurated in Morocco on Tuesday, the two sides said, in a move underscoring the South Asian giant's widening defence footprint. 

The TATA Advanced Systems Maroc plant, located in the industrial zone of Berrechid, will build the WhAP 8x8 vehicles for Morocco's army and for export markets, the kingdom's official MAP news agency reported.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:31:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Germany pledges EUR35 bn for space defence against Russia, China</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Germany_pledges_EUR35_bn_for_space_defence_against_Russia_China_999.html</link><description>Berlin (AFP) Sept 25, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/milspace-comms-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Germany will spend 35 billion euros ($41 billion) on outer space defence by 2030, Defence Minister Boris Pistorius said Thursday, citing the threat posed by Russia and China. 

"Russia and China have in recent years rapidly expanded their capabilities for conducting warfare in space," he said.   

"They can disrupt, jam, manipulate or even physically destroy satellites. In space, there are n</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:31:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pentagon bans reporters from accessing unauthorized info</title><link>https://www.terradaily.com/reports/Pentagon_bans_reporters_from_accessing_unauthorized_info_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Sep 20, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/pentagon-new-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Journalists covering the Pentagon will have to pledge to access only authorized information or lose their press credentials, the Department of War announced Friday. 
 The new policy enables Pentagon officials to revoke the credentials for any press staff that they might deem a security threat, according to The Washington Post. 
 War Department officials published a 17-page document e</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:31:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela claims 'impregnable' defenses; experts doubtful</title><link>https://www.oilgasdaily.com/reports/Venezuela_claims_impregnable_defenses_experts_doubtful_999.html</link><description>Caracas (AFP) Sept 19, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/ecuador-colombia-venezuela-guyana-suriname-guiana-amazon-panama-central-america-caribbean-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Faced with a major US naval build-up near its waters, Venezuela has flexed its muscle by conducting military exercises, arming civilians and deploying thousands of troops to its land and sea borders. 

But military experts take a dim view of Venezuela's combat readiness, saying years of crisis have made a paper tiger of its armed forces. 

President Nicolas Maduro has accused the United Stat</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:31:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SATNUS completes third NGWS flight campaign with autonomous systems integration</title><link>https://www.gpsdaily.com/reports/SATNUS_completes_third_NGWS_flight_campaign_with_autonomous_systems_integration_999.html</link><description>Madrid, Spain (SPX) Sep 29, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/gmv-galileo-mission-operations-room-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
SATNUS has carried out its third flight test campaign for the Next Generation Weapon System (NGWS), marking significant progress toward the program's Phase 1B demonstrations. The trials centered on validating the MUT2 and Common Systems Demonstrator platforms, as well as the integration and testing of the Next Generation Autonomy Computer (NGAC). 

The campaign featured three single and thre</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:31:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US approves $1.2 bn missile sale to Germany</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/US_approves_12_bn_missile_sale_to_Germany_999.html</link><description>Washington (AFP) Sept 29, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/f-35-spear-3-missile-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 The United States on Thursday announced the approval of a $1.23 billion sale of up to 400 advanced air-to-air missiles and related equipment to NATO ally Germany. 

"The proposed sale will improve Germany's capability to meet current and future threats by providing increased air-to-air capability for the German F-35 program and supporting German and shared NATO planning, training, and operatio</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:31:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>France doubles down on threat to build future fighter jet alone</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/France_doubles_down_on_threat_to_build_future_fighter_jet_alone_999.html</link><description>Paris (AFP) Sept 29, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/future-combat-air-system-fcas-europe-jet-fighter-stealth-marker-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 France is in a position to develop a next-generation combat aircraft alone should negotiations with Germany and Spain fail, a government official said Wednesday. 

The statement comes a day after the head of French defence company Dassault said his firm could build the future European fighter jet by itself, as tensions persist with Germany over the multi-billion-euro project. 

The Future Co</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:31:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India signs $7 bn deal for 97 domestically made fighter jets</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/India_signs_7_bn_deal_for_97_domestically_made_fighter_jets_999.html</link><description>New Delhi (AFP) Sept 29, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/india-fighter-jet-tejas-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 India on Thursday signed a $7 billion order for 97 domestically designed and built Tejas fighter jets as its air force retires its outgoing Russian MiG-21 jets after decades of use. 

The first Tejas jets - meaning "brilliance" in Hindi - were commissioned into the airforce in 2016, with the latest commission for the fourth-generation version of the fighter, Mk-1A. 

India, one of the worl</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:31:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Two mass shootings; Troops to Portland?; Trump to join Hegseth-brass confab; Arrested by ICE for “how they look”; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-29-2025/408439/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 11:21:45 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Military AI needs guardrails—not to slow it down, but to keep it useful</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/military-ai-needs-guardrailsnot-slow-it-down-keep-it-useful/408452/</link><description>Modifying commercial models isn’t as easy as removing the parts that discourage users from killing people.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 16:50:36 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Shutdown could erode cyber defenses by sidelining critical staff, experts warn</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/shutdown-could-erode-cyber-defenses-sidelining-critical-staff-experts-warn/408466/</link><description>And it would happen just as a bedrock law on sharing cyber threat data expires.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 18:48:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Don’t let the ‘unequal dialogue’ become a partisan one</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/dont-let-unequal-dialogue-become-partisan-one/408467/</link><description>Secretary Hegseth's short-notice summoning of flag officers evinces a dangerous lack of respect.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 20:21:13 -0400</pubDate></item></channel></rss>