<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Merged Defense / NATO / SpaceWar Feed</title><link>https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml</link><description>Aggregated RSS feed from NATO, DefenseOne, and SpaceWar</description><atom:link href="https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 03:28:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Senators call for election-security briefing from intel chief</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/senators-call-election-security-briefing-major-races-draw-closer/408158/</link><description>“We are concerned that you may have directed the Intelligence Community (IC) to cease its intelligence reporting on this vital topic,” the senators wrote to the DNI.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Today’s D Brief: 2nd boat strike; Israel’s Gaza City push; NATO’s Eastern Sentry; Army’s VCs; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/todays-d-brief-2nd-boat-strike-israels-gaza-city-push-natos-eastern-sentry-armys-vcs-and-bit-more/408140/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Russian drone over Romania is an early test of NATO’s ‘Eastern Sentry’ operation</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/russian-drone-over-romania-early-test-natos-eastern-sentry-operation/408134/</link><description>New campaign aims for a more integrated and comprehensive response to Moscow’s incursions, officials said.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 13:06:41 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Pentagon CTO wants AI on every desktop in 6 to 9 months</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2025/09/pentagon-research-official-wants-have-ai-every-desktop-6-9-months/408155/</link><description>Emil Michael said he's spending up to half his time rethinking DOD's AI-deployment strategy.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 16:54:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The Pentagon’s new startup focus is pushing established companies to try new strategies</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/pentagons-new-startup-focus-pushing-established-companies-try-new-strategies/408161/</link><description>Older firms are finding ways to partner with tomorrow’s defense stars.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 23:59:27 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: New industry strategies; National strategy debate; Taiwan’s Anduril missile; AI on every DOD desktop?; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-17-2025/408167/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Returning the Air Force to its expeditionary roots</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/returning-air-force-its-expeditionary-roots/408171/</link><description>Agility and innovation helped win WWII. They will be essential for the next conflict.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 12:44:38 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>US-UK tech partnership likely to be signed Thursday</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/us-uk-tech-partnership-likely-be-signed-thursday/408180/</link><description>The proposed deal would focus on chipmaking, quantum science, data center development, and more.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 15:14:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Data shows more US extremist violence is right-wing than left-wing</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/data-shows-more-extremist-violence-right-wing-left-wing/408184/</link><description>The trends are clear, but more could be done to give policymakers and the public reliable evidence.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 16:58:06 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>State Department CIO hopes agentic AI can help employees</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2025/09/state-department-hopes-use-agentic-ai-assist-employee-tasks-cio-says/408187/</link><description>Tools that could complete tasks across multiple systems would go far beyond the agency’s StateChat chatbot.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 17:07:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: U.S. troops observe Zapad drills; Air Force’s future; Jokes about killing; Cost of Guard’s DC mission; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-18-2025/408194/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 11:46:27 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Senators question legality of strikes on alleged drug boats in Caribbean</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/senators-question-legality-strikes-alleged-drug-boats-caribbean/408200/</link><description>The nominee to lead the Pentagon’s counterterror policy office declined to comment on the administration’s strategy.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 14:18:24 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>AFSOC exercise brings concept created for great-power conflict to the Caribbean</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/afsoc-exercise-brings-concept-created-great-power-conflict-caribbean/408205/</link><description>Last month, U.S. forces “seized” a St. Croix airport in a demonstration of the Agile Combat Employment maneuver scheme.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:20:45 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How the rapid pace of AI connects to China’s threats toward Taiwan</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2025/09/what-rapid-pace-ai-means-chinas-threats-toward-taiwan/408220/</link><description>A hearing Wednesday explored why Taiwanese chips are more prized than ever.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 01:12:55 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: AFSOC’s Caribbean exercise; NATO’s new Ukraine aid-pool; Saudi-Pakistani pact; Back to Bagram?; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-19-2025/408228/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 11:57:50 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>When China plays orbital hide-and-seek, Maui’s telescopes give the US an edge</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2025/09/when-china-plays-orbital-hide-and-seek-mauis-telescopes-give-us-edge/408236/</link><description>In an interview, Space Force’s Saltzman reveals what’s next for the key sensor site.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 15:15:21 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Lockheed’s Skunk Works unveils work on a potential CCA competitor</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/lockheeds-skunk-works-unveils-work-drone-may-compete-future-cca-work/408252/</link><description>Officials say multipurpose Vectis drone is to fly by 2027, have “Indo-Pacific” range.</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 13:30:25 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Another boat strike; Russian jets over Estonia; F-47’s new flight date; Shutdown watch; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-22-2025/408267/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 11:20:49 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Anduril blames CCA delay on push for ‘semi-autonomous’ first flight</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/anduril-blames-cca-delays-push-semi-autonomous-first-flight/408278/</link><description>Air Force officials, who expected the milestone over the summer, now anticipate it by mid-October.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 15:42:19 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>F-47’s first flight expected in 2028</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/defense-systems/2025/09/f-47s-first-flight-expected-2028/408283/</link><description>That’s a year earlier than Air Force officials have previously said Boeing's sixth-gen combat aircraft might take wing.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 15:58:48 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>NATO will ‘not hesitate’ to act if Russian threats continue, says Estonian defense minister</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/nato-will-not-hesitate-act-if-russian-threats-continue-says-estonian-defense-minister/408292/</link><description>An alliance declaration about increased air defenses for Eastern Europe is expected on Tuesday.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 17:38:01 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The China threat goes beyond the Pacific, intel chiefs say</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/china-threat-goes-beyond-pacific-intel-chiefs-say/408293/</link><description>Air and Space Force intelligence chiefs warn of China’s global influence as military partnerships flourish.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 22:58:02 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>China deploys Yaogan 45 satellite on Long March 7A rocket</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/China_deploys_Yaogan_45_satellite_on_Long_March_7A_rocket_999.html</link><description>Tokyo, Japan (SPX) Sep 17, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/long-march-7a-wenchang-hainan-night-launch-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

China has successfully launched the Yaogan 45 remote-sensing satellite into orbit aboard a Long March 7A carrier rocket, the China Aerospace Science and Technology Corp. reported. The rocket lifted off at 10 am Tuesday from the Wenchang Space Launch Center in Hainan province and delivered its payload to the designated orbit. 

Developed by the Shanghai Academy of Spaceflight Technology, Yaog</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:01:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SES to test Cailabs optical ground stations for next generation laser links</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/SES_to_test_Cailabs_optical_ground_stations_for_next_generation_laser_links_999.html</link><description>Paris, France (SPX) Sep 17, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/ses-thales-alenia-space-ses-26-software-defined-geostationary-satellite-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

SES will evaluate new optical ground stations from France-based Cailabs to move space data using laser rather than radio signals. The company aims to lift throughput, harden link security, and ease congestion across increasingly crowded radio frequency bands by tapping optical communications. 

The effort advances space laser links that can reach up to 10 gigabits per second, roughly 100 tim</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:01:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Constellations of Power: Smart Dragon-3 and the Geopolitics of China's Space Strategy</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/Constellations_of_Power_Smart_Dragon_3_and_the_Geopolitics_of_Chinas_Space_Strategy_999.html</link><description>Budapest, Hungary (SPX) Sep 17, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/smart-dragon-3-carrier-rocket-sea-launch-day-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
On 9 September 2025, a Smart Dragon-3 rocket roared to life off the coast of Rizhao City, in eastern China's Shandong Province, carrying 11 Geely-05 satellites into orbit. Conducted from a maritime platform by the Taiyuan Satellite Launch Centre, the mission marked the seventh successful flight of the Smart Dragon-3 and another step forward in China's quest to fuse commercial innovation with nat</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:01:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beijing company sets new thrust record in rocket engine test</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/Beijing_company_sets_new_thrust_record_in_rocket_engine_test_999.html</link><description>Tokyo, Japan (SPX) Sep 17, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/space-pioneer-tl-3-rocket-carrier-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Space Pioneer, a Beijing-based private launch firm, has completed a major ignition test of its TL 3 carrier rocket, establishing a national record for thrust produced by any Chinese privately developed launch vehicle. 

The test took place Monday on an offshore platform in Haiyang, Shandong province. Nine TH-12 liquid oxygen-kerosene engines fired for 30 seconds, generating around 840 metric</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:01:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Two Scandinavian airports temporarily shutter over drone sightings</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Two_Scandinavian_airports_temporarily_shutter_over_drone_sightings_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Sep 22, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/uav-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Two Scandinavian airports shuttered on Monday due to drone sightings, raising concerns about aviation safety in Europe amid Russia's war in Ukraine. 
 Copenhagen Airport, Scandinavia's largest, reopened early Tuesday, though it is warning passengers in a statement that "there will be delays and some cancelled departures." 
 The airport suspended service earlier Monday after "2-3 larg</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:01:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Maxar and AIDC advance Taiwan UAV sector with GPS-jamming resilience software</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Maxar_and_AIDC_advance_Taiwan_UAV_sector_with_GPS_jamming_resilience_software_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Sep 22, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/uav-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Maxar Intelligence has partnered with Taiwan's Aerospace Industrial Development Corporation (AIDC) to integrate its Raptor vision-based navigation software across the country's unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) sector. The collaboration aims to strengthen the reliability of autonomous systems operating in environments where GPS and GNSS signals are denied or jammed. 

Raptor enables drones to ma</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:01:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US lawmaker warns of military 'misunderstanding' risk with China</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/US_lawmaker_warns_of_military_misunderstanding_risk_with_China_999.html</link><description>Beijing (AFP) Sept 23, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/china-usa-butt-heads-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 The leader of a US congressional delegation to China warned Tuesday of the "risk of a misunderstanding" between the two countries' militaries as advances in defence technology move at breakneck speed. 

Adam Smith, the most senior Democrat on Washington's Armed Services Committee, told journalists in Beijing that China needs to talk more about its military with other global powers "for basic d</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:01:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US envoy to UN vows to 'defend every inch of NATO territory'</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/US_envoy_to_UN_vows_to_defend_every_inch_of_NATO_territory_999.html</link><description>United Nations, United States (AFP) Sept 22, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/nato-missile-defence-capability-map-finland-sweden-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Washington's new envoy to the United Nations vowed Monday to "defend every inch of NATO territory" as he addressed an emergency meeting over an incursion by Russian fighter jets into Estonia's air space. 

NATO scrambled jets after three Russian MiG-31 fighters on Friday breached Estonian airspace for some 12 minutes, triggering complaints of a dangerous new provocation and a denial from Mosco</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:01:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>U.N. Security Council to meet on Russia's incursion into Estonia airspace</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/UN_Security_Council_to_on_Russias_incursion_into_Estonia_airspace_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Sep 22, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/superpowers-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 The United Nations Security Council is to convene Monday to address Russia's breach last week of Estonia airspace, according to the European union and NATO member. 
 Kremlin MiG-31 fighter jets flew through Estonian airspace for 12 minutes on Friday, the latest transgression of a foreign national's airspace in recent weeks during Russia's war in Ukraine. 
 Estonia announced the U.N.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:01:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Estonia says UN Security Council to meet over Russian air incursion</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Estonia_says_UN_Security_Council_to_meet_over_Russian_air_incursion_999.html</link><description>Tallinn (AFP) Sept 21, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/un-security-council-empty-marker-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
 Estonia said Sunday the UN Security Council would hold an emergency meeting on the violation of the country's airspace by Russian fighter jets, an incursion condemned by US President Donald Trump. 

NATO forces intercepted three Russian MiG-31 fighters on Friday after they entered Estonian airspace over the Gulf of Finland, triggering complaints of a dangerous new provocation from the transatl</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:01:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IAEA says Iran nuclear diplomacy at a 'difficult juncture'</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/IAEA_says_Iran_nuclear_diplomacy_at_a_difficult_juncture_999.html</link><description>United Nations, United States (AFP) Sept 22, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/international-atomic-energy-agency-iaea-logo-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 The head of the UN's nuclear watchdog, Rafael Grossi, told AFP Monday that diplomatic efforts to resolve the dispute over Iran's nuclear program were at a "difficult juncture" but dialogue would continue. 

The UN Security Council voted on Friday to reimpose UN sanctions that had been frozen, after three European governments activated the "snapback" mechanism in a decade-old nuclear agreement,</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:01:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>North Korea's Kim open to US talks, has 'fond memories' of Trump</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/North_Koreas_Kim_open_to_US_talks_has_fond_memories_of_Trump_999.html</link><description>Seoul (AFP) Sept 22, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/kim-trump-dinner-hanoi-vietnam-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 North Korean leader Kim Jong Un says he has "fond memories" of US President Donald Trump and is open to future talks with the United States - if he can keep his nuclear arsenal. 

Kim met Trump three times for high-profile summits during Trump's first term, before talks collapsed in Hanoi in 2019 over what concessions Pyongyang was prepared to make on its atomic weapons. 

The US demand tha</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:01:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Spain faces uphill battle to cut Israel military ties: experts</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Spain_faces_uphill_battle_to_cut_Israel_military_ties_experts_999.html</link><description>Madrid (AFP) Sept 22, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/milplex-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Spain's drive to cut military ties with Israel over the devastating war in Gaza will face formidable hurdles as cutting-edge Israeli technology is embedded in the armed forces, experts say. 

Socialist Prime Minister Pedro Sanchez announced earlier this month a package of measures aimed at stopping what he called "the genocide in Gaza", including an arms embargo. 

The leftist government sai</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:01:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>York confirms successful deployment and health of 21 satellites for SDA Tranche 1 mission</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/York_confirms_successful_deployment_and_health_of_21_satellites_for_SDA_Tranche_1_mission_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Sep 17, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/northrop-grumman-tranche-1-transport-layer-joint-all-domain-command-control-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

York Space Systems has confirmed first contact and the healthy status of all 21 satellites launched September 10 from Vandenberg Space Force Base for the Space Development Agency's (SDA) Tranche 1 Transport Layer mission, part of the Proliferated Warfighter Space Architecture. 

The satellites were deployed and checked within hours, a milestone that underscores York's high-rate production an</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:01:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HawkEye 360 expands signals intelligence network with operational deployment of Cluster 12</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/HawkEye_360_expands_signals_intelligence_network_with_operational_deployment_of_Cluster_12_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Sep 22, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/spysat-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

HawkEye 360 Inc. has announced that its latest trio of satellites, known as Cluster 12, has reached Full Operational Capability (FOC). The satellites, launched June 26 aboard a Rocket Lab Electron rocket, are now calibrated, commissioned, and integrated into the company's growing constellation, delivering signals intelligence to global customers. 

The mission also carried Kestrel-0A, an exp</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:01:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: China’s global challenge; NATO on Russian incursions; Estonia’s requests; Germany’s big arms plan; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-23-2025/408300/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 11:27:33 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Has Space Force cracked the code on faster acquisition?</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/has-space-force-cracked-code-faster-acquisition/408312/</link><description>Leaders say the service is “disrupting” the Valley of Death, among other innovations.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 15:33:30 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>‘A game changer’: Space Force’s leader aims to debut future operating plans this year</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/game-changer-space-forces-leader-aims-debut-future-operating-plans-year/408320/</link><description>The document will predict future threats, so the service can better prepare for them.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 18:04:31 -0400</pubDate></item></channel></rss>