<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Merged Defense / NATO / SpaceWar Feed</title><link>https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml</link><description>Aggregated RSS feed from NATO, DefenseOne, and SpaceWar</description><atom:link href="https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 11:12:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Poland seeks better counter-drone tech after Russian incursion</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/poland-seeks-better-counter-drone-tech-after-russian-incursion/408522/</link><description>Warsaw’s foreign minister also hopes the U.S. will send more troops to train with its military.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:38:10 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Silicon Valley in St. Louis?</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/10/silicon-valley-st-louis/408542/</link><description>With the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency as its north star, a non-profit is working to get defense tech to put down roots in the Midwest.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 16:49:33 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Hegseth, Vought actions heighten fears about inspector-general independence</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/hegseth-vought-actions-heighten-fears-about-continued-inspector-general-independence/408559/</link><description>Good-government groups and lawmakers from both parties say Trump-administration moves will chill whistleblowing and watchdog offices.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:21:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: War on leaks; IGs, targeted; Guard-deployment sitrep; The next geoint hub?; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-02-2025/408556/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:36:52 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Elon Musk’s SpaceX took money directly from Chinese investors, company insider testifies</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/elon-musks-spacex-took-money-directly-chinese-investors-company-insider-testifies/408557/</link><description>The newly unsealed testimony marks the first time direct Chinese investment in the company has been disclosed, raising new questions about foreign stakes in one of America’s most important military contractors.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:01:58 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>'Shadow economies' are growing. Military planners and operators must take them into account</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/shadow-economies-are-growing-military-planners-and-operators-must-take-them-account/408560/</link><description>Black markets prolong wars, defang sanctions, fray alliances, and help rogue governments and groups survive and thrive.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 13:21:41 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Inside Europe's crash effort to create a 'drone wall'</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2025/10/inside-emergency-effort-create-european-drone-wall/408582/</link><description>More sensors, more maneuverable, less expensive: How the Ukraine war is shaping the future of drone air defense.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:26:08 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Trump declares war on cartels; Feds storm Chicago apartments; Europe’s ‘drone wall’; Shadow economies; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-03-2025/408590/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:19:38 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Shutdown poised to drag into next week as layoff threat looms</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/shutdown-poised-drag-next-week-layoff-threat-looms/408602/</link><description>Senate once again fails to approve spending bill and the two sides remain far divided.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:35:33 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>NGA wants to put its idle PCs to work</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/defense-systems/2025/10/nga-wants-put-its-idle-pcs-work/408603/</link><description>GDIT is networking the agency’s St. Louis workstations to crunch geospatial data even when analysts aren’t around.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:42:55 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Guard deployments on hold; 4th speedboat bombed; Russia strikes Lviv; China’s black-market oil; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-06-2025/408615/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:37:39 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela, US edge toward war footing—but the White House may blink first</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/venezuela-and-us-edge-toward-war-footing-domestic-concerns-international-risks-may-hold-washington-back/408637/</link><description>The Trump administration is increasing the pressure, but domestic concerns, international risks may hold it back.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:30:03 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Hamas has run out of options</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/hamas-has-run-out-options/408639/</link><description>The group's survival now rests on accepting Trump’s plan and political reform.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>More employees set to receive furlough notices as shutdown drags on</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/more-employees-set-receive-furlough-notices-shutdown-drags/408636/</link><description>DOD has not said how long nonexempt civilian employees might be kept working.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:22:40 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Flood of questions leads Missile Defense Agency to push Golden Dome deadline one week</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/10/flood-questions-leads-missile-defense-agency-push-golden-dome-deadline-one-week/408635/</link><description>Pitches for a slice of MDA’s 10-year, up-to-$151 billion contract vehicle are now due Oct. 16.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:38:41 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>OMB quietly deletes reference to law requiring back pay to furloughed feds</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/omb-deletes-reference-law-guaranteeing-backpay-furloughed-feds-shutdown-guidance/408650/</link><description>A White House FAQ now says restitution is only guaranteed to excepted employees forced to work without pay.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:16:46 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Troops to Chicago; Trump’s partisan speech to sailors; F/A-XX OK?; MDA’s big Golden Dome vehicle; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-07-2025/408652/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 11:14:29 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Denied in July, DHS intelligence office resumes efforts to shed staff</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/dhs-intelligence-office-sent-deferred-resignation-offers-shed-staff-recent-months/408661/</link><description>After stakeholders scuttled dramatic cuts, the Office of Intelligence and Analysis is quietly offering buyouts instead.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 15:22:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Skeptical senators grill White House pick to lead Indo-Pacific policy</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/skeptical-senators-grill-white-house-pick-lead-indo-pacific-policy/408674/</link><description>The nominee to be assistant defense secretary for Indo-Pacific security affairs, backed the president's push for Taiwan to spend more.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 19:21:18 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Federal shutdown deals blow to already-hobbled cybersecurity agency</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/federal-shutdown-deals-blow-already-hobbled-cybersecurity-agency/408675/</link><description>Two-thirds of the staff at the nation’s cybersecurity agency are sidelined, opening opportunities for malicious hackers.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 21:46:45 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Senators doubt Asia policy; Jail Illinois leaders, says POTUS; Civil-military ‘crisis’; DHS cuts intel staff; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-08-2025/408684/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 11:26:01 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>It’s time to return Turkey to the F-35 fold, even if we have to get creative</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/its-time-return-turkey-f-35-fold-even-if-we-have-get-creative/408695/</link><description>It's a sticking point that is blocking deeper US-NATO-Turkish defense cooperation.</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 16:07:04 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Legal experts fear Trump admin is ignoring JAGs on cartel strikes, Guard deployments</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/military-legal-experts-fear-trump-admin-ignoring-jags-cartel-strikes-guard-deployments/408699/</link><description>A former military lawyer and a former judge encouraged commanders to stand up to unlawful orders.</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 17:25:15 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Lawmakers call for more defense biotech research as China pursues breakthroughs</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2025/10/lawmakers-call-more-defense-biotech-research-china-pursues-breakthroughs/408700/</link><description>Shelf-stable blood, biological camouflage, and biosensors are just some of the potential innovations.</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 17:36:20 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Stop trying to control every step’ of shipbuilding, senator tells Navy</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/stop-trying-control-every-step-shipbuilding-senator-tells-navy/408703/</link><description>Focus less on requirements and more on outcomes, says Montana’s Sheehy, and the entire Pentagon might get on board.</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 22:57:04 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Next generation interceptor from Raytheon takes aim at drone warfare</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Next_generation_interceptor_from_Raytheon_takes_aim_at_drone_warfare_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Oct 09, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/raytheon-us-army-lids-ounter-uas-uav-drone-test-fire-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Raytheon, an RTX business, has revealed a prototype for its Next Generation Short Range Interceptor (NGSRI), a system designed to replace the combat-proven Stinger missile and meet the growing threat posed by drones and advanced airborne systems. Built with extensive input from soldiers and Marines, the new interceptor promises to fly both faster and farther, while integrating next-level sensing</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:02:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Top UK prosecutor blames government for dropped China spy case</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Top_UK_prosecutor_blames_government_for_dropped_China_spy_case_999.html</link><description>London (AFP) Oct 8, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/cyberwar-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 A high-profile case involving two men accused of spying for China was dropped because the UK government failed to provide evidence Beijing was a security threat, the chief prosecutor has said. 

Prosecutors have come under fire from lawmakers and government officials after charges against two men, including a former parliamentary researcher, were dismissed last month. 

But Director of Publi</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:02:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Germany joins EU nations with plans to shoot down unknown drones</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Germany_joins_EU_nations_with_plans_to_shoot_down_unknown_drones_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Oct 8, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/uav-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Federal authorities in Germany were granted permission to shoot down drones following a series of recent sightings of unknown drones spotted near Munich. 
 The German government's cabinet on Wednesday signed-off on the new reform package that now awaits approval of the Bundestag, the country's parliament. 
 The move came after drones were seen at Munich Airport last week, which led t</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:02:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Guyana strengthens territorial defense with French military support</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Guyana_strengthens_territorial_defense_with_French_military_support_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Oct 8, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/guyana-map-flag-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 During the opening ceremony of the French Embassy in Guyana, President Irfaan Ali said his country was ready to accept the France's offer of technological assistance - including land and maritime radar systems - to monitor Venezuela's movements amid pressure over the Essequibo region. 
 At the event Saturday, Ali confirmed that Guyana and France are cooperating on defense and security a</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:02:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>German police to get power to shoot down drones: minister</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/German_police_to_get_power_to_shoot_down_drones_minister_999.html</link><description>Berlin (AFP) Oct 8, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/auds-anti-uav-drone-system-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 German federal police will soon be allowed to shoot down unmanned aerial vehicles, Interior Minister Alexander Dobrindt said Wednesday, after a spate of drone sightings believed to be Russian efforts to spy and intimidate. 

Unveiling a draft law, Dobrindt said police would be authorised "to take state-of-the-art technical action against drone threats, for example with electromagnetic pulses,</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:02:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Space Systems Command adds second Blue Origin deal to boost vehicle processing at Cape Canaveral</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Space_Systems_Command_adds_second_Blue_Origin_deal_to_boost_vehicle_processing_at_Cape_Canaveral_999.html</link><description>El Segundo CA (SPX) Oct 09, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/blue-origin-new-glenn-ng-1-night-pad-laucher-candj-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Space Systems Command is expanding its space vehicle processing capacity at Cape Canaveral Space Force Station by 2028, awarding Blue Origin a $78.25 million contract. The award is the second National Security Space Launch Space Vehicle Processing Commercial Solutions Opening contract aimed at strengthening responsive and resilient launch operations. 

"This second CSO award reflects our con</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:02:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran dismissees Israel's missile concern as 'made-up threat'</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Iran_dismissees_Israels_missile_concern_as_made-up_threat_999.html</link><description>Tehran (AFP) Oct 7, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/missiles-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Iran on Tuesday dismissed Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's warnings over its missile programme as fabricated, after he alleged the Islamic republic was developing rockets capable of reaching US cities. 

In an interview with US podcaster Ben Shapiro released on Monday, Netanyahu said: "Iran is developing now... intercontinental ballistic missiles for 8,000 kilometre range". 

"Wha</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:02:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran summons EU envoys over bloc's 'interventionist' stance</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Iran_summons_EU_envoys_over_blocs_interventionist_stance_999.html</link><description>Tehran (AFP) Oct 8, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/iran-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Iran summoned envoys from European Union member states to protest the bloc's "interventionist" statements on contested islands in the Strait of Hormuz as well as the Islamic republic's nuclear programme, local media reported Wednesday. 

Iran considers the islands of Greater Tunb, Lesser Tunb and Abu Musa, all near the strategic Strait of Hormuz in the Gulf, as part of its sovereign territory.</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:02:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>North Korea expected to stage military parade as party turns 80</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/North_Korea_expected_to_stage_military_parade_as_party_turns_80_999.html</link><description>Seoul (AFP) Oct 9, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/north-korean-military-parade-pyongyang-kim-jong-un-dais-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 North Korea is set to host top officials from China and Russia to mark 80 years under the ruling Workers' Party, a celebration that is expected to feature a massive military parade showcasing its latest advanced weaponry.  

Planning for the spectacle, which could begin as early as Thursday, has been shrouded in secrecy, with South Korea's military saying the North may stage the parade at nigh</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:02:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Grenade attack in western Iran kills two IRGC members: local media</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Grenade_attack_in_western_Iran_kills_two_IRGC_members_local_media_999.html</link><description>Tehran (AFP) Oct 7, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/iran-revolutionary-guards-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 A grenade attack in western Iran, blamed on militants, killed two members of the country's Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC), including a cleric, local media reported Tuesday. 

The assault, late on Monday, targeted a building belonging to pro-government paramilitary forces near the city of Sarvabad in the western province of Kurdistan and left three other members of the guard corps wou</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:02:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Spanish parliament approves Israel arms embargo</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Spanish_parliament_approves_Israel_arms_embargo_999.html</link><description>Madrid (AFP) Oct 8, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/milplex-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Spanish lawmakers on Wednesday approved the enshrinement in law of an arms embargo on Israel that Prime Minister Pedro Sanchez introduced to end what he called "the genocide in Gaza". 

Parliament backed by 178 votes to 169 the decree announced in September by Sanchez, one of the most virulent critics among world leaders of Israel's devastating two-year-old war in the Palestinian territory.</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:02:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US report says European giant, others sell to Chinese military-linked companies</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/US_report_says_European_giant_others_sell_to_Chinese_military-linked_companies_999.html</link><description>Washington (AFP) Oct 7, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/milplex-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 A US Congressional committee report released Tuesday said that five major semiconductor equipment manufacturers, including European giant ASML, sold $38 billion worth of critical technology to China in 2024, including to companies flagged as US national security threats. 

The House Select Committee on the Strategic Competition between the United States and the Chinese Communist Party found th</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:02:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump unlikely to win Nobel Peace Prize, but who will?</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Trump_unlikely_to_win_Nobel_Peace_Prize_but_who_will_999.html</link><description>Oslo (AFP) Oct 8, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/nobel-peace-prize-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
 When it comes to this year's Nobel Peace Prize, one thing is almost certain: US President Donald Trump will not win, no matter how much he wants it. But who will? 

The Norwegian Nobel Committee in Oslo will bring the suspense to an end when it announces the winner Friday at 11:00 am (0900 GMT). 

The backdrop is bleak: the number of armed conflicts worldwide involving at least one state has</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:02:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia says missile strike kills three in Belgorod region: governor</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Russia_says_missile_strike_kills_three_in_Belgorod_region_governor_999.html</link><description>Moscow (AFP) Oct 8, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/ukraine-russia-belgorod-missile-attack-fuel-depot-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 A missile strike killed three people in a village in Russia's Belgorod region bordering Ukraine on Wednesday, the local governor said. 

"The village of Maslova Pristan in the Shebekinsky District was hit by a missile strike. According to preliminary data, three people were killed and one was wounded," governor Vyacheslav Gladkov said on Telegram, adding that some people could still be trapped</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:02:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU 'must respond' to Russia's 'hybrid warfare': von der Leyen</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/EU_must_respond_to_Russias_hybrid_warfare_von_der_Leyen_999.html</link><description>Strasbourg, France Oct 8, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/ukraine-snow-bohdanivka-russian-flag-hoisted-near-bakhmut-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 EU chief Ursula von der Leyen on Wednesday said Europe must ramp up its defences to deter Russia's "hybrid warfare", after a catalogue of air incursions, cyber attacks and damage to undersea cables. 

"These incidents are calculated to linger in the twilight of deniability. This is not random harassment. It is a coherent and escalating campaign," the European Commission head said in a speech t</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:02:55 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>