<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Merged Defense / NATO / SpaceWar Feed</title><link>https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml</link><description>Aggregated RSS feed from NATO, DefenseOne, and SpaceWar</description><atom:link href="https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 11:11:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Shutdown could erode cyber defenses by sidelining critical staff, experts warn</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/shutdown-could-erode-cyber-defenses-sidelining-critical-staff-experts-warn/408466/</link><description>And it would happen just as a bedrock law on sharing cyber threat data expires.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 18:48:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Don’t let the ‘unequal dialogue’ become a partisan one</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/dont-let-unequal-dialogue-become-partisan-one/408467/</link><description>Secretary Hegseth's short-notice summoning of flag officers evinces a dangerous lack of respect.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 20:21:13 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Hegseth, Trump at Quantico; Shutdown watch; Defense-strategy concerns; Troops-in-streets update; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-30-2025/408474/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 11:55:36 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Shutdown would curtail long-term intelligence work at DOD</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/dod-would-curtail-long-term-intelligence-work-during-government-shutdown/408501/</link><description>Routine spying activities conducted by NSA, the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, and others would continue, but some forward-looking intelligence planning would be halted, a department document shows.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 12:45:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>SecDef uses unprecedented meeting to unveil 10 personnel, due-process reviews</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/secdef-uses-unprecedented-meeting-unveil-10-personnel-due-process-reviews/408483/</link><description>After summoning senior officers from around the world, Hegseth invites them to resign if they don’t agree with him.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 13:13:54 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>NATO members say they’re confident, mostly coordinated on how to deal with Russian drone threats</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/nato-members-say-theyre-confident-mostly-coordinated-how-deal-russian-drone-threats/408509/</link><description>Alliance nations are working to do more together to counter increasing Russian air threats—and downplaying the possibility of a U.S. force reduction in Europe.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 18:34:10 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>As government spirals toward a shutdown, Trump promises mass layoffs</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/government-spirals-toward-shutdown-trump-promising-mass-layoffs/408511/</link><description>A last-ditch effort to keep government funded failed Tuesday night. Agencies will begin furloughing staff on Wednesday.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 19:40:23 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Reactions to Quantico; Shutdown, in effect; USAF chief nom; GOP govs call out troops; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-01-2025/408529/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump administration knocks out at least 15 oversight websites, saying IGs 'lied to the public'</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/government-watchdog-websites-go-dark-omb-withholds-funds-ig-committee/408544/</link><description>It's not a shutdown issue: the White House is withholding funds from the umbrella organization for the government's inspectors general.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 13:54:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Poland seeks better counter-drone tech after Russian incursion</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/poland-seeks-better-counter-drone-tech-after-russian-incursion/408522/</link><description>Warsaw’s foreign minister also hopes the U.S. will send more troops to train with its military.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:38:10 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Silicon Valley in St. Louis?</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/10/silicon-valley-st-louis/408542/</link><description>With the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency as its north star, a non-profit is working to get defense tech to put down roots in the Midwest.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 16:49:33 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Hegseth, Vought actions heighten fears about inspector-general independence</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/hegseth-vought-actions-heighten-fears-about-continued-inspector-general-independence/408559/</link><description>Good-government groups and lawmakers from both parties say Trump-administration moves will chill whistleblowing and watchdog offices.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:21:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: War on leaks; IGs, targeted; Guard-deployment sitrep; The next geoint hub?; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-02-2025/408556/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:36:52 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Elon Musk’s SpaceX took money directly from Chinese investors, company insider testifies</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/elon-musks-spacex-took-money-directly-chinese-investors-company-insider-testifies/408557/</link><description>The newly unsealed testimony marks the first time direct Chinese investment in the company has been disclosed, raising new questions about foreign stakes in one of America’s most important military contractors.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:01:58 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>'Shadow economies' are growing. Military planners and operators must take them into account</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/shadow-economies-are-growing-military-planners-and-operators-must-take-them-account/408560/</link><description>Black markets prolong wars, defang sanctions, fray alliances, and help rogue governments and groups survive and thrive.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 13:21:41 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Inside Europe's crash effort to create a 'drone wall'</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2025/10/inside-emergency-effort-create-european-drone-wall/408582/</link><description>More sensors, more maneuverable, less expensive: How the Ukraine war is shaping the future of drone air defense.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:26:08 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Trump declares war on cartels; Feds storm Chicago apartments; Europe’s ‘drone wall’; Shadow economies; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-03-2025/408590/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:19:38 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Shutdown poised to drag into next week as layoff threat looms</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/shutdown-poised-drag-next-week-layoff-threat-looms/408602/</link><description>Senate once again fails to approve spending bill and the two sides remain far divided.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:35:33 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>NGA wants to put its idle PCs to work</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/defense-systems/2025/10/nga-wants-put-its-idle-pcs-work/408603/</link><description>GDIT is networking the agency’s St. Louis workstations to crunch geospatial data even when analysts aren’t around.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:42:55 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Guard deployments on hold; 4th speedboat bombed; Russia strikes Lviv; China’s black-market oil; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-06-2025/408615/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:37:39 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela, US edge toward war footing—but the White House may blink first</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/venezuela-and-us-edge-toward-war-footing-domestic-concerns-international-risks-may-hold-washington-back/408637/</link><description>The Trump administration is increasing the pressure, but domestic concerns, international risks may hold it back.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:30:03 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Hamas has run out of options</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/hamas-has-run-out-options/408639/</link><description>The group's survival now rests on accepting Trump’s plan and political reform.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>More employees set to receive furlough notices as shutdown drags on</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/more-employees-set-receive-furlough-notices-shutdown-drags/408636/</link><description>DOD has not said how long nonexempt civilian employees might be kept working.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:22:40 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Flood of questions leads Missile Defense Agency to push Golden Dome deadline one week</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/10/flood-questions-leads-missile-defense-agency-push-golden-dome-deadline-one-week/408635/</link><description>Pitches for a slice of MDA’s 10-year, up-to-$151 billion contract vehicle are now due Oct. 16.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:38:41 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Cuba, Nicaragua, Venezuela not invited to Summit of the Americas</title><link>https://www.terradaily.com/reports/Cuba_Nicaragua_Venezuela_not_invited_to_Summit_of_the_Americas_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Oct 2, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/trade-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 The Dominican Republic is preparing to welcome hemispheric leaders to the 10th Summit of the Americas on Dec. 4 to 5 in Punta Cana. But the Cuban, Nicaraguan and Venezuelan governments have been excluded. 
 The Dominican Foreign Ministry confirmed the decision in an official statement. The Caribbean nation holds the rotating presidency of the regional forum, and it invited 32 countries to</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:55:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says U.S. in 'non-international armed conflict' with drug cartels</title><link>https://www.terradaily.com/reports/Trump_says_US_in_non-international_armed_conflict_with_drug_cartels_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Oct 2, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/pirates-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 President Donald Trump last month notified several congressional committees that the United States is in armed conflict with drug cartels that he has designated as terrorist organizations. 
 The notice to relevant congressional committees described drug cartels as "unlawful combatants" and comes after the military struck alleged drug-running vessels in the Caribbean Sea last month, includ</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:55:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Swiss seek mini-drone defence system</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Swiss_seek_mini-drone_defence_system_999.html</link><description>Geneva (AFP) Oct 3, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/uav-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Switzerland's military said Friday it plans to acquire a defence system against "mini-drones", after several European countries recently reported incursions into their airspace, pointing the finger at Russia. 

Following multiple incursions, European leaders are seeking to build an anti-drone "wall" for protection. 

Switzerland is not part of the European Union or the NATO defence alliance,</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:55:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India and China to resume direct flights after 5 years</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/India_and_China_to_resume_direct_flights_after_5_years_999.html</link><description>New Delhi (AFP) Oct 3, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/aerospace-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
 India and China will resume direct flights between their two countries this month after a five-year suspension, officials said, with bookings opening on Friday.  

Direct flights between the world's two most populous countries were suspended during the Covid-19 pandemic in 2020 and were not resumed as tensions grew between Beijing and New Delhi over border disputes. 

Relations between the A</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:55:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hong Kong to install surveillance cameras with AI facial recognition</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Hong_Kong_to_install_surveillance_cameras_with_AI_facial_recognition_999.html</link><description>Hong Kong (AFP) Oct 3, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/cyberwar-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Hong Kong plans to install tens of thousands of surveillance cameras that will make use of AI-powered facial recognition, the city's security chief said on Friday, bringing it closer to China where authorities often monitor public spaces with cutting-edge technology. 

The Chinese finance hub has already installed almost 4,000 closed-circuit television (CCTV) cameras under a police crime-fight</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:55:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hegseth fires Navy chief of staff</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Hegseth_fires_Navy_chief_of_staff_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Oct 4, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/naval-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Secretary of Defense Pete Hegseth on Friday fired U.S. Navy Chief of Staff Jon Harrison after the Senate earlier in the week confirmed Hung Cao as the Navy's undersecretary. 
 Harrison had no military experience prior to being nominated and confirmed as the Navy's chief of staff and oversaw the War Department's realignment of the U.S. Navy's budgeting and policy wings, in addition to mini</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:55:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China's premier to visit North Korea this week</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Chinas_premier_to_visit_North_Korea_this_week_999.html</link><description>Beijing (AFP) Oct 7, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/china-north-korea-collage-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 China's premier will pay an official visit to North Korea this week, Beijing said Tuesday, announcing the high-level diplomatic engagement to the isolated nuclear state. 

Despite periods of strained ties between China and North Korea over Pyongyang's nuclear programme, the neighbours have maintained a close relationship in recent years. 

Premier Li Qiang "will lead a party and government d</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:55:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>From Donbas to the desert: Mali Tuaregs borrow Ukraine's war tactics</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/From_Donbas_to_the_desert_Mali_Tuaregs_borrow_Ukraines_war_tactics_999.html</link><description>Dakar (AFP) Oct 7, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/tuareg-rebels-mali-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 From explosive drones to inflatable decoy vehicles, Tuareg rebels in Mali have increasingly turned to tactics learnt from Ukrainian intelligence to strike the west African country's army and its Russian allies. 

The tactics are reshaping the balance in the conflict between Mali's junta government and the Azawad Liberation Front (FLA), a pro-independence armed coalition of predominantly Tuareg</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:55:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ESA unveils Pulse framework to streamline mission management</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/ESA_unveils_Pulse_framework_to_streamline_mission_management_999.html</link><description>Paris, France (SPX) Sep 30, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/airbus-esa-earth-explorer-mission-biomass-satellite-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

The European Space Agency has launched Pulse, a new initiative designed to transform mission monitoring and control across its expanding portfolio of space operations. Developed under ESA's Operations Directorate, Pulse provides a European, royalty-free, multi-mission solution that spans from spacecraft assembly and integration through to operations in low Earth orbit and deep space. 

Pulse</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:55:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TakeMe2Space and AICRAFT partner to deliver orbital data centre infrastructure</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/TakeMe2Space_and_AICRAFT_partner_to_deliver_orbital_data_centre_infrastructure_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Oct 01, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/data-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

AICRAFT of Australia and India's TakeMe2Space (TM2S) have entered into a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) to integrate AICRAFT's edge computing systems into the TM2S satellite constellation from 2026. The collaboration will begin with a hosted payload mission in 2026, after which AICRAFT's high-performance, low-power edge devices will become a core part of TM2S' orbiting platform. 

This al</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:55:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Navigating through interference at Jammertest</title><link>https://www.gpsdaily.com/reports/Navigating_through_interference_at_Jammertest_999.html</link><description>Paris (ESA) Oct 07, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/jammertest-2024-antennas-esa-arctic-sat-nav-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

is essential to everything from tracking your morning jog to landing air ambulances. But as reliance on satellite navigation grows, so do the risks associated with its interruption, natural or intentional. In its pursuit of strengthening European resilience in navigation, the European Space Agency (ESA) took part in Jammertest. 

Global Navigation Satellite Systems (GNSS) such as the Europea</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:55:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia regularly targeting UK satellites: space command boss</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Russia_regularly_targeting_UK_satellites_space_command_boss_999.html</link><description>London (AFP) Oct 3, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/milspace-comms-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Russia is attempting to jam British military satellites on a regular basis, the head of UK Space Command has said, amid growing tensions between Moscow and some European countries. 

"We're seeing our satellites being jammed by the Russians on a reasonably persistent basis," Major General Paul Tedman told the BBC. 

"They've got payloads on board that can see our satellites and are trying to</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:55:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Firefly Aerospace to Acquire SciTec in $855M Deal Expanding National Security Portfolio</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Firefly_Aerospace_to_Acquire_SciTec_in_855_Million_Deal_Expanding_National_Security_Portfolio_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Oct 07, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/scitec-logo-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Firefly Aerospace (Nasdaq: FLY) has announced a definitive agreement to acquire SciTec, Inc., a recognized leader in advanced national security technologies, in a transaction valued at approximately $855 million. The deal combines $300 million in cash and $555 million in Firefly shares, issued to SciTec's owners at $50 per share. 

"The acquisition of SciTec enhances our ability to support a</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:55:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lockheed Martin Sikorsky unveils scalable Nomad drone family for autonomous long-range missions</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Lockheed_Martin_Sikorsky_unveils_scalable_Nomad_drone_family_for_autonomous_long_range_missions_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Oct 07, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/sikorsky-nomad-rendering-2025-uav-drone-family-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
Less than a year after validating its rotor blown wing vertical take-off and landing (VTOL) uncrewed aircraft in flight tests, Sikorsky, a Lockheed Martin company (NYSE: LMT), has introduced the Nomad family of long-endurance, runway-independent drones. 

The twin proprotor system merges helicopter-style agility with fixed-wing speed and range. Each Nomad platform can lift off vertically, ho</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:55:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Revolutionising the Skies: How Helsing's CA-1 Europa Drone Could Transform Autonomous Warfare</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Revolutionising_the_Skies_How_Helsings_CA_1_Europa_Drone_Could_Transform_Autonomous_Warfare_999.html</link><description>Budapest, Hungary (SPX) Oct 06, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/uav-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Amid rising geopolitical tensions, Europe is accelerating its push into autonomous military technology. German AI defence firm Helsing recently unveiled its fully autonomous combat drone, the CA-1 Europa, with operational deployment targeted for 2029. More than a drone, the CA-1 Europa could signal a strategic shift in how European forces plan, respond, and assert independence in aerial combat.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:55:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>