<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Merged Defense / NATO / SpaceWar Feed</title><link>https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml</link><description>Aggregated RSS feed from NATO, DefenseOne, and SpaceWar</description><atom:link href="https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 20:14:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>China, China, Chi—wait, what? Air Force mulls next steps amid homeland focus</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/china-china-chiwait-what-air-force-mulls-next-steps-amid-homeland-focus/408392/</link><description>Officials tout applicability of ongoing modernization, but experts and former officials have doubts.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 16:52:06 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Air Force’s AI ambitions mean simplifying its tangle of networks</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/defense-systems/2025/09/air-forces-ai-ambitions-mean-simplifying-its-tangle-networks/408397/</link><description>Over the next year, battle-networks chief aims to reduce systems to a “rational number.”</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 18:56:21 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How Trump can make defense reform stick</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/how-trump-can-make-defense-reform-stick/408383/</link><description>It will require sustained presidential attention and unprecendented transparency.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Defense One Radio, Ep. 195: Europe's growing defense industry</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/defense-one-radio-ep-195-europes-growing-defense-industry/408388/</link><description>The EU's ambassador to the U.S. underscores the importance of the bloc's $910 billion defense plans known as Readiness 2030.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 10:34:18 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: DOD sheds 60K civilians; EU warns Moscow; USAF’s new ‘homeland’ focus; China’s airborne gets help; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-26-2025/408407/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 11:21:29 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>SOCOM to get robotic anti-drone turret for maritime platforms</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/socom-get-robotic-anti-drone-tech-maritime-platforms/408418/</link><description>Defense tech startup Allen Control Systems landed a contract for Bullfrog, which can use a variety of common weapons.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 16:10:54 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Two mass shootings; Troops to Portland?; Trump to join Hegseth-brass confab; Arrested by ICE for “how they look”; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-29-2025/408439/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 11:21:45 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Military AI needs guardrails—not to slow it down, but to keep it useful</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/military-ai-needs-guardrailsnot-slow-it-down-keep-it-useful/408452/</link><description>Modifying commercial models isn’t as easy as removing the parts that discourage users from killing people.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 16:50:36 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Shutdown could erode cyber defenses by sidelining critical staff, experts warn</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/shutdown-could-erode-cyber-defenses-sidelining-critical-staff-experts-warn/408466/</link><description>And it would happen just as a bedrock law on sharing cyber threat data expires.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 18:48:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Don’t let the ‘unequal dialogue’ become a partisan one</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/dont-let-unequal-dialogue-become-partisan-one/408467/</link><description>Secretary Hegseth's short-notice summoning of flag officers evinces a dangerous lack of respect.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 20:21:13 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Hegseth, Trump at Quantico; Shutdown watch; Defense-strategy concerns; Troops-in-streets update; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-30-2025/408474/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 11:55:36 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Shutdown would curtail long-term intelligence work at DOD</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/dod-would-curtail-long-term-intelligence-work-during-government-shutdown/408501/</link><description>Routine spying activities conducted by NSA, the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, and others would continue, but some forward-looking intelligence planning would be halted, a department document shows.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 12:45:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>SecDef uses unprecedented meeting to unveil 10 personnel, due-process reviews</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/secdef-uses-unprecedented-meeting-unveil-10-personnel-due-process-reviews/408483/</link><description>After summoning senior officers from around the world, Hegseth invites them to resign if they don’t agree with him.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 13:13:54 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>NATO members say they’re confident, mostly coordinated on how to deal with Russian drone threats</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/nato-members-say-theyre-confident-mostly-coordinated-how-deal-russian-drone-threats/408509/</link><description>Alliance nations are working to do more together to counter increasing Russian air threats—and downplaying the possibility of a U.S. force reduction in Europe.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 18:34:10 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>As government spirals toward a shutdown, Trump promises mass layoffs</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/government-spirals-toward-shutdown-trump-promising-mass-layoffs/408511/</link><description>A last-ditch effort to keep government funded failed Tuesday night. Agencies will begin furloughing staff on Wednesday.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 19:40:23 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Reactions to Quantico; Shutdown, in effect; USAF chief nom; GOP govs call out troops; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-01-2025/408529/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump administration knocks out at least 15 oversight websites, saying IGs 'lied to the public'</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/government-watchdog-websites-go-dark-omb-withholds-funds-ig-committee/408544/</link><description>It's not a shutdown issue: the White House is withholding funds from the umbrella organization for the government's inspectors general.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 13:54:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Poland seeks better counter-drone tech after Russian incursion</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/poland-seeks-better-counter-drone-tech-after-russian-incursion/408522/</link><description>Warsaw’s foreign minister also hopes the U.S. will send more troops to train with its military.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:38:10 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Silicon Valley in St. Louis?</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/10/silicon-valley-st-louis/408542/</link><description>With the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency as its north star, a non-profit is working to get defense tech to put down roots in the Midwest.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 16:49:33 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Beyond Gravity wins order to build robotic thruster mechanisms for HummingSat satellites</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/Beyond_Gravity_wins_order_to_build_robotic_thruster_mechanisms_for_HummingSat_satellites_999.html</link><description>Berlin, Germany (SPX) Sep 30, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/swissto12-hummingsat-geostationary-satellite-inmarsat-l-band-network-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Beyond Gravity has secured a contract to supply robotic thruster pointing mechanisms for five HummingSat geostationary telecommunications satellites being developed by Swiss satellite manufacturer SWISSto12. The multi-axis robotic arms will control the satellites' electric propulsion systems, keeping them on station 35,786 kilometers above Earth. 

"With this thruster pointing mechanism, we</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 07:04:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Long March 2D reaches 100th mission milestone with dual satellite launch</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/Long_March_2D_reaches_100th_mission_milestone_with_dual_satellite_launch_999.html</link><description>Tokyo, Japan (SPX) Sep 30, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/china-long-march-2d-carrier-rocket-xichang-night-launch-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

The Long March 2D rocket has completed its 100th successful flight, placing two experimental satellites into orbit in a milestone mission for China's space program. 

The vehicle lifted off at 11 am local time from the Xichang Satellite Launch Center in Sichuan province, carrying Shiyan 30A and 30B. Both satellites were deployed into their planned orbits, according to China Aerospace Science</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 07:04:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kinetica 2 rocket on track for inaugural mission in 2025</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/Kinetica_2_rocket_on_track_for_inaugural_mission_in_2025_999.html</link><description>Tokyo, Japan (SPX) Sep 29, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/china-cas-space-kinetica-1-rocket-model-launch-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

CAS Space, a subsidiary of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, is completing development of its new Kinetica 2 rocket and aims to launch it before the end of 2025. The company confirmed that the first vehicle has been assembled and is undergoing integrated testing ahead of its debut flight in the fourth quarter. That mission will also introduce a new robotic cargo ship named Qingzhou, or Light Ship</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 07:04:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SFL Missions to Deliver Spacecraft Buses for HawkEye 360 RF Signal Detection Expansion</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/SFL_Missions_to_Deliver_Spacecraft_Buses_for_HawkEye_360_RF_Signal_Detection_Expansion_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Sep 29, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/hawkeye-360-logo-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
SFL Missions Inc. has secured a contract to build spacecraft bus units for three new HawkEye 360 satellite clusters, adding nine spacecraft to the company's expanding constellation for RF signal detection and geolocation. The order covers Cluster 14, which follows earlier designs, and Clusters 15 and 16, which incorporate advanced capabilities. 

Through its Flex Production program, SFL Miss</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 07:04:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia blamed for GPS attack on Spanish defence minister's plane</title><link>https://www.gpsdaily.com/reports/Russia_blamed_for_GPS_attack_on_Spanish_defence_ministers_plane_999.html</link><description>Madrid (AFP) Sept 24, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/gps-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 A plane carrying Spain's defence minister suffered an attack on its GPS navigation while flying near Russia's exclave of Kaliningrad on Wednesday, a ministry source said, the latest such incident blamed on Moscow. 

"There was an attempt to scramble the GPS signal" of the plane transporting Margarita Robles to Lithuania, the defence ministry source said, adding that the flight had an encrypted</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 07:04:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NASA begins testing PExT wideband communications system in orbit</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/NASA_begins_testing_PExT_wideband_communications_system_in_orbit_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Sep 29, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/wideband-global-satcom-wgs-11+-orbit-marker-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Payload commissioning has started for NASA's Polylingual Experimental Terminal (PExT), a pioneering wideband space communications technology designed to connect spacecraft with both government and commercial networks. 

The demonstration rides aboard York Space Systems' Bard satellite, launched on July 23. The satellite completed its bus commissioning within four weeks, validating key system</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 07:04:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Planet captures first light from Pelican-3 satellite as constellation expands</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/Planet_captures_first_light_from_Pelican_3_satellite_as_constellation_expands_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Sep 29, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/planet-labs-pelican-satellite-constellation-marker-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Planet Labs PBC (NYSE: PL) has released the first light image from its Pelican-3 satellite, capturing Turin, Italy on September 5 from an altitude of 458 km. The spacecraft, launched on August 26 aboard a SpaceX Falcon 9 NAOS mission with Pelican-4, is currently undergoing instrument calibration before entering full operations. 

CEO Will Marshall said the rapid imaging highlights the Pelica</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 07:04:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Commcrete shrinks satcom on the move with 29M to miniaturize antennas to three centimeters</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/Commcrete_shrinks_satcom_on_the_move_with_29M_to_miniaturize_antennas_to_three_centimeters_999.html</link><description>Tel Aviv Israel (SPX) Oct 01, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/iraq-am-general-humvee-hmmwv-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Commcrete has raised 29 million dollars across Seed and Series A financing to scale ultra compact tactical satellite communications. The 21 million dollar Series A was led by Greenfield Partners with Redseed Ventures and existing backers, following a Seed round that included Prof. Amnon Shashua, Q Fund and private angels. 

The company says its handheld, omni directional platform keeps secur</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 07:04:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Orbital Internet Exchange plans unveiled by DE-CIX</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/Orbital_Internet_Exchange_plans_unveiled_by_DE_CIX_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Sep 29, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/spideroak-orbitsecure-cybersecurity-command-control-satellites-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

DE-CIX, the world's largest operator of Internet Exchanges, is extending its interconnection model beyond Earth. Through its Space-IX program, the company is laying the foundation for the first orbital Internet Exchange, enabling satellites and space-based systems to link seamlessly with terrestrial networks. 

Building on its network of 60 global IX locations that connect more than 4,000 pr</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 07:04:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>GPU powered satellite propagation tool launched by Kayhan Space</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/GPU_powered_satellite_propagation_tool_launched_by_Kayhan_Space_999.html</link><description>Broomfield CO (SPX) Oct 01, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/kayhan-space-logo-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Kayhan Space has released sgp4.gl, a GPU-accelerated version of the standard SGP4 propagator designed for real-time, browser-based satellite visualization at scale. The tool enables smooth rendering of thousands of satellite tracks simultaneously, addressing performance challenges as orbital catalogs grow. 

Traditional CPU-driven visualization often suffers from degraded frame rates when ha</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 07:04:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Elbit secures 120 million order for Hermes 900 maritime surveillance UAS</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Elbit_secures_120_million_order_for_Hermes_900_maritime_surveillance_UAS_999.html</link><description>Paris, France (SPX) Sep 30, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/uav-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Elbit Systems has received a contract worth approximately $120 million to supply its Hermes 900 Unmanned Aerial System for long-range maritime surveillance to an international customer. The award underscores sustained global demand for the companys high-performance unmanned capabilities. 

The Hermes 900 is Elbits largest MALE platform, designed for multi-mission operations including area do</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 07:04:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China tests effects of successive nuclear strikes</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/China_tests_effects_of_successive_nuclear_strikes_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Oct 1, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/nuclear-doctrine-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Chinese military researchers recently reported that multiple nuclear strikes on a single target will produce greater damage than a single blast from a larger warhead to destroy hard targets. 
 The researchers examined the effect of three nuclear strikes on a single target in rapid succession in a laboratory study published in a peer-reviewed journal. 
 The study examined how three su</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 07:04:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Moldova backs EU in elections marred by Russian interference</title><link>https://www.terradaily.com/reports/Moldova_backs_EU_in_elections_marred_by_Russian_interference_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Sep 29, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/transdniestr-moldova-map-transnistria-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Moldova's pro-Europe party of President Maia Sandu has claimed victory in Parliamentary elections that are being framed as a repudiation of Russia and its alleged actions to undermine the small nation's democracy. 
 The Sunday contest is also being seen as a win for Moldova's bid to join the European Union, which it has sought since Russia's invasion of Ukraine, fearing it could be the Kr</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 07:04:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>We can build fighter jet without Germany: France's Dassault</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/We_can_build_fighter_jet_without_Germany_Frances_Dassault_999.html</link><description>Cergy-Pontoise, France (AFP) Sept 23, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/jet-rafale-dassault-300-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 The head of French defence company Dassault said on Tuesday his firm could build the future European fighter jet by itself, as tensions persist with Germany over the multi-billion-euro project. 

The Future Combat Air System (FCAS) programme was launched in 2017 to replace France's Rafale jet and the Eurofighter planes used by Germany and Spain. 

But the scheme, jointly developed by the thr</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 07:04:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Northrop Grumman Hypersonic Navigation System Exceeds Rocket Test Milestones</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/Northrop_Grumman_Hypersonic_Navigation_System_Exceeds_Rocket_Test_Milestones_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Sep 29, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/northrop-grumman-hypersonic-attack-cruise-missile-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Northrop Grumman's Advanced Hypersonic Technology Inertial Measurement Unit (AHT IMU) has surpassed expectations in its third major test, this time onboard a sounding rocket. The trial confirmed the unit's ability to withstand extreme g-forces, altitudes, and velocities beyond projected limits. 

The navigation system demonstrated reliable operation in GPS-denied environments, validating its</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 07:04:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hegseth, Vought actions heighten fears about inspector-general independence</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/hegseth-vought-actions-heighten-fears-about-continued-inspector-general-independence/408559/</link><description>Good-government groups and lawmakers from both parties say Trump-administration moves will chill whistleblowing and watchdog offices.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:21:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: War on leaks; IGs, targeted; Guard-deployment sitrep; The next geoint hub?; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-02-2025/408556/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:36:52 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Elon Musk’s SpaceX took money directly from Chinese investors, company insider testifies</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/elon-musks-spacex-took-money-directly-chinese-investors-company-insider-testifies/408557/</link><description>The newly unsealed testimony marks the first time direct Chinese investment in the company has been disclosed, raising new questions about foreign stakes in one of America’s most important military contractors.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:01:58 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>'Shadow economies' are growing. Military planners and operators must take them into account</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/shadow-economies-are-growing-military-planners-and-operators-must-take-them-account/408560/</link><description>Black markets prolong wars, defang sanctions, fray alliances, and help rogue governments and groups survive and thrive.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 13:21:41 -0400</pubDate></item></channel></rss>