<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Merged Defense / NATO / SpaceWar Feed</title><link>https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml</link><description>Aggregated RSS feed from NATO, DefenseOne, and SpaceWar</description><atom:link href="https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:14:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Shutdown could erode cyber defenses by sidelining critical staff, experts warn</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/shutdown-could-erode-cyber-defenses-sidelining-critical-staff-experts-warn/408466/</link><description>And it would happen just as a bedrock law on sharing cyber threat data expires.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 18:48:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Don’t let the ‘unequal dialogue’ become a partisan one</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/dont-let-unequal-dialogue-become-partisan-one/408467/</link><description>Secretary Hegseth's short-notice summoning of flag officers evinces a dangerous lack of respect.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 20:21:13 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Hegseth, Trump at Quantico; Shutdown watch; Defense-strategy concerns; Troops-in-streets update; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-30-2025/408474/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 11:55:36 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Shutdown would curtail long-term intelligence work at DOD</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/dod-would-curtail-long-term-intelligence-work-during-government-shutdown/408501/</link><description>Routine spying activities conducted by NSA, the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, and others would continue, but some forward-looking intelligence planning would be halted, a department document shows.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 12:45:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>SecDef uses unprecedented meeting to unveil 10 personnel, due-process reviews</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/secdef-uses-unprecedented-meeting-unveil-10-personnel-due-process-reviews/408483/</link><description>After summoning senior officers from around the world, Hegseth invites them to resign if they don’t agree with him.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 13:13:54 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>NATO members say they’re confident, mostly coordinated on how to deal with Russian drone threats</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/nato-members-say-theyre-confident-mostly-coordinated-how-deal-russian-drone-threats/408509/</link><description>Alliance nations are working to do more together to counter increasing Russian air threats—and downplaying the possibility of a U.S. force reduction in Europe.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 18:34:10 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>As government spirals toward a shutdown, Trump promises mass layoffs</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/government-spirals-toward-shutdown-trump-promising-mass-layoffs/408511/</link><description>A last-ditch effort to keep government funded failed Tuesday night. Agencies will begin furloughing staff on Wednesday.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 19:40:23 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Reactions to Quantico; Shutdown, in effect; USAF chief nom; GOP govs call out troops; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-01-2025/408529/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump administration knocks out at least 15 oversight websites, saying IGs 'lied to the public'</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/government-watchdog-websites-go-dark-omb-withholds-funds-ig-committee/408544/</link><description>It's not a shutdown issue: the White House is withholding funds from the umbrella organization for the government's inspectors general.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 13:54:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Poland seeks better counter-drone tech after Russian incursion</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/poland-seeks-better-counter-drone-tech-after-russian-incursion/408522/</link><description>Warsaw’s foreign minister also hopes the U.S. will send more troops to train with its military.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:38:10 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Silicon Valley in St. Louis?</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/10/silicon-valley-st-louis/408542/</link><description>With the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency as its north star, a non-profit is working to get defense tech to put down roots in the Midwest.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 16:49:33 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Hegseth, Vought actions heighten fears about inspector-general independence</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/hegseth-vought-actions-heighten-fears-about-continued-inspector-general-independence/408559/</link><description>Good-government groups and lawmakers from both parties say Trump-administration moves will chill whistleblowing and watchdog offices.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:21:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: War on leaks; IGs, targeted; Guard-deployment sitrep; The next geoint hub?; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-02-2025/408556/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:36:52 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Elon Musk’s SpaceX took money directly from Chinese investors, company insider testifies</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/elon-musks-spacex-took-money-directly-chinese-investors-company-insider-testifies/408557/</link><description>The newly unsealed testimony marks the first time direct Chinese investment in the company has been disclosed, raising new questions about foreign stakes in one of America’s most important military contractors.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:01:58 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>'Shadow economies' are growing. Military planners and operators must take them into account</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/shadow-economies-are-growing-military-planners-and-operators-must-take-them-account/408560/</link><description>Black markets prolong wars, defang sanctions, fray alliances, and help rogue governments and groups survive and thrive.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 13:21:41 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Inside Europe's crash effort to create a 'drone wall'</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2025/10/inside-emergency-effort-create-european-drone-wall/408582/</link><description>More sensors, more maneuverable, less expensive: How the Ukraine war is shaping the future of drone air defense.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:26:08 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Trump declares war on cartels; Feds storm Chicago apartments; Europe’s ‘drone wall’; Shadow economies; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-03-2025/408590/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:19:38 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Shutdown poised to drag into next week as layoff threat looms</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/shutdown-poised-drag-next-week-layoff-threat-looms/408602/</link><description>Senate once again fails to approve spending bill and the two sides remain far divided.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:35:33 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>NGA wants to put its idle PCs to work</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/defense-systems/2025/10/nga-wants-put-its-idle-pcs-work/408603/</link><description>GDIT is networking the agency’s St. Louis workstations to crunch geospatial data even when analysts aren’t around.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:42:55 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Guard deployments on hold; 4th speedboat bombed; Russia strikes Lviv; China’s black-market oil; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-06-2025/408615/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:37:39 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela, US edge toward war footing—but the White House may blink first</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/venezuela-and-us-edge-toward-war-footing-domestic-concerns-international-risks-may-hold-washington-back/408637/</link><description>The Trump administration is increasing the pressure, but domestic concerns, international risks may hold it back.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:30:03 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Hamas has run out of options</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/hamas-has-run-out-options/408639/</link><description>The group's survival now rests on accepting Trump’s plan and political reform.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>More employees set to receive furlough notices as shutdown drags on</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/more-employees-set-receive-furlough-notices-shutdown-drags/408636/</link><description>DOD has not said how long nonexempt civilian employees might be kept working.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:22:40 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Flood of questions leads Missile Defense Agency to push Golden Dome deadline one week</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/10/flood-questions-leads-missile-defense-agency-push-golden-dome-deadline-one-week/408635/</link><description>Pitches for a slice of MDA’s 10-year, up-to-$151 billion contract vehicle are now due Oct. 16.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:38:41 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia Japan partnership to accelerate laser links for satellites</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/Australia_Japan_partnership_to_accelerate_laser_links_for_satellites_999.html</link><description>Sydney, Australia (SPX) Sep 30, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/laser-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

A new collaboration between the University of South Australia, Adelaide start-up RapidBeam, and Japan's Warpspace aims to speed development of next-generation space laser communications. The agreement targets faster, more secure, and more reliable data transfer than today's radio-based systems for missions spanning Earth observation to deep space. 

At the core is Warpspace's HOCSAI optical</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:41:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>German military satellites to fly on Ariane 6 under new Arianespace contract</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/German_military_satellites_to_fly_on_Ariane_6_under_new_Arianespace_contract_999.html</link><description>Paris, France (SPX) Sep 25, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/ariane-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Arianespace has secured a contract to launch two SATCOMBw Stufe 3 satellites for the German Armed Forces using Ariane 6 heavy-lift rockets from Europe's Spaceport in French Guiana. The new satellites will replace the Bundeswehr's COMSATBw 1 and 2 communications platforms. 

Airbus serves as prime contractor for the SATCOMBw Stufe 3 program, responsible for satellite design, integration, test</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:41:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Germany vows defence against Russia in drone warfare and in space</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Germany_vows_defence_against_Russia_in_drone_warfare_and_in_space_999.html</link><description>Berlin (AFP) Sept 25, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/milspace-comms-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Germany said Thursday it would step up its defences - from drone warfare to outer space - at a time of growing tensions between Russia and NATO while the Ukraine war grinds on. 

Recent weeks have seen Russia send fighter jets and drones into NATO airspace in Poland and Romania, followed by suspicious drone flights near airports in Denmark and Norway. 

German Chancellor Friedrich Merz -</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:41:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran says will not resume nuclear talks with Europeans 'at this stage'</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Iran_says_will_not_resume_nuclear_talks_with_Europeans_at_this_stage_999.html</link><description>Tehran (AFP) Oct 6, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/iran-flag-nuclear-plant-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Iran does not plan to immediately resume nuclear talks with European nations after they reimposed sanctions, the foreign ministry said on Monday. 

Britain, France and Germany, signatories to Iran's 2015 nuclear deal, reimposed sanctions on September 28, triggering in turn the return of UN sanctions under the so-called snapback mechanism. 

"We have no plans for negotiations at this stage,"</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:41:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Defense contractors brace for climate threats despite Trump's denials</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Defense_contractors_brace_for_climate_threats_despite_Trumps_denials_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Oct 2, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/milplex-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 President Donald Trump repeatedly calls climate change a "hoax," but the nation's five largest defense contractors say they are challenged to balance the Earth's warming with operational demands, technological adaptations and emission liabilities, according to a review of their filings with the Securities and Exchange Commission. 
 Lockheed Martin, RTX, Northrop Grumman, General Dynamics</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:41:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>UK expands international space ties with 23 new collaborations</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/UK_expands_international_space_ties_with_23_new_collaborations_999.html</link><description>London, UK (SPX) Sep 30, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/industry-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

A fresh wave of 23 projects will extend the UK's international reach in space science and technology, the UK Space Agency confirmed during the International Astronautical Congress in Sydney. 

Backed by GBP 6.5 million from the International Bilateral Fund (IBF), this initiative connects UK universities and companies with partners in the US, Australia, Canada, France, Germany, India, Japan,</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:41:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Terran Orbital finalizes Tranche 1 satellite bus delivery for Lockheed Martin</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Terran_Orbital_finalizes_Tranche_1_satellite_bus_delivery_for_Lockheed_Martin_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Sep 25, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/lockheed-martin-terran-orbital-logo-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Terran Orbital Corporation has completed delivery of all 42 satellite bus platforms for the Space Development Agency's Tranche 1 Transport Layer program. The spacecraft, built in partnership with Lockheed Martin, will support a resilient low-Earth orbit communications network providing secure, low-latency data links for U.S. and allied forces worldwide. 

"Completing delivery of all satellit</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:41:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Starcloud partners with Mission Space to protect orbital datacenters with real time space weather intelligence</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/Starcloud_partners_with_Mission_Space_to_protect_orbital_datacenters_with_real_time_space_weather_intelligence_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Sep 22, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/esa-space-situational-awareness-weather-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Mission Space, a space weather intelligence provider, has entered a strategic partnership with orbital datacenter company Starcloud to embed real-time space weather forecasting into orbital AI compute infrastructure. 

The integration will supply Starcloud with high-resolution data and predictive analytics, allowing its orbital platforms to dynamically adjust power and thermal management to</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:41:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Maintaining US space dominance requires rapid and reliable delivery of new systems</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Maintaining_US_space_dominance_requires_rapid_and_reliable_delivery_of_new_systems_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Sep 25, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/raytheon-intelligence-space-next-gen-opir-geo-marker-satellite-milspace-comms-misisle-icbm-warning-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Winning in space depends on accelerating the way capabilities are developed and delivered, Chief of Space Operations Gen. Chance Saltzman told thousands attending the Air, Space and Cyber Conference on Sept. 23. He emphasized that future superiority hinges on force design, system acquisition, and delivering tools Guardians can employ immediately. 

Saltzman cited recent progress in GPS accur</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:41:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China exiles in Thailand lose hope, fearing Beijing's long reach</title><link>https://www.terradaily.com/reports/China_exiles_in_Thailand_lose_hope_fearing_Beijings_long_reach_999.html</link><description>Bangkok (AFP) Oct 7, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/china-beijing-tiananmen-square-marker-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
 With tears rolling down his cheeks, detained Chinese political exile Zhou Junyi struggles to make his voice heard over dozens of families visiting Bangkok's main immigration detention centre. 

Zhou's China Democracy Party, an exile group, organised a commemoration on June 4 in Kanchanaburi, west of Bangkok, for the victims of the 1989 Tiananmen Square crackdown in Beijing. 

"Chinese people</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:41:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Navigating through interference at Jammertest</title><link>https://www.gpsdaily.com/reports/Navigating_through_interference_at_Jammertest_999.html</link><description>Paris (ESA) Oct 07, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/jammertest-2024-antennas-esa-arctic-sat-nav-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

is essential to everything from tracking your morning jog to landing air ambulances. But as reliance on satellite navigation grows, so do the risks associated with its interruption, natural or intentional. In its pursuit of strengthening European resilience in navigation, the European Space Agency (ESA) took part in Jammertest. 

Global Navigation Satellite Systems (GNSS) such as the Europea</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:41:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lockheed Martin Sikorsky unveils scalable Nomad drone family for autonomous long-range missions</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Lockheed_Martin_Sikorsky_unveils_scalable_Nomad_drone_family_for_autonomous_long_range_missions_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Oct 07, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/sikorsky-nomad-rendering-2025-uav-drone-family-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
Less than a year after validating its rotor blown wing vertical take-off and landing (VTOL) uncrewed aircraft in flight tests, Sikorsky, a Lockheed Martin company (NYSE: LMT), has introduced the Nomad family of long-endurance, runway-independent drones. 

The twin proprotor system merges helicopter-style agility with fixed-wing speed and range. Each Nomad platform can lift off vertically, ho</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:41:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukraine finds Western parts in Russian drones, missiles: Zelensky</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Ukraine_finds_Western_parts_in_Russian_drones_missiles_Zelensky_999.html</link><description>Kyiv, Ukraine (AFP) Oct 6, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/ukraine-russian-drone-uav-bombed-city-town-homes-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Ukraine found tens of thousands of foreign parts, some Western-made, in Russian drones and missiles fired on Ukraine over the weekend, Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said Monday. 

"During the massive combined strike on Ukraine on the night of October 5, Russia used 549 weapon systems containing 102,785 foreign-made components," Zelensky said on social media, referring to an attack in</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:41:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China's premier to visit North Korea this week</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Chinas_premier_to_visit_North_Korea_this_week_999.html</link><description>Beijing (AFP) Oct 7, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/china-north-korea-collage-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 China's premier will pay an official visit to North Korea this week, Beijing said Tuesday, announcing the high-level diplomatic engagement to the isolated nuclear state. 

Despite periods of strained ties between China and North Korea over Pyongyang's nuclear programme, the neighbours have maintained a close relationship in recent years. 

Premier Li Qiang "will lead a party and government d</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:41:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Firefly Aerospace to Acquire SciTec in $855M Deal Expanding National Security Portfolio</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Firefly_Aerospace_to_Acquire_SciTec_in_855_Million_Deal_Expanding_National_Security_Portfolio_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Oct 07, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/scitec-logo-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Firefly Aerospace (Nasdaq: FLY) has announced a definitive agreement to acquire SciTec, Inc., a recognized leader in advanced national security technologies, in a transaction valued at approximately $855 million. The deal combines $300 million in cash and $555 million in Firefly shares, issued to SciTec's owners at $50 per share. 

"The acquisition of SciTec enhances our ability to support a</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:41:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>