<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Merged Defense / NATO / SpaceWar Feed</title><link>https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml</link><description>Aggregated RSS feed from NATO, DefenseOne, and SpaceWar</description><atom:link href="https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 11:11:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>NATO members say they’re confident, mostly coordinated on how to deal with Russian drone threats</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/nato-members-say-theyre-confident-mostly-coordinated-how-deal-russian-drone-threats/408509/</link><description>Alliance nations are working to do more together to counter increasing Russian air threats—and downplaying the possibility of a U.S. force reduction in Europe.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 18:34:10 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>As government spirals toward a shutdown, Trump promises mass layoffs</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/government-spirals-toward-shutdown-trump-promising-mass-layoffs/408511/</link><description>A last-ditch effort to keep government funded failed Tuesday night. Agencies will begin furloughing staff on Wednesday.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 19:40:23 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Reactions to Quantico; Shutdown, in effect; USAF chief nom; GOP govs call out troops; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-01-2025/408529/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump administration knocks out at least 15 oversight websites, saying IGs 'lied to the public'</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/government-watchdog-websites-go-dark-omb-withholds-funds-ig-committee/408544/</link><description>It's not a shutdown issue: the White House is withholding funds from the umbrella organization for the government's inspectors general.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 13:54:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Poland seeks better counter-drone tech after Russian incursion</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/poland-seeks-better-counter-drone-tech-after-russian-incursion/408522/</link><description>Warsaw’s foreign minister also hopes the U.S. will send more troops to train with its military.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:38:10 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Silicon Valley in St. Louis?</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/10/silicon-valley-st-louis/408542/</link><description>With the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency as its north star, a non-profit is working to get defense tech to put down roots in the Midwest.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 16:49:33 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Hegseth, Vought actions heighten fears about inspector-general independence</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/hegseth-vought-actions-heighten-fears-about-continued-inspector-general-independence/408559/</link><description>Good-government groups and lawmakers from both parties say Trump-administration moves will chill whistleblowing and watchdog offices.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:21:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: War on leaks; IGs, targeted; Guard-deployment sitrep; The next geoint hub?; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-02-2025/408556/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:36:52 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Elon Musk’s SpaceX took money directly from Chinese investors, company insider testifies</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/elon-musks-spacex-took-money-directly-chinese-investors-company-insider-testifies/408557/</link><description>The newly unsealed testimony marks the first time direct Chinese investment in the company has been disclosed, raising new questions about foreign stakes in one of America’s most important military contractors.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:01:58 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>'Shadow economies' are growing. Military planners and operators must take them into account</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/shadow-economies-are-growing-military-planners-and-operators-must-take-them-account/408560/</link><description>Black markets prolong wars, defang sanctions, fray alliances, and help rogue governments and groups survive and thrive.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 13:21:41 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Inside Europe's crash effort to create a 'drone wall'</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2025/10/inside-emergency-effort-create-european-drone-wall/408582/</link><description>More sensors, more maneuverable, less expensive: How the Ukraine war is shaping the future of drone air defense.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:26:08 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Trump declares war on cartels; Feds storm Chicago apartments; Europe’s ‘drone wall’; Shadow economies; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-03-2025/408590/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:19:38 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Shutdown poised to drag into next week as layoff threat looms</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/shutdown-poised-drag-next-week-layoff-threat-looms/408602/</link><description>Senate once again fails to approve spending bill and the two sides remain far divided.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:35:33 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>NGA wants to put its idle PCs to work</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/defense-systems/2025/10/nga-wants-put-its-idle-pcs-work/408603/</link><description>GDIT is networking the agency’s St. Louis workstations to crunch geospatial data even when analysts aren’t around.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:42:55 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Guard deployments on hold; 4th speedboat bombed; Russia strikes Lviv; China’s black-market oil; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-06-2025/408615/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:37:39 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela, US edge toward war footing—but the White House may blink first</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/venezuela-and-us-edge-toward-war-footing-domestic-concerns-international-risks-may-hold-washington-back/408637/</link><description>The Trump administration is increasing the pressure, but domestic concerns, international risks may hold it back.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:30:03 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Hamas has run out of options</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/hamas-has-run-out-options/408639/</link><description>The group's survival now rests on accepting Trump’s plan and political reform.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>More employees set to receive furlough notices as shutdown drags on</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/more-employees-set-receive-furlough-notices-shutdown-drags/408636/</link><description>DOD has not said how long nonexempt civilian employees might be kept working.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:22:40 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Flood of questions leads Missile Defense Agency to push Golden Dome deadline one week</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/10/flood-questions-leads-missile-defense-agency-push-golden-dome-deadline-one-week/408635/</link><description>Pitches for a slice of MDA’s 10-year, up-to-$151 billion contract vehicle are now due Oct. 16.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:38:41 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>OMB quietly deletes reference to law requiring back pay to furloughed feds</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/omb-deletes-reference-law-guaranteeing-backpay-furloughed-feds-shutdown-guidance/408650/</link><description>A White House FAQ now says restitution is only guaranteed to excepted employees forced to work without pay.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:16:46 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Troops to Chicago; Trump’s partisan speech to sailors; F/A-XX OK?; MDA’s big Golden Dome vehicle; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-07-2025/408652/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 11:14:29 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Denied in July, DHS intelligence office resumes efforts to shed staff</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/dhs-intelligence-office-sent-deferred-resignation-offers-shed-staff-recent-months/408661/</link><description>After stakeholders scuttled dramatic cuts, the Office of Intelligence and Analysis is quietly offering buyouts instead.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 15:22:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Skeptical senators grill White House pick to lead Indo-Pacific policy</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/skeptical-senators-grill-white-house-pick-lead-indo-pacific-policy/408674/</link><description>The nominee to be assistant defense secretary for Indo-Pacific security affairs, backed the president's push for Taiwan to spend more.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 19:21:18 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Federal shutdown deals blow to already-hobbled cybersecurity agency</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/federal-shutdown-deals-blow-already-hobbled-cybersecurity-agency/408675/</link><description>Two-thirds of the staff at the nation’s cybersecurity agency are sidelined, opening opportunities for malicious hackers.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 21:46:45 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia regularly targeting UK satellites: space command boss</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Russia_regularly_targeting_UK_satellites_space_command_boss_999.html</link><description>London (AFP) Oct 3, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/milspace-comms-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Russia is attempting to jam British military satellites on a regular basis, the head of UK Space Command has said, amid growing tensions between Moscow and some European countries. 

"We're seeing our satellites being jammed by the Russians on a reasonably persistent basis," Major General Paul Tedman told the BBC. 

"They've got payloads on board that can see our satellites and are trying to</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:49:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Firefly Aerospace to Acquire SciTec in $855M Deal Expanding National Security Portfolio</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Firefly_Aerospace_to_Acquire_SciTec_in_855_Million_Deal_Expanding_National_Security_Portfolio_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Oct 07, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/scitec-logo-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Firefly Aerospace (Nasdaq: FLY) has announced a definitive agreement to acquire SciTec, Inc., a recognized leader in advanced national security technologies, in a transaction valued at approximately $855 million. The deal combines $300 million in cash and $555 million in Firefly shares, issued to SciTec's owners at $50 per share. 

"The acquisition of SciTec enhances our ability to support a</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:49:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lockheed Martin Sikorsky unveils scalable Nomad drone family for autonomous long-range missions</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Lockheed_Martin_Sikorsky_unveils_scalable_Nomad_drone_family_for_autonomous_long_range_missions_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Oct 07, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/sikorsky-nomad-rendering-2025-uav-drone-family-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
Less than a year after validating its rotor blown wing vertical take-off and landing (VTOL) uncrewed aircraft in flight tests, Sikorsky, a Lockheed Martin company (NYSE: LMT), has introduced the Nomad family of long-endurance, runway-independent drones. 

The twin proprotor system merges helicopter-style agility with fixed-wing speed and range. Each Nomad platform can lift off vertically, ho</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:49:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Revolutionising the Skies: How Helsing's CA-1 Europa Drone Could Transform Autonomous Warfare</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Revolutionising_the_Skies_How_Helsings_CA_1_Europa_Drone_Could_Transform_Autonomous_Warfare_999.html</link><description>Budapest, Hungary (SPX) Oct 06, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/uav-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Amid rising geopolitical tensions, Europe is accelerating its push into autonomous military technology. German AI defence firm Helsing recently unveiled its fully autonomous combat drone, the CA-1 Europa, with operational deployment targeted for 2029. More than a drone, the CA-1 Europa could signal a strategic shift in how European forces plan, respond, and assert independence in aerial combat.</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:49:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Burkina junta arrests European NGO workers for 'spying'; frees two activists press-ganged to fight jihadists</title><link>https://www.africadaily.net/reports/Burkina_junta_arrests_European_NGO_workers_for_spying_999.html</link><description>Abidjan (AFP) Oct 7, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/burkina-faso-africa-map-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
 Burkina Faso's military government said Tuesday it had arrested eight members of a humanitarian group, including three Europeans, accusing them of "spying and treason". 

Security Minister Mahamadou Sana said the eight were members of INSO, a Netherlands-based group specialising in humanitarian safety, and included a Frenchman, a French-Senegalese woman, a Czech man, a Malian and four Burkinab</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:49:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CENTCOM kills Al-Qaida-affiliated terrorist leader in Syria</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/CENTCOM_kills_Al-Qaida-affiliated_terrorist_leader_in_Syria_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Oct 8, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/syria-map-1-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 The U.S. military has killed a senior member of an Al-Qaida-affiliated terrroist group in Syria, U.S. Central Command said Tuesday. 
 Muhammad Abd-al-Wahhab al-Ahmad was killed Thursday in a U.S. CENTCOM airstrike, the exact location in Syria was not made public. 
 "U.S. forces in the Middle East remain postured to disrupt and defeat efforts by terrorists to plan, organize and conduc</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:49:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gaza war second anniversary could reopen path to Palestinian statehood</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Gaza_war_second_anniversary_could_reopen_path_to_Palestinian_statehood_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Oct 7, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/gaza-strip-map-closeup-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Hamas's daring "Operation Al Aqsa Flood" two years ago and Israel's devastating war on the Gaza Strip have not only transformed the Middle East, but also reverberated across the world. 
 They have again drawn attention to the 75-year unresolved Palestinian issue, gradually shifting global opinion against Israel as accusations of genocide mounted, and reopening the path toward a Palestinia</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:49:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Top UK prosecutor blames government for dropped China spy case</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Top_UK_prosecutor_blames_government_for_dropped_China_spy_case_999.html</link><description>London (AFP) Oct 8, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/cyberwar-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 A high-profile case involving two men accused of spying for China was dropped because the UK government failed to provide evidence Beijing was a security threat, the chief prosecutor has said. 

Prosecutors have come under fire from lawmakers and government officials after charges against two men, including a former parliamentary researcher, were dismissed last month. 

But Director of Publi</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:49:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran dismissees Israel's missile concern as 'made-up threat'</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Iran_dismissees_Israels_missile_concern_as_made-up_threat_999.html</link><description>Tehran (AFP) Oct 7, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/missiles-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Iran on Tuesday dismissed Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's warnings over its missile programme as fabricated, after he alleged the Islamic republic was developing rockets capable of reaching US cities. 

In an interview with US podcaster Ben Shapiro released on Monday, Netanyahu said: "Iran is developing now... intercontinental ballistic missiles for 8,000 kilometre range". 

"Wha</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:49:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran summons EU envoys over bloc's 'interventionist' stance</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Iran_summons_EU_envoys_over_blocs_interventionist_stance_999.html</link><description>Tehran (AFP) Oct 8, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/iran-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Iran summoned envoys from European Union member states to protest the bloc's "interventionist" statements on contested islands in the Strait of Hormuz as well as the Islamic republic's nuclear programme, local media reported Wednesday. 

Iran considers the islands of Greater Tunb, Lesser Tunb and Abu Musa, all near the strategic Strait of Hormuz in the Gulf, as part of its sovereign territory.</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:49:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Grenade attack in western Iran kills two IRGC members: local media</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Grenade_attack_in_western_Iran_kills_two_IRGC_members_local_media_999.html</link><description>Tehran (AFP) Oct 7, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/iran-revolutionary-guards-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 A grenade attack in western Iran, blamed on militants, killed two members of the country's Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC), including a cleric, local media reported Tuesday. 

The assault, late on Monday, targeted a building belonging to pro-government paramilitary forces near the city of Sarvabad in the western province of Kurdistan and left three other members of the guard corps wou</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:49:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>US report says European giant, others sell to Chinese military-linked companies</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/US_report_says_European_giant_others_sell_to_Chinese_military-linked_companies_999.html</link><description>Washington (AFP) Oct 7, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/milplex-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 A US Congressional committee report released Tuesday said that five major semiconductor equipment manufacturers, including European giant ASML, sold $38 billion worth of critical technology to China in 2024, including to companies flagged as US national security threats. 

The House Select Committee on the Strategic Competition between the United States and the Chinese Communist Party found th</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:49:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump unlikely to win Nobel Peace Prize, but who will?</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Trump_unlikely_to_win_Nobel_Peace_Prize_but_who_will_999.html</link><description>Oslo (AFP) Oct 8, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/nobel-peace-prize-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
 When it comes to this year's Nobel Peace Prize, one thing is almost certain: US President Donald Trump will not win, no matter how much he wants it. But who will? 

The Norwegian Nobel Committee in Oslo will bring the suspense to an end when it announces the winner Friday at 11:00 am (0900 GMT). 

The backdrop is bleak: the number of armed conflicts worldwide involving at least one state has</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:49:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia says missile strike kills three in Belgorod region: governor</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Russia_says_missile_strike_kills_three_in_Belgorod_region_governor_999.html</link><description>Moscow (AFP) Oct 8, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/ukraine-russia-belgorod-missile-attack-fuel-depot-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 A missile strike killed three people in a village in Russia's Belgorod region bordering Ukraine on Wednesday, the local governor said. 

"The village of Maslova Pristan in the Shebekinsky District was hit by a missile strike. According to preliminary data, three people were killed and one was wounded," governor Vyacheslav Gladkov said on Telegram, adding that some people could still be trapped</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:49:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU 'must respond' to Russia's 'hybrid warfare': von der Leyen</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/EU_must_respond_to_Russias_hybrid_warfare_von_der_Leyen_999.html</link><description>Strasbourg, France Oct 8, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/ukraine-snow-bohdanivka-russian-flag-hoisted-near-bakhmut-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 EU chief Ursula von der Leyen on Wednesday said Europe must ramp up its defences to deter Russia's "hybrid warfare", after a catalogue of air incursions, cyber attacks and damage to undersea cables. 

"These incidents are calculated to linger in the twilight of deniability. This is not random harassment. It is a coherent and escalating campaign," the European Commission head said in a speech t</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:49:18 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>