<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Merged Defense / NATO / SpaceWar Feed</title><link>https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml</link><description>Aggregated RSS feed from NATO, DefenseOne, and SpaceWar</description><atom:link href="https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 03:34:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Defense One Radio, Ep. 195: Europe's growing defense industry</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/defense-one-radio-ep-195-europes-growing-defense-industry/408388/</link><description>The EU's ambassador to the U.S. underscores the importance of the bloc's $910 billion defense plans known as Readiness 2030.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 10:34:18 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: DOD sheds 60K civilians; EU warns Moscow; USAF’s new ‘homeland’ focus; China’s airborne gets help; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-26-2025/408407/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 11:21:29 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>SOCOM to get robotic anti-drone turret for maritime platforms</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/socom-get-robotic-anti-drone-tech-maritime-platforms/408418/</link><description>Defense tech startup Allen Control Systems landed a contract for Bullfrog, which can use a variety of common weapons.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 16:10:54 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Two mass shootings; Troops to Portland?; Trump to join Hegseth-brass confab; Arrested by ICE for “how they look”; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-29-2025/408439/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 11:21:45 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Military AI needs guardrails—not to slow it down, but to keep it useful</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/military-ai-needs-guardrailsnot-slow-it-down-keep-it-useful/408452/</link><description>Modifying commercial models isn’t as easy as removing the parts that discourage users from killing people.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 16:50:36 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Shutdown could erode cyber defenses by sidelining critical staff, experts warn</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/shutdown-could-erode-cyber-defenses-sidelining-critical-staff-experts-warn/408466/</link><description>And it would happen just as a bedrock law on sharing cyber threat data expires.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 18:48:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Don’t let the ‘unequal dialogue’ become a partisan one</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/dont-let-unequal-dialogue-become-partisan-one/408467/</link><description>Secretary Hegseth's short-notice summoning of flag officers evinces a dangerous lack of respect.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 20:21:13 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Hegseth, Trump at Quantico; Shutdown watch; Defense-strategy concerns; Troops-in-streets update; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-30-2025/408474/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 11:55:36 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Shutdown would curtail long-term intelligence work at DOD</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/dod-would-curtail-long-term-intelligence-work-during-government-shutdown/408501/</link><description>Routine spying activities conducted by NSA, the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, and others would continue, but some forward-looking intelligence planning would be halted, a department document shows.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 12:45:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>SecDef uses unprecedented meeting to unveil 10 personnel, due-process reviews</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/secdef-uses-unprecedented-meeting-unveil-10-personnel-due-process-reviews/408483/</link><description>After summoning senior officers from around the world, Hegseth invites them to resign if they don’t agree with him.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 13:13:54 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>NATO members say they’re confident, mostly coordinated on how to deal with Russian drone threats</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/nato-members-say-theyre-confident-mostly-coordinated-how-deal-russian-drone-threats/408509/</link><description>Alliance nations are working to do more together to counter increasing Russian air threats—and downplaying the possibility of a U.S. force reduction in Europe.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 18:34:10 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>As government spirals toward a shutdown, Trump promises mass layoffs</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/government-spirals-toward-shutdown-trump-promising-mass-layoffs/408511/</link><description>A last-ditch effort to keep government funded failed Tuesday night. Agencies will begin furloughing staff on Wednesday.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 19:40:23 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Reactions to Quantico; Shutdown, in effect; USAF chief nom; GOP govs call out troops; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-01-2025/408529/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump administration knocks out at least 15 oversight websites, saying IGs 'lied to the public'</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/government-watchdog-websites-go-dark-omb-withholds-funds-ig-committee/408544/</link><description>It's not a shutdown issue: the White House is withholding funds from the umbrella organization for the government's inspectors general.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 13:54:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Poland seeks better counter-drone tech after Russian incursion</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/poland-seeks-better-counter-drone-tech-after-russian-incursion/408522/</link><description>Warsaw’s foreign minister also hopes the U.S. will send more troops to train with its military.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:38:10 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Silicon Valley in St. Louis?</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/10/silicon-valley-st-louis/408542/</link><description>With the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency as its north star, a non-profit is working to get defense tech to put down roots in the Midwest.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 16:49:33 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Hegseth, Vought actions heighten fears about inspector-general independence</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/hegseth-vought-actions-heighten-fears-about-continued-inspector-general-independence/408559/</link><description>Good-government groups and lawmakers from both parties say Trump-administration moves will chill whistleblowing and watchdog offices.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:21:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: War on leaks; IGs, targeted; Guard-deployment sitrep; The next geoint hub?; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-02-2025/408556/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 11:36:52 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Elon Musk’s SpaceX took money directly from Chinese investors, company insider testifies</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/elon-musks-spacex-took-money-directly-chinese-investors-company-insider-testifies/408557/</link><description>The newly unsealed testimony marks the first time direct Chinese investment in the company has been disclosed, raising new questions about foreign stakes in one of America’s most important military contractors.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:01:58 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>'Shadow economies' are growing. Military planners and operators must take them into account</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/shadow-economies-are-growing-military-planners-and-operators-must-take-them-account/408560/</link><description>Black markets prolong wars, defang sanctions, fray alliances, and help rogue governments and groups survive and thrive.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 13:21:41 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Inside Europe's crash effort to create a 'drone wall'</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2025/10/inside-emergency-effort-create-european-drone-wall/408582/</link><description>More sensors, more maneuverable, less expensive: How the Ukraine war is shaping the future of drone air defense.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:26:08 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Trump declares war on cartels; Feds storm Chicago apartments; Europe’s ‘drone wall’; Shadow economies; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-03-2025/408590/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 11:19:38 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Shutdown poised to drag into next week as layoff threat looms</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/shutdown-poised-drag-next-week-layoff-threat-looms/408602/</link><description>Senate once again fails to approve spending bill and the two sides remain far divided.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:35:33 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>NGA wants to put its idle PCs to work</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/defense-systems/2025/10/nga-wants-put-its-idle-pcs-work/408603/</link><description>GDIT is networking the agency’s St. Louis workstations to crunch geospatial data even when analysts aren’t around.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:42:55 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump wants Nobel but 'forgotten' peacemakers more likely, experts say</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Trump_wants_Nobel_but_forgotten_peacemakers_more_likely_experts_say_999.html</link><description>Stockholm (AFP) Oct 2, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/war-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 US President Donald Trump has made it clear he wants the Nobel Peace Prize when it is announced next week but experts predict he has little chance against those toiling on forgotten causes outside the limelight. 

The prestigious prize will be announced on Friday, October 10 but before that, Trump's assault on science is likely to stir debate when the laureates for the medicine prize are revea</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 23:53:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India and China to resume direct flights after 5 years</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/India_and_China_to_resume_direct_flights_after_5_years_999.html</link><description>New Delhi (AFP) Oct 3, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/aerospace-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
 India and China will resume direct flights between their two countries this month after a five-year suspension, officials said, with bookings opening on Friday.  

Direct flights between the world's two most populous countries were suspended during the Covid-19 pandemic in 2020 and were not resumed as tensions grew between Beijing and New Delhi over border disputes. 

Relations between the A</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 23:53:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hegseth fires Navy chief of staff</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Hegseth_fires_Navy_chief_of_staff_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Oct 4, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/naval-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Secretary of Defense Pete Hegseth on Friday fired U.S. Navy Chief of Staff Jon Harrison after the Senate earlier in the week confirmed Hung Cao as the Navy's undersecretary. 
 Harrison had no military experience prior to being nominated and confirmed as the Navy's chief of staff and oversaw the War Department's realignment of the U.S. Navy's budgeting and policy wings, in addition to mini</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 23:53:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hong Kong to install surveillance cameras with AI facial recognition</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Hong_Kong_to_install_surveillance_cameras_with_AI_facial_recognition_999.html</link><description>Hong Kong (AFP) Oct 3, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/cyberwar-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Hong Kong plans to install tens of thousands of surveillance cameras that will make use of AI-powered facial recognition, the city's security chief said on Friday, bringing it closer to China where authorities often monitor public spaces with cutting-edge technology. 

The Chinese finance hub has already installed almost 4,000 closed-circuit television (CCTV) cameras under a police crime-fight</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 23:53:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Advancing European satellite security through quantum communications</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Advancing_European_satellite_security_through_quantum_communications_999.html</link><description>Paris, France (SPX) Oct 06, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/cyberwar-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

The European Space Agency (ESA) has signed a  euro 50 million contract with Thales Alenia Space to initiate the preliminary design phase of the Security And cryptoGrAphic (SAGA) mission. This milestone marks a significant step toward establishing secure quantum communications from orbit. 

SAGA's goal is to demonstrate satellite-based quantum key distribution (QKD), which enables encryption</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 23:53:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lithuania builds shelters as drones prowl border skies</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Lithuania_builds_shelters_as_drones_prowl_border_skies_999.html</link><description>Vilnius (AFP) Oct 2, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/uav-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Recent drone sorties over Lithuania and its neighbours have sparked fears of a full-scale Russian attack, prompting the small Baltic country to encourage the building of bomb shelters. 

Not every community has yet heeded the call, but residents showed AFP the basement of an apartment block in Lithuania's capital Vilnius where they were readying a bunker in case of war. 

"People wanted to h</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 23:53:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>French navy responds to drone threat with jamming and a 'wall of steel'</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/French_navy_responds_to_drone_threat_with_jamming_and_a_wall_of_steel_999.html</link><description>Toulon, France (AFP) Oct 3, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/uav-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 The 76-mm cannon fires three shells into the sky, shaking the floor of the bridge. "UAV (unmanned aerial vehicle) destroyed," shouts a sailor on board the French frigate Lorraine, his eyes glued to binoculars. 

Moments earlier, a target representing a surface drone slowly sank into the depths of the Mediterranean Sea, riddled with 12.7-mm machine gun bullets. 

"You nailed it, Tristan!" the</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 23:53:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU eyes building 'drone wall': question is, what is it?</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/EU_eyes_building_drone_wall_question_is_what_is_it_999.html</link><description>Copenhagen (AFP) Oct 2, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/uav-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 European Union leaders are discussing setting up a "drone wall" of defences after high-profile air incursions by Russia. 

But the plan appears to mean different things to different countries, and not everyone seems entirely convinced.  

Here's where we stand: 

- Eastern shield? - 

The first call for the project came last month from EU chief Ursula von der Leyen in the hours after a s</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 23:53:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Revolutionising the Skies: How Helsing's CA-1 Europa Drone Could Transform Autonomous Warfare</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Revolutionising_the_Skies_How_Helsings_CA_1_Europa_Drone_Could_Transform_Autonomous_Warfare_999.html</link><description>Budapest, Hungary (SPX) Oct 06, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/uav-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Amid rising geopolitical tensions, Europe is accelerating its push into autonomous military technology. German AI defence firm Helsing recently unveiled its fully autonomous combat drone, the CA-1 Europa, with operational deployment targeted for 2029. More than a drone, the CA-1 Europa could signal a strategic shift in how European forces plan, respond, and assert independence in aerial combat.</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 23:53:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Swiss seek mini-drone defence system</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Swiss_seek_mini-drone_defence_system_999.html</link><description>Geneva (AFP) Oct 3, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/uav-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Switzerland's military said Friday it plans to acquire a defence system against "mini-drones", after several European countries recently reported incursions into their airspace, pointing the finger at Russia. 

Following multiple incursions, European leaders are seeking to build an anti-drone "wall" for protection. 

Switzerland is not part of the European Union or the NATO defence alliance,</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 23:53:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran says cooperation with UN nuclear watchdog 'no longer relevant'</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Iran_says_cooperation_with_UN_nuclear_watchdog_no_longer_relevant_999.html</link><description>Tehran (AFP) Oct 5, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/iran-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Iran's top diplomat said Sunday that cooperation with the United Nations nuclear watchdog was no longer relevant following the reimposition of international sanctions on the Islamic republic. 

"The Cairo agreement is no longer relevant for our cooperation with the IAEA (International Atomic Energy Agency)," Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi said, referring to a September deal with the UN agency</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 23:53:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shield or Spark? The U.S. Golden Dome and the New Missile Arms Race</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Shield_or_Spark_The_U_S__Golden_Dome_and_the_New_Missile_Arms_Race_999.html</link><description>Budapest, Hungary (SPX) Oct 06, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/abm-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

The launch of the US 'Golden Dome' missile defence initiative has already set in motion ripple effects across the globe. Rival nations are considering their own layered missile defence architectures, and experts warn this may trigger a new era of competitive missile development. What began as a domestic shield is now fuelling a missile defence arms race, with competitors racing to counter, repli</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 23:53:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Defense contractors brace for climate threats despite Trump's denials</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Defense_contractors_brace_for_climate_threats_despite_Trumps_denials_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Oct 2, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/milplex-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 President Donald Trump repeatedly calls climate change a "hoax," but the nation's five largest defense contractors say they are challenged to balance the Earth's warming with operational demands, technological adaptations and emission liabilities, according to a review of their filings with the Securities and Exchange Commission. 
 Lockheed Martin, RTX, Northrop Grumman, General Dynamics</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 23:53:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>French navy boards Russia 'shadow fleet' ship, arrests two</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/French_navy_boards_Russia_shadow_fleet_ship_arrests_two_999.html</link><description>Brest, France (AFP) Oct 1, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/milplex-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
 France has detained two senior crew members of a tanker linked to Russia, which data showed was off the Danish coast last month during mysterious drone flights, prosecutors said on Wednesday.  

The Boracay, a Benin-flagged vessel blacklisted by the European Union for being part of Russia's sanction-busting "shadow fleet" of ageing oil tankers, was stationed off Denmark from September 22 to 25</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 23:53:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia regularly targeting UK satellites: space command boss</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Russia_regularly_targeting_UK_satellites_space_command_boss_999.html</link><description>London (AFP) Oct 3, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/milspace-comms-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Russia is attempting to jam British military satellites on a regular basis, the head of UK Space Command has said, amid growing tensions between Moscow and some European countries. 

"We're seeing our satellites being jammed by the Russians on a reasonably persistent basis," Major General Paul Tedman told the BBC. 

"They've got payloads on board that can see our satellites and are trying to</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 23:53:02 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>