<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Merged Defense / NATO / SpaceWar Feed</title><link>https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml</link><description>Aggregated RSS feed from NATO, DefenseOne, and SpaceWar</description><atom:link href="https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 02:49:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Shutdown poised to drag into next week as layoff threat looms</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/shutdown-poised-drag-next-week-layoff-threat-looms/408602/</link><description>Senate once again fails to approve spending bill and the two sides remain far divided.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:35:33 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>NGA wants to put its idle PCs to work</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/defense-systems/2025/10/nga-wants-put-its-idle-pcs-work/408603/</link><description>GDIT is networking the agency’s St. Louis workstations to crunch geospatial data even when analysts aren’t around.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:42:55 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Guard deployments on hold; 4th speedboat bombed; Russia strikes Lviv; China’s black-market oil; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-06-2025/408615/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:37:39 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela, US edge toward war footing—but the White House may blink first</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/venezuela-and-us-edge-toward-war-footing-domestic-concerns-international-risks-may-hold-washington-back/408637/</link><description>The Trump administration is increasing the pressure, but domestic concerns, international risks may hold it back.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:30:03 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Hamas has run out of options</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/hamas-has-run-out-options/408639/</link><description>The group's survival now rests on accepting Trump’s plan and political reform.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>More employees set to receive furlough notices as shutdown drags on</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/more-employees-set-receive-furlough-notices-shutdown-drags/408636/</link><description>DOD has not said how long nonexempt civilian employees might be kept working.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:22:40 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Flood of questions leads Missile Defense Agency to push Golden Dome deadline one week</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/10/flood-questions-leads-missile-defense-agency-push-golden-dome-deadline-one-week/408635/</link><description>Pitches for a slice of MDA’s 10-year, up-to-$151 billion contract vehicle are now due Oct. 16.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:38:41 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>OMB quietly deletes reference to law requiring back pay to furloughed feds</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/omb-deletes-reference-law-guaranteeing-backpay-furloughed-feds-shutdown-guidance/408650/</link><description>A White House FAQ now says restitution is only guaranteed to excepted employees forced to work without pay.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:16:46 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Troops to Chicago; Trump’s partisan speech to sailors; F/A-XX OK?; MDA’s big Golden Dome vehicle; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-07-2025/408652/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 11:14:29 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Denied in July, DHS intelligence office resumes efforts to shed staff</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/dhs-intelligence-office-sent-deferred-resignation-offers-shed-staff-recent-months/408661/</link><description>After stakeholders scuttled dramatic cuts, the Office of Intelligence and Analysis is quietly offering buyouts instead.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 15:22:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Skeptical senators grill White House pick to lead Indo-Pacific policy</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/skeptical-senators-grill-white-house-pick-lead-indo-pacific-policy/408674/</link><description>The nominee to be assistant defense secretary for Indo-Pacific security affairs, backed the president's push for Taiwan to spend more.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 19:21:18 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Federal shutdown deals blow to already-hobbled cybersecurity agency</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/federal-shutdown-deals-blow-already-hobbled-cybersecurity-agency/408675/</link><description>Two-thirds of the staff at the nation’s cybersecurity agency are sidelined, opening opportunities for malicious hackers.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 21:46:45 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Senators doubt Asia policy; Jail Illinois leaders, says POTUS; Civil-military ‘crisis’; DHS cuts intel staff; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-08-2025/408684/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 11:26:01 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>It’s time to return Turkey to the F-35 fold, even if we have to get creative</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/10/its-time-return-turkey-f-35-fold-even-if-we-have-get-creative/408695/</link><description>It's a sticking point that is blocking deeper US-NATO-Turkish defense cooperation.</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 16:07:04 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Legal experts fear Trump admin is ignoring JAGs on cartel strikes, Guard deployments</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/military-legal-experts-fear-trump-admin-ignoring-jags-cartel-strikes-guard-deployments/408699/</link><description>A former military lawyer and a former judge encouraged commanders to stand up to unlawful orders.</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 17:25:15 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Lawmakers call for more defense biotech research as China pursues breakthroughs</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/technology/2025/10/lawmakers-call-more-defense-biotech-research-china-pursues-breakthroughs/408700/</link><description>Shelf-stable blood, biological camouflage, and biosensors are just some of the potential innovations.</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 17:36:20 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Stop trying to control every step’ of shipbuilding, senator tells Navy</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/stop-trying-control-every-step-shipbuilding-senator-tells-navy/408703/</link><description>Focus less on requirements and more on outcomes, says Montana’s Sheehy, and the entire Pentagon might get on board.</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 22:57:04 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>DHS tells hundreds of staffers: accept reassignment to border security, immigration—or face termination</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/hundreds-dhs-staff-face-reassignments-border-security-immigration/408709/</link><description>The affected workers including some at CISA, FEMA, and the Coast Guard. Some have been given a week to respond.</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 11:16:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Ceasefire near in Gaza?; Troops arrive in Chicago; Shipbuilding advice; Deportation stats; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-09-2025/408708/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 11:46:58 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Get more F-35s in the air and don't break the bank, senators beg USAF chief nominee</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/senators-beg-air-force-chief-staff-nominee-fix-f-35s-mission-capable-rates-costs/408727/</link><description>Gen. Wilsbach declined to endorse the service’s ongoing reorganization to counter China.</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 16:18:56 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Current, former state leaders weigh in on Trump’s deployment of National Guard troops</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/current-former-state-leaders-weigh-trumps-deployment-national-guard-troops/408737/</link><description>In legal briefs, 17 current Republican attorneys general support the president, while a bipartisan group of former governors objects.</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 23:12:53 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Amid shutdown, the Army will do its best to talk transformation, counter-drones, and acquisition reform</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/amid-shutdown-army-will-do-its-best-talk-transformation-counter-drones-and-acquisition-reform/408720/</link><description>AUSA's annual meeting is slated to feature a rare public discussion of Pentagon’s new homeland focus.</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 23:17:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Two newly launched NASA missions will help scientists understand the influence of the Sun</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/2_newly_launched_NASA_missions_will_help_scientists_understand_the_influence_of_the_Sun-_999.html</link><description>Boulder CO (SPX) Sep 25, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/solarscience-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
Even at a distance of 93 million miles (150 million kilometers) away, activity on the Sun can have adverse effects on technological systems on Earth. Solar flares - intense bursts of energy in the Sun's atmosphere - and coronal mass ejections - eruptions of plasma from the Sun - can affect the communications, satellite navigation and power grid systems that keep society functioning. 

On Sep</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>We need a solar sail probe to detect space tornadoes earlier, more accurately</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/We_need_a_solar_sail_probe_to_detect_space_tornadoes_earlier_more_accurately_999.html</link><description>Ann Arbor, MI (SPX) Oct 07, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/solarsails-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Spirals of solar wind can spin off larger solar eruptions and disrupt Earth's magnetic field, yet they are too difficult to detect with our current single-location warning system, according to a new study from the University of Michigan. 

But a constellation of spacecraft, including one that sails on sunlight, could help find the tornado-like features in time to protect equipment on Earth a</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Space Force awards launch missions to SpaceX, ULA</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/Space_Force_awards_launch_missions_to_SpaceX_ULA_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (SPX) Oct 07, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/spacex-falcon-9-rocket-launch-complex-40-cape-canaveral-air-force-station-18th-commercial-resupply-mission-iss-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

The U.S. Space Force announced winning bids for missions, and SpaceX is the clear favorite. 

Space Systems Command awarded seven National Security Space Launch contracts last week. Five of the missions were awarded to SpaceX for $714 million. United Launch Alliance got the other two, worth $428 million. Blue Origin didn't qualify because its New Glenn rocket still needs certification for na</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Raytheon and Anduril achieve breakthrough test in advanced rocket propulsion</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/Raytheon_and_Anduril_achieve_breakthrough_test_in_advanced_rocket_propulsion_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Oct 09, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/raytheon-logo-wall-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Raytheon, an RTX business, and Anduril Industries have completed a successful static fire test of an advanced solid rocket motor under contract with the U.S. Air Force Research Laboratory's Munitions Directorate. The achievement marks a major step toward expanding U.S. rocket motor production and strengthening the defense industrial base. 

With global demand for munitions rising, the test u</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DLR's ATHEAt Flight Experiment Achieves Hypersonic Milestone Over Norway</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/DLRs_ATHEAt_Flight_Experiment_Achieves_Hypersonic_Milestone_Over_Norway_999.html</link><description>Berlin, Germany (SPX) Oct 09, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/nordic-countries-sweden-finland-norway-denmark-iceland-faroe-islands-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

The German Aerospace Center (DLR) has successfully launched its ATHEAt flight experiment from Andoya, Norway, marking a major advance in reusable space transportation technology. The sounding rocket lifted off on 6 October 2025 at 10:45 local time, flying for approximately four minutes and surpassing Mach 9 for two of those minutes - conditions comparable to atmospheric re-entry. 

During th</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dutch NGO rejects Burkina junta's claims of spying</title><link>https://www.africadaily.net/reports/Dutch_NGO_rejects_Burkina_juntas_claims_of_spying_999.html</link><description>Abidjan (AFP) Oct 8, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/africa-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 An NGO on Wednesday denied claims by the Burkina Faso authorities that its workers had been involved in spying a day after the military regime arrested more of its staff. 

The International and Safety Organisation (INSO) was responding a day after the country's Security Minister Mahamadou Sana accused its staff of "spying and treason". 

"We categorically reject the allegations made regardi</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>U.S. to buy 4 Finnish icebreakers and build 7 more for $6.1B</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/US_to_buy_4_Finnish_icebreakers_and_build_7_more_for_61B_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Oct 9, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/arctic-sea-ice-research-vessel-icebreaker-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Finnish President Alexander Stubb visited the White House on Thursday to sign a deal to sell four icebreakers to the United States and build seven more at U.S. shipyards. 
 President Donald Trump and Stubb announced the deal at the White House ahead of them signing the deal for the vessels that are designed to create paths through icefloes to support commercial and military vessels, The H</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NATO to start annual nuclear exercise Monday</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/NATO_to_start_annual_nuclear_exercise_Monday_999.html</link><description>Brussels, Belgium (AFP) Oct 10, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/nuclear-doctrine-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 NATO will launch its annual nuclear exercise Steadfast Noon next week, alliance chief Mark Rutte said Friday, as tensions with Russia have risen after a series of air incursions by Moscow. 

In a video posted online Rutte stressed that the two-week drill starting on Monday was "regular" and NATO said it is not linked directly to the Kremlin's latest actions.  

"We need to do this because it</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Muon Space to Demonstrate Dual-Use Environmental Monitoring Constellation under $44.6M Space Force Agreement</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Muon_Space_to_Demonstrate_Dual_Use_Environmental_Monitoring_Constellation_under_44_6M_Space_Force_Agreement_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Oct 09, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/muon-space-logo-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Muon Space has secured a $44.6 million Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) Phase III Other Transaction Authority (OTA) agreement from the U.S. Space Force's Space Systems Command System Delta 810 (SYD 810) to develop and demonstrate a dual-use space-based environmental monitoring (SBEM) constellation. The mission will deliver on-orbit prototype capability designed to support both Departmen</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eutelsat and Tusass Strengthen Greenland's Digital Backbone with LEO Connectivity Expansion</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/Eutelsat_and_Tusass_Strengthen_Greenlands_Digital_Backbone_with_LEO_Connectivity_Expansion_999.html</link><description>Paris, France (SPX) Oct 06, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/eutelsat-oneweb-logo-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Eutelsat and Tusass, Greenland's national telecommunications provider, have expanded their strategic partnership through a new multi-year agreement to deliver low Earth orbit (LEO) satellite connectivity across Greenland. The collaboration will use Eutelsat's OneWeb network to enhance secure, resilient, and high-speed communications across the Arctic nation's remote regions. 

The extended p</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says 'stepping up pressure' to end Ukraine war</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Trump_says_stepping_up_pressure_to_end_Ukraine_war_999.html</link><description>Washington (AFP) Oct 9, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/putin-trump-parody-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 US President Donald Trump said Thursday that Washington and NATO allies were "stepping up the pressure" to end the war in Ukraine, after his outreach to Russia's Vladimir Putin failed to achieve a ceasefire. 

"Yeah, we are stepping up the pressure," Trump said in the Oval Office during a meeting with Finnish President Alexander Stubb when asked by an AFP reporter if he would increase efforts</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Team of 200 US troops to 'oversee' Gaza truce: US officials</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Team_of_200_US_troops_to_oversee_Gaza_truce_US_officials_999.html</link><description>Washington (AFP) Oct 9, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/israel-soldiers-gaza-city-hamas-bunker-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 A US military team of 200 people will be deployed in the Middle East to "oversee" the Gaza ceasefire between Israel and Hamas after a peace deal brokered by President Donald Trump, senior US officials said Thursday. 

Admiral Brad Cooper, the head of the US military's Central Command, "will initially have 200 people on the ground. His role will be to oversee, observe, make sure there are no vi</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>IDF prepares for Gaza withdrawal following Israel-Hamas agreement</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/IDF_prepares_for_Gaza_withdrawal_following_Israel-Hamas_agreement_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Oct 9, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/israel-sodiers-tanks-gaza-desert-marker-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 The Israeli military said Thursday that it has begun preparing to withdraw troops from Gaza after Hamas and Israel reached an agreement to end the two-year-old war. 
 "Following the political echelon's instructions and due to situational assessment, the IDF has begun operational preparations ahead of the implementation of the agreement," the Israel Defense Forces said in a statement.</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taiwan leader vows stronger air defences to counter 'enemy threats'</title><link>https://www.sinodaily.com/reports/Taiwan_leader_vows_stronger_air_defences_to_counter_enemy_threats_999.html</link><description>Taipei (AFP) Oct 10, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/china-joint-sword-taiwan-wargames-2023-j-15-fighter-aircraft-flyby-pilot-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Taiwanese President Lai Ching-te vowed on Friday to speed up construction of a multi-layered air defence system as part of efforts to counter "enemy threats". 

Lai's government has been under US pressure to improve its ability to defend itself against a potential attack by China, which claims the island is part of its territory.  

"We will accelerate our building of the T-Dome, establish a</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Maria Corina Machado: the face and fire of Venezuela's opposition</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Maria_Corina_Machado_the_face_and_fire_of_Venezuelas_opposition_999.html</link><description>Caracas (AFP) Oct 10, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/maria-corina-machado-closeup-wikipedia-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Maria Corina Machado, a fearless activist with rock-star appeal, is a key face of the opposition to Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro's iron-fisted regime. 

Hailed as "la libertadora", in an allusion to Venezuelan independence hero Simon "The Liberator" Bolivar, Machado was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize on Friday for her work. 

She was barred from challenging Maduro in 2024 elections, th</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Senate passes NDAA; US troops to monitor Gaza ceasefire; Guard enters Memphis; AUSA preview; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-10-2025/408746/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 11:31:05 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Defense tech has a new unicorn</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/10/defense-tech-has-new-unicorn/408764/</link><description>Data-tech startup Govini cinched $150 million in growth capital, tipping the company’s valuation over the $1 billion mark.</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 17:22:53 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>US to build facility for Qatari F-15s in Idaho; details remain unclear</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/10/us-build-facility-qatari-f-15s-idaho-details-remain-unclear/408767/</link><description>The project, which appears to flow from the terms of the jets' 2017 sale, drew criticism and questions.</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 20:24:52 -0400</pubDate></item></channel></rss>