<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Merged Defense / NATO / SpaceWar Feed</title><link>https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml</link><description>Aggregated RSS feed from NATO, DefenseOne, and SpaceWar</description><atom:link href="https://yourusername.github.io/your-repo/merged-defense.xml" rel="self"/><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 21:12:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Defense One Radio, Ep. 194: Highlights from AFA's Air, Space &amp; Cyber Conference</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/defense-one-radio-ep-194-highlights-afas-air-space-cyber-conference/408344/</link><description>Our editors explore the dominant themes from this year's edition.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 18:59:10 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>DOGE risks Americans’ data by operating outside federal law, Democrats say</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/democrat-report-doge-risking-americans-data-operating-outside-federal-law/408380/</link><description>A report released by the Senate Homeland Committee's ranking member says lax security practices cause “serious cybersecurity vulnerabilities, privacy violations, and risk of corruption.”</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Agencies should prep for mass layoffs if shutdown occurs, White House says</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/agencies-should-prep-mass-layoffs-if-shutdown-occurs-white-house-says/408378/</link><description>OMB is requesting updated reduction-in-force plans even if a shutdown is averted.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:36:22 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Hegseth yanks brass to Quantico; Drones close Danish airports; AFSOC’s Caribbean work; Russia’s AI drones; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-25-2025/408367/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 11:18:07 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>More than 60K defense civilians have left under Hegseth—but officials are mum on the effects</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/more-60k-defense-civilians-have-left-under-hegseth-officials-are-mum-effects/408375/</link><description>Months into a hastily ordered overhaul, officials declined to disclose metrics, discuss problems.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 12:24:30 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>China, China, Chi—wait, what? Air Force mulls next steps amid homeland focus</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/china-china-chiwait-what-air-force-mulls-next-steps-amid-homeland-focus/408392/</link><description>Officials tout applicability of ongoing modernization, but experts and former officials have doubts.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 16:52:06 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Air Force’s AI ambitions mean simplifying its tangle of networks</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/defense-systems/2025/09/air-forces-ai-ambitions-mean-simplifying-its-tangle-networks/408397/</link><description>Over the next year, battle-networks chief aims to reduce systems to a “rational number.”</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 18:56:21 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>How Trump can make defense reform stick</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/how-trump-can-make-defense-reform-stick/408383/</link><description>It will require sustained presidential attention and unprecendented transparency.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Defense One Radio, Ep. 195: Europe's growing defense industry</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/defense-one-radio-ep-195-europes-growing-defense-industry/408388/</link><description>The EU's ambassador to the U.S. underscores the importance of the bloc's $910 billion defense plans known as Readiness 2030.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 10:34:18 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: DOD sheds 60K civilians; EU warns Moscow; USAF’s new ‘homeland’ focus; China’s airborne gets help; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-26-2025/408407/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 11:21:29 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>SOCOM to get robotic anti-drone turret for maritime platforms</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/09/socom-get-robotic-anti-drone-tech-maritime-platforms/408418/</link><description>Defense tech startup Allen Control Systems landed a contract for Bullfrog, which can use a variety of common weapons.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 16:10:54 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Two mass shootings; Troops to Portland?; Trump to join Hegseth-brass confab; Arrested by ICE for “how they look”; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-29-2025/408439/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 11:21:45 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Military AI needs guardrails—not to slow it down, but to keep it useful</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/military-ai-needs-guardrailsnot-slow-it-down-keep-it-useful/408452/</link><description>Modifying commercial models isn’t as easy as removing the parts that discourage users from killing people.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 16:50:36 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Shutdown could erode cyber defenses by sidelining critical staff, experts warn</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/shutdown-could-erode-cyber-defenses-sidelining-critical-staff-experts-warn/408466/</link><description>And it would happen just as a bedrock law on sharing cyber threat data expires.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 18:48:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Don’t let the ‘unequal dialogue’ become a partisan one</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/ideas/2025/09/dont-let-unequal-dialogue-become-partisan-one/408467/</link><description>Secretary Hegseth's short-notice summoning of flag officers evinces a dangerous lack of respect.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 20:21:13 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Hegseth, Trump at Quantico; Shutdown watch; Defense-strategy concerns; Troops-in-streets update; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/the-d-brief-september-30-2025/408474/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 11:55:36 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Shutdown would curtail long-term intelligence work at DOD</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/dod-would-curtail-long-term-intelligence-work-during-government-shutdown/408501/</link><description>Routine spying activities conducted by NSA, the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, and others would continue, but some forward-looking intelligence planning would be halted, a department document shows.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 12:45:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>SecDef uses unprecedented meeting to unveil 10 personnel, due-process reviews</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/policy/2025/09/secdef-uses-unprecedented-meeting-unveil-10-personnel-due-process-reviews/408483/</link><description>After summoning senior officers from around the world, Hegseth invites them to resign if they don’t agree with him.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 13:13:54 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>NATO members say they’re confident, mostly coordinated on how to deal with Russian drone threats</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/nato-members-say-theyre-confident-mostly-coordinated-how-deal-russian-drone-threats/408509/</link><description>Alliance nations are working to do more together to counter increasing Russian air threats—and downplaying the possibility of a U.S. force reduction in Europe.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 18:34:10 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>As government spirals toward a shutdown, Trump promises mass layoffs</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/09/government-spirals-toward-shutdown-trump-promising-mass-layoffs/408511/</link><description>A last-ditch effort to keep government funded failed Tuesday night. Agencies will begin furloughing staff on Wednesday.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 19:40:23 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump's ego and 'Finnish solution' for Ukraine: ex-NATO chief's memoir</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Trumps_ego_and_Finnish_solution_for_Ukraine_ex-NATO_chiefs_memoir_999.html</link><description>Oslo (AFP) Sept 29, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/putin-trump-alaska-parody-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 From stroking US President Donald Trump's ego to a "Finnish solution" for peace in Ukraine, former NATO chief Jens Stoltenberg opens up about his decade as head of the alliance in a new memoir. 

In "On My Watch" launched Monday in Norway, Stoltenberg revealed behind-the-scenes details of a 2018 NATO summit when Trump, during his first term, threatened to walk out due to a number of European c</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 07:18:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump's Pentagon chief outlines vision for the US military</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Trumps_Pentagon_chief_outlines_vision_for_the_US_military_999.html</link><description>Washington (AFP) Oct 1, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/pete-hegseth-face-palm-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth portrayed the US military Tuesday as too fat, too focused on leftist "woke" ideas, and in need of major shake-up with an emphasis on being tough "war fighters." 

The speech, to an auditorium of hundreds of generals and admirals hastily called to Virginia from around the world, touted a plan for ending what the former Fox News host claimed had been "decades of de</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 07:18:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>State Department sanctions North Koreans for role in arms sales</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/State_Department_sanctions_North_Koreans_for_role_in_arms_sales_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Sep 25, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/korea-kim-big-hat-ground-binoculars-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 The United States on Thursday sanctioned one person and five entities for their role in generating money for North Korea and its weapons programs. 
 "This action aims to disrupt illicit networks that facilitate these attacks and simultaneously cutting off funding for the DPRK unlawful weapons of mass destruction (WMD) and ballistic missile programs," the State Department said in a stateme</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 07:18:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seoul official hints at US-North Korea meeting this year</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Seoul_official_hints_at_US-North_Korea_meeting_this_year_999.html</link><description>Seoul (AFP) Sept 27, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/korea-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 A meeting between North Korea and the United States on the sidelines of this year's APEC summit in South Korea "cannot be ruled out", according to a Seoul foreign ministry official. 

Ties between Pyongyang and Washington have been in the deep freeze since a high-profile summit between North Korean leader Kim Jong Un and President Donald Trump in 2019 collapsed over sanctions relief and Pyongy</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 07:18:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>York and SDA prove space to ground laser link for Transport Layer</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/York_and_SDA_prove_space_to_ground_laser_link_for_Transport_Layer_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Sep 25, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/laser-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

York Space Systems announced a successful space-to-ground optical laser communications demonstration with the U.S. Space Development Agency, advancing the Transport Layer that aims to deliver resilient, low-latency, high-volume connectivity for U.S. and allied forces worldwide. 

In the test, a York-built Tranche 0 satellite linked with an SDA optical ground terminal. The campaign logged mor</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 07:18:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Welsh project aims to reinvent space cooling with laser textured graphite</title><link>https://www.spacedaily.com/reports/Welsh_project_aims_to_reinvent_space_cooling_with_laser_textured_graphite_999.html</link><description>Los Angeles CA (SPX) Fri Sep 26, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/graphite-film-coat-perovskite-solar-cells-waterproof-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Teledyne Labtech and Bangor University have launched the Advanced Thermal Management for Space Electronics (ATMS) program to address heat removal in spacecraft, with support from Airbus Endeavr, a joint initiative between Airbus and the Welsh Government. The effort targets lighter, higher performance thermal solutions for space hardware. 

ATMS centers on replacing traditional copper heat co</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 07:18:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Iran denounces 'unjustifiable' return of UN sanctions</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Iran_denounces_unjustifiable_return_of_UN_sanctions_999.html</link><description>Tehran (AFP) Sept 28, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/iran-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
 Iran on Sunday condemned as "unjustifiable" the reinstatement of United Nations sanctions over its nuclear programme, after the collapse of talks with Western powers and Israeli and US strikes on its nuclear sites. 

The measures, which bar dealings linked to the Islamic republic's nuclear and ballistic missile activities, took effect overnight after Western powers triggered the so-called "sna</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 07:18:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sierra Space clears design milestone for missile tracking satellites in SDA Tranche 2</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Sierra_Space_clears_design_milestone_for_missile_tracking_satellites_in_SDA_Tranche_2_999.html</link><description>Louisville CO (SPX) Sep 30, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/sierra-space-logo-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

Sierra Space has completed the Critical Design Review (CDR) for the Space Development Agency's (SDA) Tranche 2 Tracking Layer, confirming readiness to begin production of missile tracking satellites for the Proliferated Warfighter Space Architecture (PWSA). The program will see Sierra Space deliver two orbital planes, totaling 18 satellites, each carrying advanced infrared sensors designed to de</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 07:18:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>N.Korea vows never to give up nuclear</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/NKorea_vows_at_UN_never_to_give_up_nuclear_999.html</link><description>United Nations, United States (AFP) Sept 29, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/north-korean-leader-kim-jong-un-inspection-nuclear-weapons-institute-uranium-enrichment-facility-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 A North Korean minister said on Monday in a rare address to the UN that Pyongyang would never surrender its nuclear weapons but left open the door to diplomacy. 

Vice Minister for Foreign Affairs Kim Son Gyong made the trip to New York to attend the United Nation's annual high-level week - a role previously performed at a lower level by the country's ambassador. 

"(The) imposition of 'Den</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 07:18:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China at UN warns of return to 'Cold War mentality'</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/China_at_UN_warns_of_return_to_Cold_War_mentality_999.html</link><description>United Nations, United States (AFP) Sept 26, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/un-general-assembly-marker-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
 Chinese Premier Li Qiang warned Friday against a return to a "Cold War mentality" and defended multilateralism and free trade, in a veiled criticism of the United States from the United Nations. 

The Chinese premier made no explicit reference to US President Donald Trump as he addressed the UN General Assembly. But he cast the Asian power as a defender of the global order, of which Washington</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 07:18:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Estonia PM says Russia incursions aim to distract EU from Ukraine</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Estonia_PM_says_Russia_incursions_aim_to_distract_EU_from_Ukraine_AFP_interview_999.html</link><description>Copenhagen (AFP) Sept 30, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/baltics-latvia-lithuania-estonia-russia-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Estonia's Prime Minister Kristen Michal warned Tuesday that Russia's recent air incursions were an attempt to distract Europe from helping Ukraine, ahead of a summit with EU leaders. 

"Putin wants to have us talking about ourselves, not about Ukraine, not about helping Ukraine, not to push back Russia in Ukraine," Michal told AFP in an interview in Copenhagen. 

EU leaders will discuss boos</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 07:18:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NATO says beefing up Baltic presence after Denmark drone sightings</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/NATO_says_beefing_up_Baltic_presence_after_Denmark_drone_sightings_999.html</link><description>Brussels, Belgium (AFP) Sept 28, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/naval-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;
 NATO has "enhanced vigilance"  in the Baltic after what Copenhagen called an intrusion of unwelcome drones into Danish airspace, a spokesperson for the defence alliance said. 

The reinforced measures "include multiple intelligence, surveillance and reconnaissance platforms and at least one air-defence frigate" in the region to the west of Russia, alliance spokesman Martin O'Donnell told a pre</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 07:18:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Leaked info: China's Taiwan invasion plans get help from Russia</title><link>https://www.sinodaily.com/reports/Leaked_info_Chinas_Taiwan_invasion_plans_get_help_from_Russia_999.html</link><description>Washington DC (UPI) Sep 26, 2025 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/taiwan-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Russia will train and equip Chinese paratroopers to invade Taiwan, according to leaked documents. 
 The 800-page cache of documents said that China will buy dozens of military vehicles and parachute systems for its paratroopers, and Russia will provide training to troops on how to operate them. 
 The documents' details were verified by the Royal United Services Institute, a British t</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 07:18:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Germany wants to allow military to shoot down drones</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/Germany_wants_to_allow_military_to_shoot_down_drones_999.html</link><description>Frankfurt, Germany (AFP) Sept 27, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/uav-spix-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 Germany wants to authorise its military to shoot down drones, the interior minister said Saturday, after a "swarm" of them was spotted over the north of the country.  

It comes after a string of drone sightings near airports and military sites in Denmark and Norway in recent days.  

Suspicion has fallen on Russia, even if no definite proof has been made public. Moscow has rejected suggesti</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 07:18:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EU leaders plot defence boost in shadow of Denmark drones</title><link>https://www.spacewar.com/reports/EU_leaders_plot_defence_boost_in_shadow_of_Denmark_drones_999.html</link><description>Copenhagen (AFP) Oct 1, 2025&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img align="right" border="0" height="128" hspace="5" src="https://www.spxdaily.com/images-bg/marss-nidar-surveillance-technology-end-to-end-ai-layered-defence-unmanned-aerial-systems-uav-uas-bg.jpg" vspace="2" width="160" /&gt;

 EU leaders will discuss bolstering Europe's defences and Ukraine's financial firepower at a Wednesday summit in Denmark, where mysterious drone flights have ramped up fears about the threat from Russia. 

Thousands of police are on high alert, civilian drones have been banned and NATO allies have sent reinforcements as the continent converges on Copenhagen for the long-planned talks, followed</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 07:18:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The D Brief: Reactions to Quantico; Shutdown, in effect; USAF chief nom; GOP govs call out troops; And a bit more.</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/the-d-brief-october-01-2025/408529/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Poland seeks better counter-drone tech after Russian incursion</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/threats/2025/10/poland-seeks-better-counter-drone-tech-after-russian-incursion/408522/</link><description>Warsaw’s foreign minister also hopes the U.S. will send more troops to train with its military.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 14:38:10 -0400</pubDate></item><item><title>Silicon Valley in St. Louis?</title><link>https://www.defenseone.com/business/2025/10/silicon-valley-st-louis/408542/</link><description>With the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency as its North Star, this non-profit wants to attract defense tech companies to put down roots in the Midwest.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 16:49:33 -0400</pubDate></item></channel></rss>